<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01567</identifier>
   <identifier>78RE12</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>78RE12 DeArmond Site 3RE12, Roane County, Tennessee. Features 8, 9, 10, 11; View of mound with Phase B summit. Fill and part of sideslope removed, showing four fire basins exposed. Direction northeast</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Feature 8] Rectangular postmold structure on mound. As in the case of the houses on the summit of Phase B, there has been close superposition on the summit of Phase D. Consequently, no water-tight information on the nature of Feature 8 can be given, beyond the firebasin. So, with the exception of the wall trench structure Feature 15 and the individual fire basins Features 9, 10, 11, 13, 14, and 11 the evidence will be summarized here as Feature 8. The exact depth of the summit debris, in all places on Phase D is not known. But since the origin of the firebasins varies not more than 0.1', the summit material, or accretive floors is known to be thin. Along the southwest side, the summit debris accumulated to a depth of about 0.3' and through this accumulation were intruded the postmolds lying outside the limits of the summit drawn on the ground plan. Therefore, these houses must have been the last on the phase. Also, along the southeast side of the phase, the sideslope is very steep. However, Phase D post holes were found which were only half-way in the edge of the mound, the outer sides of the posts being supported by Phase C, the heavy black clay sideslope addition. So, some of the Phase D occupation was contemporaneous with Phase C. Assuming the fireplace to be approximately in the center of the floor (and the fire basin of Feature 8 seemed last in its series) the last house, or several houses were quite large, taking up almost the whole summit of the mound, or about 30' square. Nothing is known about the superstructure, corners, interior supports, furniture, or even the distribution of the posts in the wall patterns of the last structure. Some notion of the nature of the walls of the earlier houses on Phase D can be obtained from the row of post molds, between the following to points: 48L1, 0.2;N, 2.0'W; 49CA, 0.5'N, 0.6'W. Each of these postholes had a limestone slab in its bottom which kept the butt of the post from sinking through the soft sand fill. These slabs show in the photograph of Feature 15 (wall trench). The occurance of slabs in the bottoms of post holes of this phase was quite common. The post holes intruded from Phase B to Phase D were likewise supported. The fire basin of Feature 8 deserves special mention. Its shape is shown in the detail drawing attached to the ground plan of Phase C and D. It was a square pit excavated to a depth of 1.4'. The lower half was filled with ash and mussel shells. The walls of the upper half were burned red. The mound fill, of course, was sand, so that the side walls of the fire place were of sand. The fill had occasional small lumps of clay mixed with the sand, and this was the only clay involved in the construction of the firebasin. Why only the upper half of the basin should be so baked out is not known. The southwestern side wall was partially cut down by an intrusion which disturbed the firebasin Feature 11. The nature of this intrusion has not been ascertained. The other and earlier houses seemed to be a little smaller, although in no case can size be presented too validly on this summit. The very clean nature of the summit would seem to indicate that the superstructure was cleared away for each house and for the construction of Phase B. There was no evidence that these structures had been destroyed by fire. [Feature 9] Lopsided rectangular fire basin. The detail of this basin is shown in inset accompanying ground plan of Phase C and D. Roughly rectangular in shape, it would be more accurately described as rhomboid. The bottom was flat, the walls practically perpendicular. There was no prepared coating on the inside of this basin. The bottom of the pit was unburned, but the side walls had burnt bright red. There being no daubing on the walls, they consisted of sand with a small amount of clay, the typical Phase D material. About 0.2' of ash and shell lay in the bottom of the pit. [Feature 10] Roughly rectangular firebasin. This basin belonged with one of the incomplete post mold patterns seen on the summit of Phase D (see ground plan and Feature 8 form). The pit was roughly rectangular (although NW end was disturbed by Feature 9). The bottom was flat. It is believed that this pit was not daubed. The fill of Phase D was sandy but contained a small mound of clay. This was sufficient to hold the side walls up, once burned. No ash, etc. was found in the pit. [Feature 11] Rectangular firebasin. Only a very fragile portion of one wall of Feature 11 remained. The rest of the basin was removed by some disturbance, which was visible enough but could not be traced, either vertically or horizontally. Therefore, about the only thing which could be said about the basin is that is had one straight side, form which it is supposed that it is similar to Features 8, 9, 10 and 14. Its time relationship with Feature 8 is not known. Nor is its depth.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>John Alden</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Sep 16, 1940</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1940-09-16</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>See also photographs 75RE12 [fhm01565], 77RE12 [ fhm01566], and 173RE12 [fhm01574].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 8, 9, 10, 11</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 320, 355</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Fire basins</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>General site and excavation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85087721">
      <topic>Mounds</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Woodland</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1940</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82226528">
      <geographic>Roane County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
