<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm00246</identifier>
   <identifier>99BY11</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>99BY11 Rymer Site 15BY11, Bradley Co., Tennessee. Feature 44, a dwelling house site with a depressed floor. Square 32R1. Direction northwest</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>Unburned roof clay and wattle lies upon floor. Semi-subterranean structure which seems to be the most intact of any yet encountered in regard to depth of pit. Pit was traced to depth of 1.0' and seems to have been originally 1.7' at least deep. Walls of pit nearly vertical. Wattle over floor was about 0.5' over and west of firebasin, grading down to 0.1' at edges. Wattle in main unburned but small areas burned even red - I believe this is not due to burning of structure but to burning in place before collapse of structure. Under wattle were remains of bark and/or cane thatch. Wattle cut at burial pits showing definitely that they were intrusive to structure. Wattle did not show cane or grass impressions even in burned areas. Floor baked hard mainly east and south of firebasin. Firebasin well made, lined with hard puddled clay and burned red 0.1 1/2' below bottom. Basin slightly rectangular in shape, walls vertical, curb probably once present but nearly gone now. On northwest side near west corner a pile of 22 small 0.3 dia, broken pebbles - these seem to be associated with Feature as pile touches wall, were probably in pit dug just outside house. Few stones scattered on floor. Floor fairly flat and level. Little [?] detritus above subsoil. Two entrances were found in southeast side. There is no evidence of another structure here as that entrance must be subsequent passages for same house, one being abandoned for some reason. Southern one is cut by Burials 15BY163, 15BY164, but as these cut the wattle and are subsequent to collapse of Feature 44 they could not be the reason for abandoning this trench. A large hole north of basin, 0.2 deep may have been a pit but no evidence of heat and comparatively small size lead me to believe it is simply a large post. Fill above wattle was very rich in sherds, the exceptional depth of this countersink as found probably accounts for large amounts of sherds found. Northern entrance appears to have a cross trench across outside but this may actually be caused by intrusive post holes.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <note>See also photographs 98BY11 [fhm00245], and 102BY11 [fhm00249]. Contact institution for specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: 2026 - 2048.</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 44</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 2034, 2037, 2060, 2073, 2121, 2137</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>General site and excavation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Late Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1937</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81024913">
      <geographic>Bradley County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
