<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01213</identifier>
   <identifier>99MG31</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>99MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 38, Pyramidal mound at right. Feature 39, Pyramidal mound at left. Feature 38A, Platform on the summit of F. 38. Feature 39A, Platform on the summit of F. 39. Portions of the 2 stairways, Feature 38B at right and Feature 39B at left, may be seen. Point of union between the 2 pyramids also shows in the picture. Direction southeast</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Feature 38] This pyramidal mound lies in the Southeastern section of Level E. The South and East sides are very steeply sloped and run from a top D.D. of around 15' to a base reading of Ca. 22'. The North side slopes down sharply Ca. 1.5' to a terrace (i.e. Feat. 43). On the West, the slope is pronouncedly sharp to a D.D. of Ca. 17.5' where this pyramid mound joins Feat. 39 pyramid mound. On this side, these two mounds are joined by a ramp (Feat. 38c-39c). On the south slope, a well made stairway ramp gives an approach to the top of the mound. On top of the mound is a large flat area 38' x19' showing some evidence of burning. Red patches and a slight amount of charred material indicating a fairly well made floor. Slightly west of the center in a large platform case (Feature 38A) upon which some notable probably sat. In the north side of this platform is a row of 7 P.M. but no others appear on the other side of the platform. A few misc. P.M.s are to be found but they don't form any pattern. From the evidence it must be assumed that neither this pyramid mound nor the top area and possibly not even the platform were protected by any overhead shelter but were left open to the weather. It is remarkable that little or no errosion or weathering is apparent. Feature 40 lies over the north half of the mound and also over a good part of the platform. Correction note: The row of 7 postmolds mentioned above were later found to run under the platform. Further another row was found at the east end and parallel to this one. About 1' west of this row a wall trench was found, but no post molds found in it. A short row of molds back of the platform parallels these other rows. These molds were not found until this level had been cut down ca. .3'. The indication is that this pyramid mound was used for a period before the platform was built. Then the platform was built and the molds in back of the platform and the wall mold at the east end were used for the erection of a shelter over it. The other two parallel rows were used for a similar purpose before the platform was built. [Feature 38A] This platform is made of hard-packed sandy, mottled grey clay and the surface had been baked hard and smooth. The platform is raised 1.4 above the floor of the mound Feature 38 and is somewhat west of the center point being ca. 3' farther west than the ramp. This platform apparently was not under a shelter but exposed to the weather. That it shows no sign of weathering may be due to the fact that a skin of some sort was kept over it. Feature 40 overlay the entire north half of the feature to a thickness of ca. 0.5'. Correction note: Further excavation indicates that a shelter had been built over the top area of the pyd. mound Feature 38 similar to the one noted for pyramidal mound Feature 39. [Feature 38B] This ramp is made of very hard packed mottled clay and runs from the base of level E to the top of Feature 38. It slopes at about a 40 degree angle and steps have been crudely fashioned into the clay. At the base the ramp fans out slightly so that it is wider than at the top. It is notable that considerable patching and rebuilding have been done, especially near the top. At the very top of the ramp on the mound's top surface is a small, short log mold ca. 0.2' deep. [Feature 39] This pyramid mound is in the Southwest section of Level E. The South slope is very steep and runs from a D.D. of 17.5' to a D.D. of 23' at bottom. The slope has an incline of Ca. 80 degrees. The East slope forms the junction with Feat. 38 mound with the ramp 38c and 39c connecting the two at the Northeast corner of the mound. The North slope is very sharp, being almost vertical but dropping only Ca. 1.5' to a terrace (Feat. 41 floor). On the West side the slope is rather sharp for a drop of Ca. 2' in a horizontal distance of 6'. In the next 6', it levels out almost flat before the final drop to the outer edge of Level E. On the south side slope just west of the mound proper, are a number of toe holds on the side slope. These lead up to the flat area. then on the southwest corner of the mound on the first steep slope a crude step has been built and below this another small leg mold. It would appear that this arrangement is a sort of secondary approach to the top of the mound. On the South slope of this mound slightly East of the center point is a very well made ramp (39B) with well defined steps out into it. On the top is a flat area 25' x 17' and somewhat East of the center is a very well made clay platform (Feat. 39A). In back of the seat is a row of post molds running across the width of the mound. At the extreme west end is another such row. This would indicate that some sort of canopy was placed over the seat. Feature 40 lies over the north section of the mound surface. The floor was well made and possibly hardened by fire, although this may have been accidentally done when Feature 41 burned. [Feature 39A] This platform is made of hard-packed yellow, sandy clay. The surface was smoothed and burnt dark red. The platform is raised 1.5' above the surface of the mound and is located somewhat East of the center point. The back of the platform was built up against a row of postmolds and consequently is vertical. On the other 3 sides, the bottom is somewhat farther out than the top. Twelve feet in front of the seat is another row of post molds parallel to those in back of the seat and in all probability they formed supports for a canopy over the platform. [Feature 39B] This ramp is made of very hard packed sandy clay and runs from the base of Level E to the top of Feat. 39 pyramidal mound at an angle of Ca. 45 degrees. The top surface has been cut into fairly regular, well made steps. The ramp fans out slightly at the base so that it is wider than at the top. The ramp shows no evidence of patching or of erosion although it was exposed to the weather. This ramp forms the main approach to Feat. 39 pyramidal mound.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Charles H. Nash</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Mar 20, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-03-20</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 93MG31 [fhm01208], 94MG31 [fhm01209], 95MG31 [fhm01210], 98MG31 [fhm01212], 100MG31 [fhm01214], 101MG31 [fhm01215], 102MG31 [fhm01216], 103MG31 [fhm01217], 104MG31 [fhm01218], 105MG31 [fhm01219], 106MG31 [fhm01220], 107MG31 [fhm01221], 109MG31 [fhm01223], and 115MG31 [fhm01227].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 38, 38A, 38B, 39, 39A, 39B,</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 346, 347, 348, 349</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85087721">
      <topic>Mounds</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85087721">
      <topic>Mounds</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86002076">
      <topic>Ramps (Walkways)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1937</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1938</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83030217">
      <geographic>Meigs County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
