<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01249</identifier>
   <identifier>159MG31</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>159MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 49, Level E. Postmold pattern of a large circular structure below Feature 46 and on the upper terrace of Level E. No internal features appeared upon floor; in background is Feature 44 or lower terrace and pyramidal mound. Feature 45. Direction east</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Feature 49] This structure lies directly under Feature 46 by ca. 0.1'. It is the last structure found on level E and is circular in shape being delineated by rather deep post molds. No internal features found and in all probability such as may have been present were destroyed by the above structure. The floor was well made of hard packed smooth sandy clay. The structure went under the north edge of Feature 47 pyramidal mound and gives a new surface to this mound ca .3' below the other (See form Feature 47). No wall or log molds associated with the post molds. [Feature 44] This structure is delineated by a post mold pattern of large, deep molds. The corners are closed; those on the East end being square while at the West they are rounded, with a series of small holes. This structure is Ca. 0.1' below Feat. 41 and if there had been any raised sub-features on the floor they were destroyed. The floor is well made of smooth, hard packed clay. The fire basin for Feat. 41 was, in all probability, used for this structure since it shows evidence of having been rebuilt at one time. Thus while the actual basin of 41C was very small in diameter, this same basin had a diameter of 1.6' during the first stage of use. The raised block is unchanged. (see form 41C for details of fire basin in last stage of use.) The probability is great that this structure was an earth lodge similar to Feat. 41 since the profile of Feat. 40 showed an underneath bank of earth placed up against the post mold pattern of this structure. All other evidence, however, was destroyed when this structure was cleared away for Feature 41. It seems certain that this structure is on a terrace to the north of Feature 45 pyramidal mound. However, the north side slope of this mound down to the terrace could not be found and the supposition is that it was destroyed when this structure and mound were cleared for the building of Features 41 and 39. This structure is, of course, a part of the Level E complex. Post molds were set in a wall trench Ca. 1.8' deep. At the northwest corner the wall trench turned the corner, while at the other three corners it stopped and a corner post filled up the corner. The posts were vertical and showed no effects of such stresses as may have been set up by roof constructure. The wall trenches were filled with earth and gave no indication of having had horizontal support logs placed in them. [Feature 45] This pyramidal mound lies Ca. 1' under Feat. 39 pyramidal mound and is exactly similar in every respect except that no platform was found on the top surface. On the West, this mound leveled out to the same side slope as was in use by mound Feat. 39; on the other three sides, however, the side slopes are in somewhat farther. The top surface is a rather indefinite but hard packed floor 25.5' x 15.5'. At the West end, a row of posts set in a wall trench was found. Parallel to this and 7' West of the East end, another such row was uncovered. The approach to the mound on the South was by a poorly made ramp (Feat. 45A). From the West, an approach (discussed for Feat. 39) was used. This consisted of a series of toe-holds on the low slope to the South that gave approach to a flat area on the West of the mound. This mound connects with Feat. 47 mound by a gentle rising slope.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Charles H. Nash</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>May 5, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-05-05</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 147MG31 [fhm01244], 148MG31 [fhm01245], 150MG31 [fhm01246], and 151MG31 [fhm01247].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 49, 44, 45</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1937</temporal>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1938</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83030217">
      <geographic>Meigs County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
