<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm00996</identifier>
   <identifier>9HY1</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>9HY1 Williams Site 1HY1, Henry County, Tennessee. Feature 14, Pit house with trenches and postmolds delineated. Representing two periods of construction within the pit. Square 1L12. Direction north</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>The area in which this structure occurred showed midden deposit at about 0.4' - 0.5' below the plowzone, however, before we were able to distinguish the delineation of the feature it was necessary to cut down to about 0.2' below the top of subsoil, due to the staining of the surrounding subsoil. By deduction then the depth of the original pit would have been 1.5' for one floor and 1.9' for the other. From the part of the pit we were able to work out, we found the pit had straight sides and no entrance way. Within the pit are two trench and post mold patterns and two floors, the smaller of the two being the later. The upper floor was of loosely packed clay 0.4' deep on average over the floor of the original structure. With this upper floor was a flat circular fire basin of rather poor construction. It seems to have been built by preparing a wet section of the floor; it has no curb and no depth. The earlier floor and fire basin had been cleaned before the addition of the clay making up the higher floor. Only a thin line of char separated the earlier floor and the later addition of clean yellow clay. Neither floor was hardened or burnt, it being in about the same consistency of ordinary subsoil clay under ordinary conditions. With this upper floor the smaller trench pattern and post mold pattern is associated. This trench and post mold pattern differs from the larger, earlier pattern only in size of the entire pattern. The trenches and post molds are the same size and there is the same range of variation in both it cases. The earlier structure had a rectangular fire basin with straight sides and flat bottom and a low rounded curb, a square wall trench pattern measuring 12.0' x 12.0' on the interior. The trench depth from the floor to the base of the trenches averaged 0.6'. The later structure had a flat circular fire basin with no curbs, a square trench pattern measuring 13.5' x 13.3' on the interior. The trench depth from floor to the bottom of the wall trench was about 1.0'. It should be noted that the difference of the depths of these trenches is great and would have produced serious error had the time positions been reversed and the time sequence deduced from the trench depths. Post molds in both structures were small (0.2' - 0.3') and interstices varied around 0.4'. There was no trace of superstructure with either structure.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>George A. Lidberg</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Jun 20, 1939</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1939-06-20</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Additional narrative information on file at the institution.</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 14</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1939</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82120714">
      <geographic>Henry County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
