<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm00254</identifier>
   <identifier>132BY13</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>132BY13 Ledford Island Site 16BY13, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 7, Showing profile through feature and horizontal aspect of feature and background as it appears directly beneath plowzone. Square 5R14. Direction west</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>Long trench. The horizontal lines at the ends of the trench demark the depth of humic infiltration into the subsoil. The large central zone marked off shows the width and depth of Feature 7. The smaller, shallower deposit marked off in the center is a black zone containing a quantity of small charcoal fragment. Trench enters west section at 3R4 stake and continues slightly south of west to 5.0W of 2R1 stake. Feature 7 in west section appears to originate quite high in the deposit - in Lev.2 probably - although due to conditions of soil it could not always be traced to its upper level. Wherever it was possible to make vertical profiles, Feature 7 appeared to extend up to about 0.3' below plowzone. Feature 7 did in most cases extend up to within the upper occupational zone. The trench had somewhat sloping straight sides and nearly flat bottom. Sometimes the bottom tended to be slightly curved. The trench was cut out vertically throughout its length and careful check kept on its shape and depth. The walls and floor of the trench showed what appeared to be a weathering profile. This consisted of a narrow zone (0.3'd) along the sides and bottom of mixed earth, with considerable ferrous stain. This probably indicates an exposed earth surface. The fill of the trench was an even dark brown to black humus. It did not appear to be disturbed except for intrusive post holes and pits. Ten intrusive post holes extended to bottom of Feature 7. Small amounts of leached shell, tempered pottery and other artifacts were found in the feature. The shell tempered pottery was definitely inclusive in the feature and included several sherds of fabric impressed salt pans. Almost no grit tempered sherds were observed in the west section of Feature 7. Feature 7 is precedent to Feature 8 and passes directly under it. In the center of Feature 8 the trench ends. After a gap of 12' if begins at 6.0W of 3 stake. The new section of the trench is designated Feature 17. Feature 7 and Feature 17 can probably be treated as a single phenomena. No logical connection of Feature 7 and the site as a whole can be observed, except that it is earlier than the occupation, or at least earlier than the majority of the site. It does not appear to be a natural feature due to its regularity. The presence of sherds inclusive in it points to contemporaneity with the site. Yet it is precedent to overthing associated with it.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Stuart Neitzel</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Jun 15, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-06-15</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Additional narrative information is on file at the institution. Contact institution for additional specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: around seventy non-consecutive numbers from 645 up to 3336.</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 7</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 645, 697, 714, 777, 810, 852, 1007, 1080, 1151, 1216, 1317, 1408, 1507, 1634, 1917, 2171, 2799, 3336</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Stratigraphy</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Late Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Woodland</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1938</temporal>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1939</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81024913">
      <geographic>Bradley County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
