<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01236</identifier>
   <identifier>127MG31</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>127MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 40 profile, Level E. Shows how earth was banked against walls of structures, Features 43 and 46. At the bottom left, a line of yellow clay lies above floors of Feature 46. This bank rises slightly, thickening from right to left, and represents the original earth placed against the side wall of F.46. [Same as photograph 126MG31] Direction east</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>Above this bank is a small homogeneous bank of sandy humic soil which was thrown up against the walls. (To the right of this are a series of pines and loads of humic soil arises from ground level to the top at approximately a 45 degree angle. This probably represents the earthen walls of Feature 43 leveled down to the Level E side slope). [Features 40A and B] For purposes of discussion Feature 40 will be divided into subfeatures A and B. Feature 40A is the earth bank to the left of the C.A. surrounding Feature 41 while Feature 40B is the right of C.A. surrounding Feature 43. This earth bank (both sections) was built up by placing a very heavy layer of earth against the side walls of Features 41-43 extending from the roof to the side slope of Level E, mound phase, overlapping the side slope evenly and in such a way as to give the appearance that the side slope of the mound continued up to the roof of the two structure mentioned. Since the roofs of the two structures were apparently covered with earth the effect was to give the two structures the appearance of rather large mounds of earth to the north of Features 39 and 38 respectively. When these two structures fell the result was to somewhat scatter this heavy load of earth and weathering caused it to round off over the post mold pattern. On the south side some of the earth fell on the north edge of the two pyramid mounds Features 38 and 39. Then Feature 40A overlies the north edge of the floor on top of Feature 39 mound and Feature 40B overlay a considerable part of Feature 38 mound including some of it over the platform 38A. Under the two sections of these earth banks postmold patterns have been found for the two above mentioned structures. Feature 40B is on a higher elevation than Feature 40A since it associates with the Feature 38 pyramid mound and the somewhat lower floor to the north Feature 43. Feature 40A, on the lower level associates with Feature 39 pyramid mound. and the somewhat lower floor Feature 41. Feature 40B has an average dd of 15.1' on the top of the ridge with a variation of 1.6' while 40A has an average dd of 17.4 and a variation of 1.3' along the top of the ridge. dd (down 10') cross section through Feature 40. See profile drawing on original sheet. This profile shows the earth bank for the two structures. The underneath mottled grey clay was the earth laid up against the wall of Feature 44 structure (below Feature 41) while the above sandy humic soil in Feature 40 was laid up against the side slope of Feature 41. This situation is duplicated for Features 43 and 47. In removing Feature 40 the original side slope of pyramid mounds 38 and 39 to floor 41 and 43 respectively is apparent. [Feature 43] This structure is rectangular in shape and is delineated by deep rather evenly spaced post molds. A fairly hard, well made floor of packed sandy clay burnt dull red in many areas runs directly to the post molds, leaving no sign of a wall trench. However, on the inside of the post molds and just below the floor is a log mold. On the floor are a number of misc. post molds most of which are a the western end back of the platform 43A. Roughly these divide this section into small compartments. The subfeatures on the floor are independently described. This location is shown on the plat for this structure. The platform, two pits and fire basin are all on an east-west central axis through the structure. Feature 40B encircled this structure lying heavily over certain sections of the post mold pattern, while over the entire floor, thin in the central sections and much thicker toward the wall was a mass of clay that in all likelihood fell from the roof. From this evidence it becomes evident that this structure was an earth lodge in all essential respect similar in form (see Feature 41 form) to Feature 41. There is practically no burnt material on the floor of this structure -- just a little piece of thatch at the southwest corner. The log mold on the inside of the post mold pattern in ca 6' deep but ranges from .3' to .9'. The effect is exactly what one would expect if the small ends of saplings were doubled over the end of another sapling where two were laid together, end to end. This, of course, was necessary because it would have been very difficult to have found single saplings long enough to have reached the length of the wall. These log molds were found only on the north and south walls and were not present for the east and west walls. Further no log mold was bound at the bottom of the post molds on the opposite side; however molds were set in a wall trench. [Feature 46] This structure lay directly under Feature 43 and is very similar in size and shape, being rectangular, 34 x 30 feet. It is delineated by a post mold pattern with closed and rounded corners on the east and a square corner at the southwest. The northwest corner was cut away by the north coor. trench. The north wall was very indefinite only a few post molds having been found and most of those are in a very shallow trench ca. .4' in depth. The south wall was almost directly under that of Feature 43 and hence was partially destroyed. However many of the molds found for Feature 43 look like double molds and it may well be that that was the result of the two rows having been in one place. No log molds were found for this structure. It is probable that this structure was an earth lodge -- evidence mainly is derived from a cross section of Feature 40 which indicated a lower band of earth, which lay up against these molds. No internal features found, but that may be due to the fact that they were destroyed at the time Feature 43 was built. It is possible that Feature 43C fire basin destroyed the basin for this structure. Structure is on the terrace of Feature 47, and is a part of Level E, Section 2 complex. No wall trenches found for the post molds of wall.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Charles H. Nash</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Mar 10, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-03-10</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs See also photographs 101MG31 [fhm01215], 103MG31 [fhm01217], 106MG31 [fhm01220], 107MG31 [fhm01221], 109MG31 [fhm01223], 115MG31 [fhm01227], 118MG31(A) [fhm01230], 118MG31(B) [fhm01231], 120MG31 [fhm01233], and 126MG31 [fhm01235].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 40A, 40B, 43, 46</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 345, 355, 356, 357, 358, 359, 352</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Earth banks</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1937</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1938</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83030217">
      <geographic>Meigs County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
