<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm00252</identifier>
   <identifier>110BY11</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>110BY11 Rymer Site 15BY11, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 51, Two fireplaces in foreground associated with feature, one to the left of number is associated with Feature 39. Square 32L3. Direction west</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Feature 39] Semi-subterranean structure with multiple firebasin lying slightly to NE of Feature 48 and lying above it. Floor does not seem to be higher, but along S-W edge of Feature 39 wattle lay beyond edge of structure and on floor of Feature 48. At stake 30L3, where edges of Feature 39, 48, touch floor of Feature 48 was 0.4' lower than floor of Feature 39. Large mass of wattle lying along SW side of these two structures seems to be composed of wattle from both structures. Lower part of wattel was unburned yellow clay; upper 0.1' was burned red but showed little grass impression. No evidence of filling of leveling Feature 48 below Feature 39 could be observed. There seems to have been some slight burning of Feature 39. The floor of Feature 39 could not be exactly traced due to superimposition of Feature 51. There are three firebasins that lay below hard floor of Feature 51 and can be presumed to be associated with Feature 39. The hard floor of Feature 51 was broken over these three basins to some extnet as fill of basins was softer than subsoil under rest of floor. The first basin was circular, 0.6' deep with vertical walls, flat bottom with a slight curve between bottom and wall, bottome burned 0.2'. No curb found. North of this was a large shallow basin without curb, walls nearly vertical, floor flat but very bumpy and burned 0.5' deep.... This seems to be a large dwelling house, except for its size it did not differ from any of the other houses encountered. [Feature 48] Semi-subterranean structure with central fire basin with only SW countersink intact, though slight indication of countersink at SE side. Countersink walls vertical where they could be traced. At NW side there is a small countersink outside main pit of Feature 48. This seems to be later than Feature 48. Wattle overlay floor and seemed to be mixed at top with wattle of Feature 39. Lower part of wattle was not burned and I believe this indicates Feature 48 was not burned. There seemed to be some oxidized remains of organic material under wattle, on floor; though it was so badly decomposed its exact nature could not be determined, I assumed it was thatch. Firebasin was very rectangular in shape with vertical walls and flat bottoms meeting abruptly without curve. Bottom was burned 0.2' deep and was cut by a large post hole. Basin was filled with mixed earth and unburned wattle. There was no curb. None of the floor was baked hard, though it all had a fairly good cleavage. Near SW edge lay one large pile of stones and several scattered stones. No entrance trench could be associated with the feature. F.S. specimens catalogued as Feature 48 came from lower levels and from SW part of the area covered by Features 39, 48, and 51 as exact separation could not be accomplished until structure was ground planned. It was necessary to work full crew on these structures and possibly some of the material catalogued as Feature 39 may belong with Feature 48. This structure from its size seems to be simply a residence structure. [Feature 51] Structure with a central firebasin. No countersink could be found for this structure. As this house is higher than the others, its countersink was probably higher and was plowed away. Just outside S corner of Feature 48, 39 was entrance trench that could not be associated with either of these Features. It may belong with Feature 51. Wattle extended beyond limits of countersinks to NW and NE (see ground plan) and this wattle presumably may belong in part to Feature 51. This wattle however was only partly burned and without grass impressions. Over floor of Feature 51 was a distinct and separate area of wattle, which was hard burned and in definite briquettes with much grass impressions. This could have only come from Feature 51 the floor under this wattle was burned fairly hard, was flat with blackened upper surface. Over firebasins of Feature 39 floor was somewhat broken but seemed to have definitely extended over those basins. The firebasin was fairly hard, and well built. It seems to show some slight evidence of low curb. Walls hard, vertical and curve to meet flat floor burned hard and red to depth of 0.3'. Directly on floor and under wattle were some burned canes.... Feature 51 number assigned to upper structure after excavation complete to clarify notes and photographs already done.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Charles H. Fairbanks</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Feb 20, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-02-20</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Additional narrative information on file at institution for Features 39 and 51. See also phototgraphs 108BY11 [fhm00250], and 109BY11 [fhm00251]. Contact institution for additional specific field specimen numbers. Field specimen numbers listed above are inclusive for all three features, and are non-consecutive ranging from 1764 - 1790, 2103 - 2216.</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 39, 48, 51</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 1764, 1790, 2103, 2129, 2138, 2146, 2154, 2167, 2177, 2183,</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Fire basins</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Late Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1937</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81024913">
      <geographic>Bradley County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
