<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01585</identifier>
   <identifier>196RE12</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>196RE12 DeArmond Site 3RE12, Roane Co., TN. [Features 25, and 26]. Phase H. View of phase H showing structure patterns on top, pyramidal form of mound, ramp (near corner in foreground) and post holes around foot and up the sides of ramp. Direction east-southeast</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>Also note two test trenches across summit. These show the amount of elevation of the occupied area above rest of summit. [Feature 25] Rectangular small-postmold structure. This was the best of the structures on Phase H, but very little information was obtained about it. For instance, it will be noted that the greatest dimension is given as either 26' or 28'. It is the SW end wall which is in doubt, as there were several short rows on this part of the summit. However, the 28' dimension is the more likely, as this associates the wall on the outside edge of the summit with Feature 25. This section of wall had the diameter and interstices of the holes which was characteristic of Feature 25, namely, small closely set postmolds. This structure had sharp, square corners. No entrance could be determined, but it probably lay in the southeast wall at the head of the ramp. The summit of this phase had two different levels. A narrow ledge extended from the middle of the northwest side, along the northeast side, turning south and terminating at the head of the ramp on the southeast side. This ledge or cat walk lay at about 9.0 d.d. The remainder of the summit, the rectangular, occupied section of the summit, arched up from 9.0 to about 8.2 dd. in the center. The first two walls of Feature 25 were found long the contact between the elevated central section and the lower strip around the north end. The southeast wall had the same relationship to this narrow path, as far as it went. Extending southwest from the ramp, the southeast wall lay sufficiently far over the turn of the summit so that the floor humped up inside the south east wall. It is for this reason that the outer-most of the southwestern walls was selected to go with this house. This outer wall lay well below the visible edge of the summit. The idea of an elevated floor within the house seems to be a characteristic of this structure. It is believed that this house had a prepared clay floor. It was not burned (except in the vicinity of the fireplace) and was from 0.05' to 0.2' thick. There was a very good cleavage. The material from this clay was bagged as "summit", but in all probability, most of the artifacts etc. came from the village along with the dirt. When this floor was stripped off, the postmolds of the other houses appeared, and for this reason, Feature 25 is thought to be the subsequent house on Phase H. The floor was very thin on the center of the summit, so that the sequence of the fireplaces is uncertain. That is to say, they all appeared at once. The fireplace at 1.0'S, 1.0E, 50L2, d.d. 8.25' seems likely because of its central location. However, Pit 22 is intrusive to it, indicating occupation after the use of this foreplace. This conflicts with the theory that Feature 25 was the last house on Phase H. There were however, two other burned fireplaces with locations at 3.0'S, 1.0W, 50L2 dd. 8.45' and 3.0'S, 3.0E 50L2, dd. 8.5'. Neither of these were disturbed, and either or both, may have been used with Feature 25. The differing datum depths merely indicate the rising curve of the floor. The fireplace adjacent to stake 50L2 appears to be a square rimmed affair, but actually is only a burned clay patch of flooring, accidentally square, with a deep ash-filled hole in the center. It is not absolutely certain that the hole actually belonged with the fireplace. Of the other two fireplaces, the one 3.0'S, 3.0E of 50L2 was flat and the burned area extended down about 0.2'. The fireplace at 3.0'S, 1.0'W 50L2 was slightly dished (about 0.05'). It was about 0.3' thick. All fireplaces had some ash on their surfaces. It is not known how many of the small midden pits in the summit of Phase H were associated with Feature 25, as one could not be certain of thier origins. All originated on theis summit, however. Nothing can be stated about the interior of this house, as a quick glance at the ground plan will readily show. There was too great a profusion of post molds. The only clue to superstructure was the occurence of small broken daub in Pits 27, 28, and 29. This does not mean that this was a daubed house, but that daub existed as a technique at that time, and this house may have been daubed. [Feature 26] Rectangular small postmold house. The distinguishing feature of this house was the size and interstices of the post molds. Pencilled lines ruled on the large scale ground plan shows the walls of this structure, as well as the excavator could make out. Notice that two closely parallel lines are shown for both the NW and NE walls (the only walls that could be pointed to with certainty). Both rows are included under Feature 26. These rows have three possibilities. Each row may represent a separate house. The two rows together may have formed the wall of a single house. The two rows may have formed the wall of a single house. The two rows may likewise have been an interior Feature 25. In any case the walls of Feature 25 contain about three holes for every hole in the walls of Feature 26. These rows appeared immediately after the floor of Feature 25 was lifted off. Some of the holes had a reddish burned appearance, possibly indicateing the destrcution by fire of Feature 26. Since this was not a characteristic of Feature 25 holes, it is additional evidence to indicate that Feature 26 wa a structure by itself. For fireplaces, only two are left after extracing the possible fireplaces of Feature 25. One of these lay underneath the fireplaces at 1.0'S, 1.0'E, 50L2, and had a datum depth of 8.45'. The other was oval and lay at 1.2'N, 1.4'W, 50L2 with an elevation of 8.2' dd. Both were dished about 0.1'. As in the case of Feature 25, the only corner found (N) was square. The over-all dimensions are the minimum possible measurements. The structure was certainly larger in one or both directions. It should be noted that the holes for this structure were well up on the summit, rather than at the very edge of the rectangular occupational area. It is not certain just what kind of floor this structure had. It was probably accumulative, but no in situ debris could be determined. Of course, no entrances to the structure could be seen because of the incomplete pattern. Likewise, it is not known which of the midden pits and excess postmolds belonged to Feature 26.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>John Alden</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Mar 10, 1941</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1941-03-10</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photograph 193RE12 [fhm01586]</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 25, 26</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Post molds</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Woodland</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1940</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82226528">
      <geographic>Roane County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
