<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01221</identifier>
   <identifier>107MG31</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>107MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 40, Earthen embankment around Feature 41, Earth lodge. A large cache pit, Feature 41B appears in center of floor near platform, F.41A. In the central background is Feature 39 mound and F.39A platform. At left is seen a portion of mound 38 and platform 38A and the connecting ramp between mounds 38 and 39, Features 38C and 39C. Direction north</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Features 40A and B] For purposes of discussion Feature 40 will be divided into subfeatures A and B. Feature 40A is the earth bank to the left of the C.A. surrounding Feature 41 while Feature 40B is the right of C.A. surrounding Feature 43. This earth bank (both sections) was built up by placing a very heavy layer of earth against the side walls of Features 41-43 extending from the roof to the side slope of Level E, mound phase, overlapping the side slope evenly and in such a way as to give the appearance that the side slope of the mound continued up to the roof of the two structure mentioned. Since the roofs of the two structures were apparently covered with earth the effect was to give the two structures the appearance of rather large mounds of earth to the north of Features 39 and 38 respectively. When these two structures fell the result was to somewhat scatter this heavy load of earth and weathering caused it to round off over the post mold pattern. On the south side some of the earth fell on the north edge of the two pyramid mounds Features 38 and 39. Then Feature 40A overlies the north edge of the floor on top of Feature 39 mound and Feature 40B overlay a considerable part of Feature 38 mound including some of it over the platform 38A. Under the two sections of these earth banks postmold patterns have been found for the two above mentioned structures. Feature 40B is on a higher elevation than Feature 40A since it associates with the Feature 38 pyramid mound and the somewhat lower floor to the north Feature 43. Feature 40A, on the lower level associates with Feature 39 pyramid mound. and the somewhat lower floor Feature 41. Feature 40B has an average dd of 15.1' on the top of the ridge with a variation of 1.6' while 40A has an average dd of 17.4 and a variation of 1.3' along the top of the ridge. dd (down 10') cross section through Feature 40. See profile drawing on original sheet. This profile shows the earth bank for the two structures. The underneath mottled grey clay was the earth laid up against the wall of Feature 44 structure (below Feature 41) while the above sandy humic soil in Feature 40 was laid up against the side slope of Feature 41. This situation is duplicated for Features 43 and 47. In removing Feature 40 the original side slope of pyramid mounds 38 and 39 to floor 41 and 43 respectively is apparent. [Feature 41] This structure is practically square and is delineated by a post mold pattern of deep evenly spaced molds ca.4' in diameter. At the ends of each wall is a very small mold not over .2' in diameter but about as deep as the rest of the molds. A very smooth hard baked floor of sandy clay runs directly up the post mold pattern leaving no sign of a wall trench, however, on the inside of the post molds is a log mold just below the floor and in all probability a wall mold will show up when the floor is cut away. The hard baked dull red floor extends all over the inside of the structure running up to such features as the firebasin, platform, etc. There is considerable amount of charred material lying on the floor but very little of it is of much value in reconstructing the superstructure. No posts of logs remain but only charred, split can material covered over with thatch and in some cases a third layer of bark (See drawing of burnt material). Heavily laid over the post mold pattern is the earth bank (see Feature 40) which indicates that a heavy layer of earth was placed on the side walls. Overlying the entire floor was earth of a similar nature as Feature 40 and this, no doubt, fell from the roof of the building. Thus we may conclude that this structure was an earth lodge. The earth placed over the wooden framework was dome-like in appearance matching into the side slope of Level E. A cross-section drawing. Through Features 39 and 41 in reconstructed form. Inside this structure are a number of sub-features, 41A, B, C, D, and E, each of which will be fully described on separate sheets. Aside from these are a number of misc. post molds located to the north of Feature 41D and tending to subdivide this back section into small compartment-like areas. This area is separated by a partition (Feature 41D) from the rest of the building and the occurance of post molds directly behind this low clay partition indicates a high wall had been placed there. Most of these internal post molds were ca. 1.4 deep and 2' diameter although a few are as large as the wall post molds and may have been for post supporting the roof. The fire basin (41C) was about centrally located and in the larger of the two rooms directly in front of a small wooden seat (41E). Between the fire basin and the partitions 41D was a cache pit (41B). These three sub-features were to the south (or in front of) the partition. The partition dividing the structure is placed just in front of the platform (41A).... [Feature 41A] This platform is made of hard packed clay burnt to a smooth dull red on the surface. It is .8' high 5.6' long, 3.8 wide and rests on the floor of Feature 41. It was thinly covered with Feature 40 earth. The sides are slightly sloping making the base of the platform somewhat larger than the top. There is an irregular post mold pattern at the back of the seat but it doesn't seem to have any specific relation to it. In front of the platform is Feature 41D partition which is open in the center to allow the person sitting on the seat to look into the larger room. [Feature 41B] This cache pit lies just to the south of partition 41D and to the north of the fire basin. The side wall and bottom are well defined but not smoothed, nor does the pit show any particular care in manufacture. The sides are nearly vertical but both ends slope rather gently to the bottom and at the west end the pit fans out to its greatest width. Two fair sized post molds are in the western down slope. Feature 40 lay in this pit to a depth of several inches. [Feature 39] This pyramid mound is in the Southwest section of Level E. The South slope is very steep and runs from a D.D. of 17.5' to a D.D. of 23' at bottom. The slope has an incline of Ca. 80 degrees. The East slope forms the junction with Feat. 38 mound with the ramp 38c and 39c connecting the two at the Northeast corner of the mound. The North slope is very sharp, being almost vertical but dropping only Ca. 1.5' to a terrace (Feat. 41 floor). On the West side the slope is rather sharp for a drop of Ca. 2' in a horizontal distance of 6'. In the next 6', it levels out almost flat before the final drop to the outer edge of Level E. On the south side slope just west of the mound proper, are a number of toe holds on the side slope. These lead up to the flat area. then on the southwest corner of the mound on the first steep slope a crude step has been built and below this another small leg mold. It would appear that this arrangement is a sort of secondary approach to the top of the mound. On the South slope of this mound slightly East of the center point is a very well made ramp (39B) with well defined steps out into it. On the top is a flat area 25' x 17' and somewhat East of the center is a very well made clay platform (Feat. 39A). In back of the seat is a row of post molds running across the width of the mound. At the extreme west end is another such row. This would indicate that some sort of canopy was placed over the seat. Feature 40 lies over the north section of the mound surface. The floor was well made and possibly hardened by fire, although this may have been accidentally done when Feature 41 burned. [Feature 39A] This platform is made of hard-packed yellow, sandy clay. The surface was smoothed and burnt dark red. The platform is raised 1.5' above the surface of the mound and is located somewhat East of the center point. The back of the platform was built up against a row of postmolds and consequently is vertical. On the other 3 sides, the bottom is somewhat farther out than the top. Twelve feet in front of the seat is another row of post molds parallel to those in back of the seat and in all probability they formed supports for a canopy over the platform. [Feature 38] This pyramidal mound lies in the Southeastern section of Level E. The South and East sides are very steeply sloped and run from a top D.D. of around 15' to a base reading of Ca. 22'. The North side slopes down sharply Ca. 1.5' to a terrace (i.e. Feat. 43). On the West, the slope is pronouncedly sharp to a D.D. of Ca. 17.5' where this pyramid mound joins Feat. 39 pyramid mound. On this side, these two mounds are joined by a ramp (Feat. 38c-39c). On the south slope, a well made stairway ramp gives an approach to the top of the mound. On top of the mound is a large flat area 38' x19' showing some evidence of burning. Red patches and a slight amount of charred material indicating a fairly well made floor. Slightly west of the center in a large platform case (Feature 38A) upon which some notable probably sat. In the north side of this platform is a row of 7 P.M. but no others appear on the other side of the platform. A few misc. P.M.s are to be found but they don't form any pattern. From the evidence it must be assumed that neither this pyramid mound nor the top area and possibly not even the platform were protected by any overhead shelter but were left open to the weather. It is remarkable that little or no errosion or weathering is apparent. Feature 40 lies over the north half of the mound and also over a good part of the platform. Correction note: The row of 7 postmolds mentioned above were later found to run under the platform. Further another row was found at the east end and parallel to this one. About 1' west of this row a wall trench was found, but no post molds found in it. A short row of molds back of the platform parallels these other rows. These molds were not found until this level had been cut down ca. .3'. The indication is that this pyramid mound was used for a period before the platform was built. Then the platform was built and the molds in back of the platform and the wall mold at the east end were used for the erection of a shelter over it. The other two parallel rows were used for a similar purpose before the platform was built. [Feature 38A] This platform is made of hard-packed sandy, mottled grey clay and the surface had been baked hard and smooth. The platform is raised 1.4' above the floor of the mound. Feature 38 is somewhat west of the center point being ca. 3' further West than the ramp. This platform apparently was not under a shelter but exposed to the weather. That it shows no sign of weathering may be due to the fact that a skin of some sort was kept over it. Feature 40 overlay the entire north half of the feature to a thickness of ca. 0.5'. Correction note: Further excavation indicates that a shelter had been built over the top area of the pyramidal mound Feature 38 similar to the one noted for pyramidal mound Feature 39. [Feature 38C] This ramp is very short serving only to connect Feature 39 with Feature 38 mound. It has a total rise of ca. 2.5' and an angle of incline of ca. 45 degrees. The surface is of hard packed clay and has been crudely cut out to form steps. Feature 40 lies over a section at the north edge. [Feature 39C] See Feature form 38C.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>Charles H. Nash</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Mar 23, 1938</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1938-03-23</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Additional narrative information for Feature 41 is on file at the institution. Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 93MG31 [fhm01208], 94MG31 [fhm01209], 95MG31 [fhm01210], 98MG31 [fhm01212], 99MG31 [fhm01213], 101MG31 [fhm01215], 102MG31 [fhm01216], 103MG31 [fhm01217], 104MG31 [fhm01218], 105MG31 [fhm01219], 106MG31 [fhm01220], 109MG31 [fhm01223], 115MG31 [fhm01227], 116MG31 [fhm01228], 117MG31 [fhm01229], 120MG31 [fhm01233], 126MG31 [fhm01235], and 131MG31 [fhm01237].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 40A, 40B, 41, 41A, 41B, 39, 39A, 38, 38A, 38C, 39C</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 345, 355, 356, 357, 358, 359, 352, 360, 361, 362, 363, 364, 365</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>General site and excavation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1937</temporal>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1938</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83030217">
      <geographic>Meigs County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
