<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">fhm01553</identifier>
   <identifier>47RE12</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>47RE12 DeArmond Site 2RE12, Roane Co., TN. Feature 30, Section of post mold wall of circular dwelling associated with the "old humus", showing molds in cross section. Note pointed and tapered ends of molds and relative depths. (Molds shown from the north and northeast sections of pattern). Datum 8.5' (Floor). Sq. 39R3. Direction north-northwest</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>[Feature 30] Post mold pattern of a circular dwelling. This structure pattern is definitely an "old humus" dwelling (woodland) and was worked out with the utmost care to insure its authenticity. Its association with the "old humus" band, which is present, and separated from the Mississippi deposit by a distinct alluvial mantel throughout most of the excavated area, is not questioned by this observer. The presence of this house pattern was first suspected when three molds were found simultaneously in Sq. 38R2, these describing a slight arc on a horizontal plane. A careful study of the various disturbances originating with the "old humus" had previously been made in an effort to isolate those believed to be post molds definitely not intrusive from the village above. It was ultimately found that "old humus" post molds, as well as other disturbances associated with this zone, were usually apparent in a rather vague manner. The old humus zone with which this house pattern associates is characterized, generally speaking, by a thick band of dark, humic, sandy loam. Intermixed in it are flecks of charcoal and occasional areas burned red by fire. No shell of any kind has been seen associated with this zone. In almost every case the post molds associated are filled with dark humic loam more or less homogeneous with the old humus loam itself. The charcoal flecks are usually readily apparent in the molds and occasional sherds are found in them. With this infomation in mind and with the presence of three molds, the interstices of which were very regular, adjacent mold in the line were located and carefully cut in profile. These were found to originate at a point not higher than 0.1' upward in the old humus band. They definitely did not originate above the old humus band and were visible in profile as originating only in the lower section of the old humus zone. The fact that in the area where the structure was first located there is a distinct and fairly thick alluvium band separating the Mississippi deposit from the old humus eliminates any possibility of the molds originating above. In addition, molds intrusive from the lowest level of the Mississippi deposit at this location (betwen R1 and R2 stakes along 39 line) would not likely have penetrated so deep. This pattern is deliniated by regularly spaced molds of fairly uniform size, describing a circle so symmetrical that it would be difficult to duplicate such a geometric outline without the aid of some kind of an improvised compass or by sheer luck. In clearing the area preparatory to completing the pattern for photographing, four burned areas were found which associated with the bottom of the old humus and seemed to belong to the house, representing the floor. These areas were sandy loam burned red, about 0.1' in thickness, and showing evidence of disintegrated organinc amtter which would give rise to the application of the term accretive floor. There was no prepared floor found. A roughly circular burned area, one of the four mentioned above, centered inside the patter, but there was no evidence suggesting it as a definite fireplace. It could, however, have resulted from a central fire within the house and its apparent isolation is very slightly indicative of this. Several larger molds found within the pattern may have been roof support molds but no interior pattern was formed by them. These were relatively shallow, and some of them showed slightly ragged outlines when first found, and narrowing down near the base, as if holes were dug for the placement of large posts. The wall molds were shown in profile to be tapered, many actually pointed. It is suggested that this would indicate that the wall posts were driven into the ground and this technique would in turn imply that relatively short wall posts were incorporated in the superstructure. The matrix of the basal end of the molds on the SE, S and SW sides of the house is more or less compact clay while on the other sides it is mostly sandy loam. This may account from the apparent shallowness of some molds in these sections, but it is possibly due to a gradual rise in the old humus eastward and southeastward, which would give a sloping land surface at the time of the erection of the house. The old humus apparently lensed out over the E section of the house, as is apparent on the 39 Line profile. For photographing, the house was worked out below its origin point and on an even plane (Datum 9.0' over most of the area). Two molds in the wall that were not shown in the photo on the SW side were located on the ground plan, where they were previously plotted as "old humus" molds. The areas that were cut into before the structure was located were restored with clay so as not to distract from the symmetry of the patter. However no molds were put in that were not actually located. In Sq. 38R3 two interior molds were found to be due to root disturbances in the old humus and these were removed from the plot of the structure. However, these two molds were shown in the photo. No artifacts were found, but a few limestone sherds were found in the interior and wall molds. The burned areas were found at Datum 8.5. The post molds on NW side were traced vertically in the old humus no. to 8.9 Datum. The old humus band is not constant in vertical depth throughout this area.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <name>
      <namePart>W. C. Walker</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/wit">Witness</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Mar 8, 1940</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1940-03-08</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>See also photograph 45RE12 [fhm01552].</note>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 30</note>
   <note>Field specimen identifier(s): 1929, 1935, 1959</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85133869">
      <topic>Tennessee--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Structure patterns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Mississippian</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Woodland</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf">1940</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80003889">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">
      <name>
         <namePart>Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82226528">
      <geographic>Roane County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017033007">Frank H. McClung Museum of Natural History and Culture</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
