<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <identifier type="local">wsw04591</identifier>
   <identifier>91BE3</identifier>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>91BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. General Progress Photograph Showing Portions of the 110, 115, 120, 125, and 130' Profiles</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <abstract>Photograph taken from the north of the mound and from the lower deck of the photographic tower. The small portion of face on the front of the foreground block is that of 130' profile, the incised line indicating the division between the mound fill and undisturbed yellow clay. On the horizontal surface of the 125-130' section are exposed the log molds of Tomb #11 (Feature #12) and Burial 40BE3 insofar as they lie in that section. The second small strip of foreground profile is that of the 125' face. This indicates little but the incised lines defining the walls of the Tomb #11, and the thin band of Old Humus dividing the mound fill from the yellow clay. On the horizontal surface of the second foreground block are the exposed log molds of Tomb #15 (Feature #11) insofar as they lie in this section. The 120' profile into which this tomb extends reveals the vertical structural details of this tomb ... the two walls and the collapsed earth roof. Above this is a vertical section through the bark lined floor of Tomb #14 (Feature #8) with its two cross sectioned log molds. The next to the last face is that of the 115' profile. Note the concave incised line ... this is the upper surface of the collapsed earth roof of Tomb #14 (Feature #8) which was utilized in the interment of Burial 16BE3 and in so became Tomb #13 (Not Featured). On either side of this zone which comprises the collapsed roof the two incised domes mark the walls of Tomb #14 (Feature #8). The background profile is that of the 110' face. The upper zone is the homogeneous upper layer of highly leached earth. At the base of this profile on the right note the incised dome and the next one to the left ... these comprise the earth wall of Tomb #16 (Feature #17) of indistinct horizontal loading. Between these two walls is the brightly dipping loaded earth of the collapsed roof of this roof. The upper surface of the collapsed roof of Tomb #16, as marked by the incised line, on its extreme left forms the west (righthand) wall of Tomb #17 (not Featured). On the extreme left is defined the east wall of this tomb. The intervening earth between the two walls is mixed in character, but very indistinct and scattered loads indicate the usual tilting into the tomb cavity associated with a collapsed roof as demonstrated in most cases at this site.</abstract>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>Jun 20, 1940</dateCreated>
      <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1940-06-20</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <note>Feature identifier(s): 12, 11, 8, 17</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006507">
      <topic>Archaeology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006502">
      <topic>Archaeological museums and collections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85071958">
      <topic>Kentucky--Antiquities</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>General site and excavation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal>Woodland</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="start">1939</temporal>
      <temporal encoding="edtf" point="end">1941</temporal>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81081809">
      <name>
         <namePart>United States. Works Progress Administration</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126249">
      <name>
         <namePart>Tennessee Valley Authority</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095733">
      <name>
         <namePart>University of Kentucky</namePart>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="naf"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81055731">
      <geographic>Boone County (Ky.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh"
            valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633">
      <geographic>Southern States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>WPA/TVA Archeological Photographs</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83061373">University of Kentucky. Museum of Anthropology</recordContentSource>
   </recordInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction"
                    xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/">Copyright Undetermined</accessCondition>
</mods>
