<record>
  <dc:title>135BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY49, a mature male. Square 8R15.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-06-14</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Mature male in good condition, extended on back with head to NW. Two small crumbs of pyrite were also found between F.S. 1171 and left elbow--these were stolen or removed before picture was taken. Particles of wood were found 0.1' above feet, but orientation of the grain was not determined. One small particle was found near the left knee and to one side of it. The grain was oriented NW-SE. Another fragment is shown over the right ilium oriented with the long axis of the skeleton. The lower thoracic vertebrae and the phalanges of the left hand were disturbed, presumably by roots or rodents; phalanges of right likewise disturbed. This disturbance may possibly explain why all the projectile points (F.S. 1165) were not pointing toward the feet, assuming that they were oriented so originally. Their deposition suggested that a sheaf of arrows had been laid along the left hip. The concave side of the turtle carapace (F.S. 1174) was up. The celt (F.S. 1167) lay crossways between the femora. The pit was filled with black organic fill containing a small amount of cultural detritus, sherds (F.S. 1176), and animal bone. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations availalble on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1165; 1167; 1168; 1166; 1169; 1170; 1171; 1172; 1173; 1174; 1175; 1176; 1178</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY49</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>135BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials; Artifacts</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00452</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007471</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
