<record>
  <dc:title>1BY11 Rymer Farm, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burials 15BY1, 4 and 7. Burial 1 is an adult female; burial 4 an infant; burial 7 a juvenile female. Square 22R6. Direction ENE.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-10-07</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[15BY1] Adult female in fair condition, extended on back with head to north. Facial portion of skull crushed and disturbed--skull inadvertently removed before remainder of skeleton uncovered. [15BY4] Indeterminate infant in fair condition, extended on back with head to SW. 15BY5 is intrusive in a round pit--it lay about 0.1' above the femora and tibiae of 15BY4. [15BY7] Juvenile female in good condition, extended on back with head to SW. The feet of 15BY1 lay immediately over the head of 15BY7. 15BY7 not disturbed by the intrusion.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>208; 210</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>15BY1; 15BY4; 15BY7</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>1BY11</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00369</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007390</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
