<record>
  <dc:title>212BN12 Eva, Benton County, Tennessee. Burials 6BN162, 163. Burial 162, juvenile. Flexed on left side. 163 dog burial lying on left side - bones partially across 162. Direction North.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-11-09</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Middle Archaic; Late Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[6BN162] On left side, legs flexed back with knees near skull and feet at pelvis. Right arm flexed at elbow, hand at chin. This individual was fairly tightly flexed. No pit in evidence. A crude blade leaning against skull. A dog burial was placed to one side of this individual in association with it. Legs of dog (6BN163) lay over legs of this individual. [6BN163] Dog burial with a human juvenile. The skull apparently has been cut off and placed in the grave and covered by body of dog.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>There are two burial data forms on file for this photograph - one for the human juvenile, and one for the dog. Institution has small illustration of the burials on file. Field specimens listed on burial data form as #1 - crude blade and #2 - awl.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1; 2</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>6BN162; 6BN163</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>212BN12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials; Dog Burial</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00141</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000006294</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
