<record>
  <dc:title>38BN12(A) Eva, Benton County, Tennessee. Burials 6BN39, 6BN40, and 6BN41. 6BN39 in back left, head NW, on right side, tight flexure. 6BN40 in middle, head NW, on back and right side, flexed. Facing NE. 6BN41 in middle foreground, flexed, head to SE, on right side, face north, tight flexure. Square 52CA. Direction East.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Douglas Osborne</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-03</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Middle Archaic; Late Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[6BN39] Juvenile female in good condition, fully flexed with head to NW, face SW, feet at pelvis, knees at chin, on right side, left arm over legs. This individual very closely flexed, spine curved, left arm has parted at elbow and forearm bones were standing almost vertically. Body had been compressed from all sides. Probably sewed up in skins etc. [6BN40] Mature male in fair to good condition, fully flexed with head NW, face NW, on back and right side, left arm across stomach and hand under knees, right hand at chin, feet at pelvis, knees at right side. Typical. [6BN41] Adult female(?) in fair condition, fully flexed with head to east, face north, on back and right side, left arm at right side and hand under knees, right hand at chin, knees at chin. Typical - this arrangement of hands and arms is usual slightly more on back and right side than is common.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Institution has small illustrations of the burials on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>6BN40(1)</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>6BN39; 6BN40; 6BN41</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>38BN12(A)</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00236</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007261</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
