<record>
  <dc:title>194BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY187, an adult male in foreground intrusive to 16BY188, an indeterminate adult in middle background. Skulls of 16BY189, 190 show at left under 16BY188. Legs of 16BY190 show between 16BY187, 188. Square 13L2. Direction SE.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-19</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY187] Adult male in poor condition, extended on back with head to SW. Pit from plowzone detected vertically but not traced horizontally until base of level 2. Pit first showed as single pit but there is adequate evidence that more than one pit existed--at least three pits are present. 189 and 190 seem to have single pit. 16BY188 has separate pit from 16BY187. 187 is intrusive to 188 and has cut away right side of 188, thus 187 is latest of group. 187 lies partly on subsoil and partly on fill of pit for 16BY189, 190. Total height from vertex to plantar surface of calcaneus is 5.65'. [16BY188] Indeterminate adult in poor condition, extended on back with head to SW. Pit from plow zone is precedent to and separate from pit 16BY187 although they could not be separated until just above the bones. Pit fill a very dark humus. Left side of 16BY188 present but right side disturbed by 16BY187, these bones probably represented 16BY185, found in upper part of pit. This will have to be separated in the laboratory. Skull on base, mouth slightly open. Bones rest on fill of pits below 16BY189, 190 which are probably precedent to 188. Several foot bones were found in fill and are probably from 16BY188. Along left side of 188 at same level were three undifferentiated river pebbles, 0.3' - 0.6' diameter. Bones are quite waxy and in poor shape. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations available on file. See photograph 196BY13 for burials 189 and 190.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>4134; 4104</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY187; 16BY188</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>194BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00497</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007516</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
