<record>
  <dc:title>161BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY112, a mature male. Part of skull lies south of main portion. Square 8R2. Direction South.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-06</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Mature male in good condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit from plowzone filled with rather dark mixed clay and humus. Pit cuts into pit of 16BY117. Bones rest 0.2' above bottom of pit. Skull face up, but tipped back, chin highest. Part of skull lies to right of main part of skull. Left shoulder higher but burial not on side. Left wrist and hand under pelvis. Left ilium higher than right. Burial does not seem disturbed as all bones are in articulation. Perhaps original deposition may account for position. Feet somewhat scattered, apparently propped at end of pit. Pit rectangular at level of bones. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>2377; 2376</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY112</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>161BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00470</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007489</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
