<record>
  <dc:title>185BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burials 16BY154, an indeterminate child on top; 16BY164, an adult male; 16By165, an adult male on bottom. Shell spoon (F.S. 3638) between tibiae of 16BY164. Square 10CA. Direction SE.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-10</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY154] Indeterminate infant in good condition, extended on back with head to SW. Deposited 0.1' to 0.2' above torso of 16BY164--oriented in opposite direction. It is definitely evident that 16BY154 is simltaneous with 164 and 165. Possibly the absence of a skull for 164 suggests that the skull was disturbed and removed by the intrusion of 154. A few calcined cranial fragments were recovered in the fill of the pit. The soil in which the charcoal recovered for dendrochronology is embedded shows a moderate amount of burning to a depth of 0.2' below and about the same above as though the live embers had been covered at time of burial with the upper fill of the pit. The top of the fill of the entire pit and lower portions in the northeast two thirds of the pit contained a large quantity of chunks of burned clay and charcoal scattered through the loose black fill of the pit. Only the soil around the large, charred piece of wood showed burning in situ. [16BY164] Mature male in fair condition, extended on back with head to NE. Tibia and second cuneiform of left foot at pelvis between femora. Left hand disturbed. Phalanges scattered between femora. Fragments of calcined cranial bones in fill of pit may have been the remains of the skull for this individual. 164 and 165 are probably simultaneous and have been intruded upon by 154. See forms for evidence of fire in pit. [16BY165] Mature male in poor condition, extended on back with head to NE. Approximately simultaneous with 16BY164. The calcined cranial fragments found in the fill of the pit may conceivably belong to 165--however, it seems more likely that the skull of 165 had deteriorated completely in keeping with the condition of the other bones of the skeleton. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>3526; 3527; 3528; 3640; 3676; 3638</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY154; 16BY164; 16BY165</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>185BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials; Artifacts</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00490</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007509</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
