<record>
  <dc:title>178BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY141 and 142 with 143 beneath. Square 7R3. Direction NE.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-30</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY141] Mature female in good condition, extended on back with head to NW. Pit from Level 2 filled with dark mixed soil. Pit may originate at base of plow though this is not certain. 16BY141 must be earlier than 16BY140 as ribs extend under 140. Burial 141 is subsequent to 16BY143 as pit extends under 141. Bones of 141 lay on subsoil except where over 16BY143. Neck arched up and head tipped back so that chin is higher than frontal. Ribs on left slumped outward, right ribs arched up in nearly normal position. Right radius only present and proximal end 0.7' above distal end. Hand somewhat disturbed but seems in main to be in articulation. Left radius and ulna seem to be in articulation, also hand. Pelvis lower (0.1'-0.2') than feet and skull, apparently settled into pit of 16BY143. [16BY142] Indeterminate infant in fair condition, extended on back with head to NW. In same pit as 16BY141. Lay between femora of 16BY141, skull almost touching pubic bones. Bones lay on fill of pit 16BY143. Appears to be on back, face up. Arms and legs somewhat disturbed but must be extended. Left leg appears to be piled beside left side. Ribs somewhat scattered and arms seem to be extended. [16BY143] Adult male in good condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit filled with dark humic soil, extends under burials 16BY141, 142. Bones lie very slightly above bottom of pit. This is then the earliest burial of the group, also the deepest. Not disturbed by other burials. Left leg straight, right leg slumped outward somewhat. Skull very slightly to right. Arms fully extended. There seems to be little or no posthumous shifting of the bones. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file. See photograph 172BY13 for burials 16BY141, 142.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>2833; 2976</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY141; 16BY142; 16BY143</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>178BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00484</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007503</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
