<record>
  <dc:title>151BY13/152BY13 [2x exposure] Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burials 16BY86 and 87. Square 5R3. Direction SE.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-27</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 -1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY86] Adult female in good condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit from plowzone filled with mixed clay and humus. Considerable burned bark and wood mixed in pit fill. Pit of 16BY87 was connected with 16BY86 at top just below plowline, forming one large pit about 7' square. About 10' below plowzone, pit divided into two separate parts, depth of pits may have necessitated considerable breadth at top, thus running pits together. Bones resting on subsoil. Head about 0.1' higher than feet. Mouth open. Right arm partly under pelvis. Knees together. Feet slightly apart. Little or no posthumous shifting of bones. [16BY87] Adult male in good condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit was same at top as 16BY86, divided below in to two pits. Bones lay on subsoil. Skull about 0.2' higher than feet. Face slightly to left, mouth open. Left arm partly under pelvis. Knees slightly apart, feet together. Left tibia posthumously rolled slightly to left. It cannot be definitely said that these are simultaneous, but pits ran together at top. Pits had two large postholes between them. This may well be a case of pits accidentally touching. Pit more rectangular just above bones.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1881</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY86; 16BY87</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>151BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00464</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007483</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
