<record>
  <dc:title>191BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY179, an adult male with projectile point (F.S. 4042) over sixth left rib and three long bone tools (F.S. 4040, 4041) at left side. Decayed bark over lumbar and frontal region. 16BY178 shows in background. Square 13L6. Direction South.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-16</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY179] Adult male in fair condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit from plowzone filled with mixed clay and humus is subsequent to pit of 16BY178. Pit more rectangular just above bones. Bones lay on subsoil. Remains of black decayed wood on frontal and at lumbar vertebrae--seems to be back over body. Triangular projectile point lay on sixth left rib. Point anterior and medial (on line from left elbow to chin). May be wound as it lay in direct contact with rib. One bone tool lay on left forearm, others under left hand. Blunt points of tools are proximal to arm. Right knee slumped inward--displacement seems mainly of femur. Large precedent post hole at feet. [16BY178] Adult female in fair condition, extended on back with head to west. Pit precedent to 16BY179, filled with fairly dark mixed clay and humus. Pit more rectangular at level of bones. Bones lay under pieces of wood--could only be preserved over left shoulder, but appeared to have been present over whole body. Wood decayed. Bones lay on subsoil, cervical vertebrae disturbed and face disturbed, possibly by rodents. Forearms slightly away from pelvis. Shell hairpins lay under skull at mastoid. Skull tipped back to rest on lambdoidal region. Left patella missing.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file. See photograph 192BY13 also.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>3898; 3899; 4039; 4040; 4041; 4042; 4050; 4051</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY179; 16BY178</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>191BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00495</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007514</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
