<record>
  <dc:title>17-601 Lea Farm, Anderson County, Tennessee. Mound 1, burial 1. Old adult female in poor condition. Head to southeast, knees flexed, one hand at shoulder, one at hips, placed on left side, face down. Partly flexed.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Anderson</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Oval shaped pit. Found in association was a portion of a small pottery vessel placed over the legs at knees, badly broken up. One small hammerstone placed with burial 15" west of face, two small pots under the head, one setting on the other, both whole but cracked. Beside the pots was a shale hoe, rectangular in shape with rounded corners.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photograph 17-602.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1; 2</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>1</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>17-601</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00041</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005109</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
