<record>
  <dc:title>123BN25 Ledbetter, Benton County, Tennessee. Burials 9BN74 and 9BN75. Left is burial 9BN75; to right with bannerstone and shell beads is burial 9BN74; at top shows burial 9BN73; in background is burial 9BN76. Direction North.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>George A. Lidberg</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-11-15</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[9BN73] indeterminate juvenile fully flexed in fair condition, head to WSW, deposited on back with legs flexed back over body.[9BN74] Mature male in fair condition, partly flexed with head to NW, deposited in sitting position. Lay at the base of Stratum II. It's vertebrae, sacrum, and the skull position indicate that the original position was a sitting one with the torso erect. The right leg is extended in front of the skeleton and the tibia is bent upwards from the knee. The left leg is disturbed but seems to have been flexed back underneath the femur and to the left. The beads were apparently around the individual's neck. The banner stone lay on the left humerus. [9BN75] Adult male in good condition, partly flexed with head to ESE, deposited "sitting" with skull slumped over. This burial has been disturbed. One leg is missing and much of the torso. The beads are near the knee but may be associated with the burial below. [9BN76] Adult male in good condition, fully flexed with head to west, deposited sitting up. This burial lay in stratum II. It was an other example of sitting up. Projectile point lay next to right forearm.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>9BN74(1); 9BN74(2); 9BN75(1); 9BN76(1)</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>9BN73; 9BN74; 9BN75; 9BN76</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>123BN25</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00193</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000006340</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
