<record>
  <dc:title>236BN12 Eva, Benton County, Tennessee. Burial 6BN196. </dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>D. Osborne</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-11-20</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Middle Archaic; Late Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Burial with 2 atlatls on right side, head West, left arm over legs, atlatl A above, atlatl B below body, partly flexed, old juvenile, probably male, feet at pelvis. Direction SE. I like this. There were 2 atlatls included as mortuary furnishing. The weight (banner) of the first lies over the left hand. It is a tubular object, revised at both ends. The antler tip lies directly under the chin with the hook facing the bannerstone. The second bannerstone lies within the crook of the left elbow. The hook is below the heel of the right foot. This second atlatl seemingly was placed below the body before burial, while the first was placed over the body. The burial is in the extreme bottom of St. II and the St. II material has stained and permeated the St. III sand around the burial. Red ochre was placed both under and over the pelvis and lumbar regions. The ends of the bannerstones were sealed with paraffin. The material within should be subjected to microscopic analysis - this might reveal wood - etc. of the shaft. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available through institution. Field specimens listed on burial data form as: # 1 - hook, # 2 - banner, # 3 - bannerstone, # 4 - atlatl hook, # 5 - red ochre.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1; 2; 3; 4; 5</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>6BN196</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>236BN12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00164</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000006317</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
