<record>
  <dc:title>155BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY96, extended child in center foreground; 16BY97, an adult female bundle burial at left; 16BY98, a juvenile bundle burial at right; 16BY100 is an extended child in background. Square 5R10. Direction NW.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>George A. Lidberg</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-06</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY96] Indeterminate juvenile in good condition, extended on back with head to SW. This burial lay in between two bundle burials 16BY97 and 98. It was thought that these burials might have been previous to the 16BY96 interment. They all lay in the same long pit. The length of the pit would lead one to believe that it may have been a simultaneous burial. This burial lay on subsoil. [16BY97] Adult female in good condition, bones in a heap. This was a bundle burial at the feet of 16BY96 and in the same pit. It lay on subsoil as did 16BY96 and seems to have been buried simultaneously with 16BY96 and 16BY98 (see drawing for 16BY96). The pit was intrusive from the plowline and was filled with mixed humic soil, clay and detritus. The presence of these bundle burials (16BY97 and 16BY98) is unexplainable from any evidence from this pit. [16BY98] Indeterminate juvenile in good condition, bones in a heap. This bundle burial lay at the head of 16BY96 (see drawing). It lay a little below 16BY97 but on the subsoil as did 16BY96 and 16BY97. It consisted of a heap of long bones, etc. with the skull lying on top. It is perhaps simultaneous with 16BY96 and 16BY97. The fill of the pit was a mixed humic and clayey soil. [16BY100] Indeterminate child in poor condition, extended on back with head to NE. This burial lay in a pit intrusive from base of plow line. Matrix of pit was mixed humic soil and clay. The bones that were missing seemed to have disappeared because of deterioration and perhaps disturbing by rodents. It lay on subsoil and about 2.0' from pit of 16BY96, 97, 98, but is not associated. The pit, however, is parallel to the pit of 16BY96, 97, 98. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>2084; 2162</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY96; 16BY97; 16BY98; 16BY100</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>155BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00465</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007484</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
