<record>
  <dc:title>64BN12 Eva, Benton County, Tennessee. Burials 6BN90, 6BN91, 6BN92, and 6BN93. 6BN90 - adult female in foreground. Red ochre in patches over pelvis, ribs and scapula. Cut bird bead in abdominal cavity. Green material at pelvis. Stratum II bottom. 6BN91 - dog burial, on top right. Stratum II bottom. 6BN92 - adult beneath and in background. Stratum II or III. 6BN93 - background to left. Adult female(?), dorsal part disturbed. Square 50R2. Direction West.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Douglas Osborne</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-21</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Middle Archaic; Late Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[6BN90] Adult female in good condition. Complete but broken. Fully flexed on left side, left arm folded beneath, right over body, feet at pelvis, head oriented to south. Check the pigments, many bits of ochre around and over the body. [6BN91] Indeterminate juvenile dog burial in poor condition, incomplete burial. These associated burials are questionable, some are certainly associated, probably 93 is not the associated but the disturbed burial. [6BN92] Adult in good condition. Fully flexed on right side and back, face north, knees at face, left hand and right, at face, feet at pelvis, head oriented SW. Fairly complete burial. There may be some pieces of scrap bone here from, possible, burial 93. Am not sure with which burials this is associated - probably all but 93. [6BN93] Adult female(?) in good condition, fragmentary burial. Fully flexed on right side with head oriented SE. This burial, at least dorsal, (southern) part badly disturbed by intrusion of burial 92.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations available through institution. </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>6BN90(1); 6BN90(2); 6BN90(3)</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>6BN90; 6BN91; 6BN92; 6BN93</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>64BN12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Dog Burial; Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00262</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007286</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
