<record>
  <dc:title>400AN15 Johnson Farm, Anderson County, Tennessee. Burial 2 - (top) Young adult female in good condition. Head to south, lying on right side, face to right. Fully flexed. Burial 3 - (bottom) Indeterminate infant in fair condition (skull broken by shovel). Head to east, lying on back, arms along sides. Partially flexed.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Anderson</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Burial 2] Both hands between legs at pubis bone and child one foot from end of foot. Two clay vessels are associated with this burial; one between face and knees, the other touching right temporal bone. [Burial 3] Skull 1' north of left foot of adult. Workman cut through skull of this burial before discovery. Probable cause of disarrangement of 1 leg (one leg flexed back over pelvis).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Photo taken from the north.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:burial_number>2; 3</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>400AN15</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials; Artifacts</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00023</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005091</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
