<record>
  <dc:title>186BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley County, Tennessee. Burial 16BY171, an adult female below with femora having been removed and placed on 16BY170, a mature male lying across it. In the background is 16BY172, an infant skull. Square 14R13. Direction South.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>William Beatty Jr.</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-11</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[16BY170] Mature male in fair condition, extended on back with head to SW. (Frontal bone broken during excavation). Buried intrusive to burial below. Femurs of 16BY171 at datum depth 7.4. Skull lying on occipital. [16BY171] Adult female in fair condition, extended on back with head to NW. 16BY170 more recent, obviously pit for 170 burial goes through 171 at femurs. Left femur of 171 on top of left radius of 170. Right femur of 171 lying across left femur and pelvis of 170. Skull of 171 crushed and turned slightly to west. Skull lying on occipital. [16BY172] Indeterminate infant in fair condition, extended on back with head to NW. Top of skull only, lying on occipital. Decomposition rather than disturbance seems to be the reason for the absence of the long bones. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>3779; 3778</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>16BY170; 16BY171; 16BY172</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>186BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>mcr00491</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000007510</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Restricted Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
