<record>
  <dc:title>189BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. General Progress Photograph</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Adena and Woodland Mound Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-04</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Boone</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Tombs shown are 35, 28, 29, 26, 36, 30, 34, 25. Also intrusive pits are Feature #21 and 22. Various segments of profile with the 90' face the main "backdrop". Photograph taken from the north of the subjects and from atop the tower. On the foreground block extreme left (105-110' section) is exposed a part of the Tomb #35 (Feature #23) consisting of a prepared bark floor on which lay a mica encased tubular stone pipe ... F.S #27. The small strip of profile behind the exposed portion of this tomb is from the 105' face and indicates by the incised lines the two earth walls around this tomb with the earth between being that of the collapsed earth roof. The collapse of this roof cause the slumping of the floor on the superimposed Tomb #26, a small remaining corner of which is shown just above this profile in the 100-105' section. To the right of Tomb #35 is indicated the partly exposed Tomb #28 (Feature #38) insofar as it lies in the 100-110' section. The profile (100') shows the collapsed loading of the roof of this tomb. On the extreme right lower block is the completely exposed Tomb #29 (Feature #32). On the block against which the stadia pole is resting and to the right of it are the Tombs 36 (Feature #31) and 30 (Feature #33) from left to right and only partly exposed. On the upper block center can be seen the open log molds of the Tomb #24 (Feature #27) upon which excavating operations have just begun. Against the background profile (90') and to the extreme left is exposed that portion of Tomb #25 lying in the 90-95' section ... the vertical structural data of this one-walled tomb is reflected in the incised lines of the 90' face behind it. Conspicuous in the 90' profile are the large intrusive pit Feature #21 which is a continuation in the profile of the large surface crater evident on surface of the contour of this profile. On the extreme right note the incised lines defining the other large intrusive pit of white origin Feature #22. Between these two pits remains an intact portion of the original mound as indicated by the loading and incise structural lines. Note the large open ground hog hole in this section ... the line marking the base of this was heavily fired and is a continuation of the fired area around Feature #10. In this section, the first two lines up from the bottom on the extreme left, mark a short bark line that evidently was destroyed Tomb #38 (Not Featured). Note above this the tilting loads. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>21; 22; 23; 38; 32; 31; 33; 27; 10</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>189BE3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04689</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200500000000284</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
