<record>
  <dc:title>47BT20, 15BT20, Butler County, Kentucky. Annis Village. Structure 11. Field specimens and occupational debris.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>R.D. Brown</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Late Prehistoric Mississippian Sites in Kentucky</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-7-15</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Butler</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>An experimental photo attempting to show the debris on or near the floor level of Structure 11. Plainly visible, toward the center, are charred pole sections, a grinding stone, and a side of a pot, fragmented. The level on which these specimens lay was one foot below the ground surface. There is, of course, no "floor" as characterized by a cleavage plane, simply a fairly even surface on which most of the debris is uncovered. View from westward.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>47BT20</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Artifacts</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04060</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004124</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
