<record>
  <dc:title>26BT20, 15BT20, Butler County, Kentucky. Annis Village. Structure 1. </dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>R. D. Brown</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Late Prehistoric Mississippian Sites in Kentucky</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-5-23</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Butler</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Wall outline of Structure 1, 18 by 20 feet in size. Stakes on pillars, 10' apart, later removed, were included in this picture to show relation to ground surface. Inside the left wall is a series of halved, excavated postmolds, apparently related to it. although these, and other postmolds (see plat), may represent a reconstruction of this dwelling, or even another later structure unrelated to structure 1. This view is supported by the presence of two fire basins, both shown here, the one complete, the other halved. View from south. See also photo 27. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>26BT20</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04039</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004104</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
