<record>
  <dc:title>29OH13, 15OH13, Ohio County, Kentucky. Bowles Site. 40 Foot Profile.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Green River Archaic Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Ohio</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>40 foot profile from the NW showing the plowed zone, the wide stratum of mixed shell and dirt and the lower-most stratum of almost pure shell. Through my own error this picture also includes a view of the men working in another trench. I forgot to tell them to clear out when I took this photo. We were rushing at this point to complete the work before we had to move off at the request of the property owner.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>29OH13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Stratigraphy</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw01882</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000006882</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
