<record>
  <dc:title>274GP22, 15GP22, Greenup County, Kentucky. Hardin Village. Pits, 248, 252.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.T.R. Bohannan</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Late Prehistoric Fort Ancient Sites in Kentucky</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-11-14</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Fort Ancient</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Greenup</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Pit 252, concave, in left background; Compound Pit 248 in center. Taken from SW. Feature 248: Group of post holes, forming southeast (magn.) corner of House "O", connected by shallow excavations, as shown. Filled with soft dark dirt. Note: This region thoroughly excavated by a ground mole, so photo will show holes not appearing on diagram. Feature 252: Concave pit, sides curving evenly, filled with ash, some dirt admixture in top and bottom. May have been fire pit, but no reddening discernible.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>More information about Features, including diagrams, available at institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1291; 1308; 1309</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>8; 252</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>274GP22</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Pits</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw03012</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003620</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
