<record>
  <dc:title>12BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. 55' Profile and Segment of 50' Profile.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Adena and Woodland Mound Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-10-30</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Boone</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Photograph taken from the south of the 55' Profile and a small portion of the 50' Profile in the foreground block. The profiles in this instance were not incised, an effort being made to see how the essential structure would reveal itself in a photograph without artificial emphasis. The faces have been sprinkled and trowelled damp to clarify soil differences. Structural definition is none too clear; however there is a very evident surface concavity in the central loaded dome of dark earth ... this to become the first indication of a collapsed earth roof dipping into Tomb #1 (Feature #3). This central dome of dark loaded earth with its concavity in the center becomes a compound of two primary mounds or earth tombs, in future cuts, rather than a simple primary structure ... the left eminence being a complete dome of dark loaded earth (later developing into Tomb #4, Feature #37), the right hand eminence being subsequent to the latter and abutting against the east side of it, overlapping somewhat, but on the mound floor in large part ... this to form later Tomb #1, Feature #3.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>12BE3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04512</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200500000000241</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
