<record>
  <dc:title>41BT20, 15BT20, Butler County, Kentucky. Annis Village. Structure 8.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>R. D. Brown</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Late Prehistoric Mississippian Sites in Kentucky</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-6-20</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Butler</wpa:county>
  <wpa:narrative>West end of south wall of Structure 8, sectioned vertically to show depth of wall fill, which at this point is only .4'- .5'. This vertical face included also a postmold, visible in this face but not in the horizontal. This postmold is either incidental or marks the end of the wall. Taken after the complete removal of Structure 7, which appears to be the later structure. View from southwest. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>41BT20</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04054</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004118</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
