<record>
  <dc:title>196BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. General Progress Photograph of the South Side of the Mound.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Adena and Woodland Mound Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-08</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Boone</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Profile segments represented are 65, 70, 75, 80, and 85. Photograph taken from the south side of the mound and from the top of the small photographic table.The small portion of the 65' profile indicates a vertical cross section through the floor of Tomb #4 (Feature #37). And atop this block tomb #5 (Feature #4) is in process of excavation although very indistinct in this photo. The second face back on the right is a portion of the 70' profile and shows nothing of particular strucutral interest. Atop this block is the 70-75' section between stakes R-1 and R-3 is the partly exposed (but not visible) Tomb #32 (Feature #35). The pertinent vertical structural data relative to this tomb is reflected in the 75' profile immediately behind this block ... namely, incised earth walls of either side of the tomb cavity, and the tilting loads of the collapsed earth roof filling the tomb cavity. In this same profile (75) to the left beneath stake L-2 is incised to the top of the earth roof over Tomb #5 which served as the floor of tomb #6. A small band of the 80' profile is exposed and incised from stake R-1 to R-7. By studying this photo in connection with the drawing can be seen vertical section through Tomb #41 (Feature #30), Tomb #40 (not featured), Tomb #9 (Feature #34 ... whose open log mold show), and Tomb #10 (Feautre #39 ... on the roof of Tomb #9). Also evident on the upper right hand corner of this face the incised lines of the intrusive pit Feature #24. The topmost ine in this fave is the bottom of the intrusive pit Feature #21. The background face, upper, is a portion of the 85' profile. Study in connection with the profile drawing. Predominatly evident is the large intrusive pit Feature #21 which extends from apex of the profile almost to the outer right edge ... this is reflected in the huge open crater in the upper surface of the mound evident in this photo. To the left of this intrusion and at the base of the profile is a cross section through the walls and collapsed roof of Tomb #37 (Feature #25) ... note the tilting loads of the collapsed roof.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>37; 4; 35; 30; 39; 24; 21; 25</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>196BE3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04696</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200500000000286</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
