<record>
  <dc:title>19JO14, 15JO14, Johnson County, Kentucky. Mayo. Feature #13.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>James C. Greenacre</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Late Prehistoric Fort Ancient Sites in Kentucky</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-10-25</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Fort Ancient</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Johnson</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Feature #13. A fireplace with burned rock, animal bone, and pottery. An oval shaped fireplace containing bones of deer, bear, fowl. Material uncovered for Photo #19 was 0.60 ft. deep. However other material was below in the ash for a depth of 0.80 ft. May have represented a pit for roasting purposes as evidenced by material found in it. Bottom of pit was a total depth of 1.40 ft. from surface at stk. 100-0.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>More information, including diagram, available at institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>13</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>19JO14</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fireplace</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw03400</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003677</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
