<record>
  <dc:title>218McL11, 15McL11, McLean, Kentucky. Ward Site. General View of Site in Operation.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Green River Archaic Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-18</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Archaic</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McLean</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Photograph taken from the lower deck of the tower toward the east looking across the Cypress Creek bottoms. Indicated is the method of shaving down squares. Note shades covereing men working on burials to prevent the soil from baking around the bones in the severe heat of the sun. The men shaving the squares into the yellow clay are throwing it behind, while those shaving the dark soil of the Habitation Level wheel it to piles on the sides for later restoration.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>218McL11</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>People Lab and Field Scenes</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw01354</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000006602</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
