<record>
  <dc:title>14BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. 55' Profile and 50' Profile.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Adena and Woodland Mound Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-11-03</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Boone</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Photograph taken from the south. Wall of foreground block is the 50' Profile and that behind the 55' Profile. This photo unincised, hence structure speaks for itself as with photo 12BE3 which is of same subject. Indicated in this photo is the same structure as in photo 12BE3 except that it is closer to the subject ... consult sheet for photo 12BE3. Burial 1BE3 is located in the notch removed from the foreground block. The overlapping of the loaded earth of the righthand dark eminence over the left is not apparent because of the extreme indistinctness thereof ... consult profile drawings for this data. The hole in the righthand eminence of the darkly loaded section is a ground-hog burrow. In the 55' Profile at the extreme right where it is interrupted by the foreground block is a small dome of bright yellow and grey horizontal loading that is the east wall of the ring about Tomb #1. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>14BE3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04514</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200500000000242</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
