<record>
  <dc:title>34BE3, 15BE3, Boone County, Kentucky. Robbins Large Mound Site. The 65 and 70' Profiles.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Adena and Woodland Mound Sites</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-12-11</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939  -  1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Boone</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>KY</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative> Photograph taken from the south with profiles incised for emphasis of the essential structure revealed there. These profiles represent only part of each face ... a condition resulting from necessity of terracing the working faces in accordance with safety procedures. The small foreground block supports Log Tomb #1 (Feature #3) as exposed from the 55-65' lines. The first foreground profile is the 65' face. Note the thin band of Old Humus extending from the foreground block of Tomb #1 to the left end of the profile. This largely underlaid the primary brightly loaded dome, which begins just at the left of the foreground block of Tome #1, and extends on beyond it to the left. Note the broad U-shaped line about two feet down from the top of this primary dome ... this is a very faint bark line which evidently indicated the floor of a tomb as yet to be undiscovered in the advance sections. Note the dipping of the loads above this bark line at the ends of this U-shape ... evidently the earth of the collapsed roof. Later investigation indicated that this tomb was not still advanced in the mound, but rather half of it had been cut away in the proceeding 60-65' section and had escaped attention because of its very faint identifying marks .. this is Tomb #4 (Feature #37). Immediately to the right of Tomb #4, and applied to its surface and up over its top, is the west wall of brightly loaded and mixed earth of Tomb #1. Between this and the bright loads of the east wall of this bomb is the dipping loads of the collapsed roof covering a small portion of the north corner of tomb. This profile indicated bark lines and suggestions of faint log molds for Tomb #3 (the tomb taking advantage of the concavity created in the surface of the earth roof of Tomb #1 by its collapse ... these just the remaining fragments of this Tomb #3 since it was removed in the 60-65' section. Note the dipping loads above this ... roof. Note the faint dark hold on the inner shoulder of the east wall of Tomb #1 ... this just the tip of a mold or cast left by a pole suggesting that perhaps it comprised one of the rafters holding the earth roof above this tomb. Immediately above Tomb #1 is the 65' profile; note the uppermost incised line ... this slightly dipping line is the first suggestion of Tomb #31 (Feature #15) which appears in fuller character in the 70' profile. In the 65' profile above the primary dome of Tomb #4 .. note the dipping line with the small tilt projecting at the bottom of this dip. This line has bark on it and is the first section, together with the dipping bright loading above it ... this develops into Tomb #5 in the 70' profile (feature #4). Note the flue-like projecting block from the center of the 65' face. With supports the charred logs of Featured #2 in the 65-70' section. With reference to this feature ... note the filled "saddle" of mixed earth and scattered loads in the 65' face between the brightly loaded and dipping loads of the collapsed roofs of the Tombs #3 and 5 to right and left. Apparently this "swag" had been filled to form a horizontal base for Feature #2. This 70' Profile is only part exposed in the background face. The uppermost layer in this profile is the soft homogeneous yellow-grey fine sandy clay loan ... this is much leached, frozen and root penetrated. On the extreme right of this profile can be seen an overlaying layer that is brightly colored mixed earth thrown out on the mound surface during the pot-holing operations responsible for the large surface crater and Features #21 and 24. The next layer beneath the above is also markedly leached, but hard, and showing mottling and faint scattered loading. Note the charred fragments of logs on the top of block of the 65-70' section behind the flue-like projection on the 65' Profile. These extend into the 70' face ... these are Feature #2. Immediately above Feature #2 in the 70' face is Tomb #2 in vertical section. Note the two irregular walls of faint horizontal loaded earth. Between them and dipping down to the tomb floor level are the very faint loads of the earth roof over the tomb. The holes penetrating this portion of the profile (as well as others) are ground hog burrows, filled or open as the case may be. This tomb present in only a very faint suggestion in the 65' face did not clearly indicate whether these logs might not be a part of the faintly suggested Tomb #3. The demarcation of the fain dipping loads of the roof of this tomb is obviously artificial since it probably flowed over the tomb walls, but this is not clearly evident. This section through Tomb #2 has evidently cut into the floor, yet it revealed neither bark on the floor level nor log molds in cross section. The right-hand surface of the right wall of Tomb #2 dropped so abruptly that it seemed to suggest another tomb whose other wall was the abrupt dome of faint horizontally laded earth, to the right of it there was no clearly marked floor line, either bark or soil color, connecting the two however. Also the intervening earth showed none of the dipping loads suggestive of a tomb roof, it being finely mixed earth with only very faint suggestions of scattered loads. The next profile (the 75' face) indicated this to be a badly mutilated log tomb utilizing the east wall of Tomb #2 as on of its walls ... this develops into Tomb #7 (Feature #14) clearly in the 75' face. Beneath the right hand wall of Tomb #7 is a dome of loaded earth (some mixed earth intervening between it and Tomb #7) which develops into the right hand (or east wall) of Tomb #31. Tomb #31 not visible in this photo except for this portion of wall. Note the intervening layer of mixed and mottled earth between Tomb #2's floor and Feature #2 (the charred logs) ... the bottom of this layer is the top of the earth roof above Tomb #5 and is seen in faint yellow and grey dipping loads immediately to the left and slightly below the left wall of Tomb #2. The upper surface of this roof dips down to form a cavity which was utilized for the construction of Tomb #6. The darker loading beneath these faint roof loads of Tomb #5 comprises the left wall of Tomb #5. Tombs #5 and 6 are thus only slightly indicated by this wall and roof. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>3; 37; 15; 4; 2; 21; 24; 14</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>34BE3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological Museums and Collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kentucky Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>wsw04534</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200500000000252</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>The William S. Webb Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological Museums and Collections; Kentucky Antiquities; University of Kentucky</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004. William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies. Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of the William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology, University of Kentucky.  For all other uses contact: Director, William S. Webb Museum of Anthropology,  University of Kentucky, 211 Lafferty Hall, Lexington, KY 40506-0024.  Phone number for inquiries: 859-257-8208.  Museum Web Site URL: http://www.uky.edu/AS/Anthropology/Museum/museum.htm</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
