<record>
  <dc:title>17SW1 Gray Farm Site 1SW1, Stewart Co., TN. Feature 34, Badly disturbed structure floor with rectangular fire basin. Several masses of clay wattle and charred saplings shown on floor. Also large quantities of sherds and several broken and incomplete posts. No post mold pattern to associate was found. Level 1. Sq. 10L8. Direction south.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Non-Reservoir</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-06-05</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Stewart</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>In Level 1 a section of badly disturbed floor and several masses of clay daub showing cane mat impressions have been found. Lying on this floor is a large amount of pottery sherds and an occasional complete or nearly complete pot as well as a number of other artifacts and a fair number of charred roof saplings, some of which have been saved as dendro specimens. At the level the wall or post mold pattern could not be worked out because of the black humus soil. A few sections of the floor had been especially prepared of puddled clay burnt to a yellowish red; however, these sections were badly disturbed and cracked. Over the rest of the area no prepared floor was apparent. Centrally located was a square fire basin well made of puddled clay burnt a brick red. The sides were vertical and rounded at the corners while the bottom was flat. The rim section was apparently level with the floor. The base was 0.6' deep and 2.1' square. Because of the lack of time to complete excavation, the wall pattern could not be worked out.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:field_specimen>4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 11; 12; 13; 14; 15; 628; 773; 774; 775; 776; 777; 778; 779; 780; 799; 800; 827; 828; 829</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>34</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>17SW1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01688</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003949</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
