<record>
  <dc:title>141BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 9, Showing pit outline and yellow sandy clay (perhaps roof ?). Square 2R6, etc. Direction north. </dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>George A. Lidberg</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-12</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938; 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Feature 9 is a pit of a Semi-subterranean structure with fire basins. The top of the pit was filled with a dark humic soild filled with scattered charcoal and burnt clay. The pit fill was extremely rich, twelve twenty-five pound bags of potsherds being removed from it. The top of the pit sloped from the north to the south, due probably to post-habitation erosion because there is a slight slope to the south on the surface. The pit at the north side was 1.2' deep and at the south 0.6' deep. The sides of the pit were nearly vertical. Above the floor on an irregualr layer of yellow sandy clay were scattered several rocks, all but one large pebble varying from about 0.1' in diameter to about 0.6', and one slab of limestone about 0.2' thick and about 1.4 in diameter. The layer of yellow sandy clay covered roughly the north half of the structure's floor and extended over the firebasins and most of the postmolds; there were a few postmolds that were intrusive to this layer. This layer of clay was in spots laminated in thin layers While this layer covered the firebasins all the detritus lay above it and only a scant layer of dark charcoal filled soil lay beneath the layer and above the floor. The floor was rather indistinct and was not very hard packed.... </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is on file at the institution. See also photograph 153BY13 [fhm00260]. Contact institution for additonal specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: about 200 numbers ranging from 724 to 1807, then non-consecutively from 1815 to 1944.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>724; 911; 1008; 1100; 1207; 1335; 1404; 1506; 1600; 1704; 1806; 1942</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>9</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>141BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00258</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003008</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
