<record>
  <dc:title>10-146 John Ausmus Farm Site 2CE10, Claiborne County, Tennessee. Mound 1. Feature 9, Area of ash and midden material.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Claiborne</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>The area from which these artifacts were taken was covered with burnt logs. These were embedded in ash and midden material. Three or four of the logs were uncovered for a length of three or four feet. They took no definite alignment. Another burnt log was encountered in Square 10.8 at the same level as those in Square 11.8. Squares 12.9, 11.9, 12.8 and 11.8 yielded an immense amount of potsherds. The original humus line which was quite distinct to the west melted away gradually between .10 and .9 into the midden material in which these artifacts were found. No floor line showed up on any of the walls to indicate the presence of a structure to which the burnt logs might have belonged. Neither do the postmolds in this area outline a structure. (See base chart- also profiles 10.0 and 11.0).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:field_specimen>17; 18; 19</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>9</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>10-146</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burnt Area</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00295</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003040</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
