<record>
  <dc:title>107UN7 Wilson Farm Site 12UN7, Union County, Tennessee. [General view of site prior to excavation].</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Union</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Floor was hard and firm composed of dark loam and sand and was irregular in shape. Highest point in mound 18" above floor. Fireplace of hard burnt clay 3 1/2 feet in diameter and 6 inches deep of which 3 inches was above floor. No post molds apparent - probably disturbed by plow. Project started 3-20-1934; finished 3-22-1934.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 106UN7 [fhm01877], 108UN7 [fhm01879], and 109UN7 [fhm01880].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:photograph_number>107UN7</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Mound; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01878</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005068</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
