<record>
  <dc:title>17-1138 Charles Lea Farm Site 4AN17, Anderson County, Tennessee. Village site. Structure pattern showing features 7, 5, and 11. Post molds of structure in trenches 2 and 4.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Anderson</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 7] Shell midden pit had been deposited above remains of structure. Traces of burnt cane were found on floor of structure. Floor hard packed and well defined. Baked clay fire pit near center of structure. Floor of structure was 12" below hardpan. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>No narrative information available for Feature 5 and Feature 11. See also photographs for Feature 7: 17-424 [fhm00029], 17-425 [fhm00030], 17-478 [fhm00035], and 17-504 [fhm00044], Feature 5: 17-419 [fhm00024], Feature 11: 17-479 [fhm00036].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>7; 5; 11</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>17-1138</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00080</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002745</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
