<record>
  <dc:title>207HS12 Patterson Site 71HS12, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Feature 1, Wall trench of Feature 1 ca. 15' below floor. Note many disturbed areas. Square 12R5. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1942-04-03</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1942</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>For detailed drawing see Ground Plan. The purpose for which this structure was built seems rather vague, however, in some respects a Mississippi-like house form is indicated. The use of relatively deep wall trench, baked sections of floor and heavy wall and possibly roof daub are familiar. Variant features would be the oval shape of the wall trench, its irregularity with regard to depth and an apparent lack of posts; none could be truly identified by means of post molds, however, one or two charred log ends in the trench were very suggestive that posts had been used. Burning of the structure was very intense as the heavy layer of daub would indicate. Looters' pits were extremely numerous and had effectively destroyed much of the hoped-for evidence. (these are plotted on the ground plan). The wall trench pattern is very similar to Feature 2 trench and it is possible that they were identical structures. If this is true then the rock wall of Feature 2 was a later addition. Small sections of hard baked floor were found. Looters' pits had torn up much of the floor, while in other places there was no evidence as to why the floor did not remain. This floor indicated the occupational level of the structure. Wall trenches originated at the same level.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file at institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>1</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>207HS12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00992</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004413</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
