<record>
  <dc:title>227HA3 Hixon Mound Site 1HA3, Hamilton Co., TN. Feature 68, Rectangular pattern of small post molds set in trenches. The caved-in top of Feature 77 shows in extreme right of structure. Feature 75, restored bench or seat shows in center of picture and adjacent to charred superstructure lying on floor. Direction northeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-10-26</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>The 4 post molds showing in the vertical cut to the left of the central background are in the northwest corner of Feature 55. The The central depression to the left of Feature 77 is the opening to a pit beneath the floor of Feature 68. [Feature 68] From the quantities of burned clay and fragmentary charcoal over and around this structure it had apparently burned after or during use. (Sketch on reverse side). Possibly a little more than half of the entire prepared floor area remained. Intrusive burial pits were partially responsible.... I did not suspect the structure extended so far to the west because of the absence of flooring. However the length of trench on the SE side suggests that its parallel mate was at least as long. Subsequent checking with earlier ground plans shows the possible extent of NW trench to the west by the presence of a few intermittant post molds. Feature 68 was no doubt an important structure in the village life at a time previous to mound construction.... No postmolds showed in the trench in contact with pit or immediately to the south. [Feature 77] Burial pit covered with flat limestone slabs. This pit was an elongated rectangle with somewhat rounded corners, dug from the floor level in Feature 68. The burial was covered with numerous limestone slabs supported by wooden cross pieces which had given way and let the slabs in on the burial. A few fragments of mineralized wood were apparent immediately above the skeleton and indicated that the wood ran crosswise of the grave. [Feature 75] This block was built up of made earth from the floor level of Feature 68 and plastered with a mixture of sandy clay - subsequently burned. It is long, low and oblong in shape with rounded corners and edges. Apparently the plastered surface was damaged in use or after deconstruction of Feature 68, becuase the surface was rough and broken. The damaged areas were restored accurately with mud before photographing the general layout of Feature 68. [Feature 55] Burned clay floor and rectangular postmold pattern at Floor R level. The floor of this structure consisted of burned packed clay. The quantity of charred superstructure (cane, bark, thatch and logs) on the floor suggest that the structure had burned, possibly explaining the thorough burning of the floor.... A fill of about 0.5' (average) intervened between the floor and the top of the old humus layer (Level #2).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is available at the institution. There is no record on file for this photograph. However, narrative information regarding Features 68, 77, 75, and 55 are available from other Feature Data Forms. See also photographs 223HA3 [fhm00896], 224HA3 [fhm00897], and 225HA3 [fhm00898].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>827; 835; 857; 864; 703; 700; 792; 809; 829; 852; 860; 845</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>68; 77; 75; 55</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>227HA3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00900</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003205</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
