<record>
  <dc:title>225HA3 Hixon Mound Site 1HA3, Hamilton Co., TN. North corner of Feature 68 showing post molds and disorderly mass of charred wood, cane and thatch lying on the floor and inside the limits of the structure. Direction southwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-10-26</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Hard, burned clay floor and associated wall trenches and post molds of a rectangular small pole structure. From the quantities of burned clay and framentary charcoal over and around this structure it had apparently burned after or during use. (Sketch on reverse side). Possibly a little more than half of the entire prepared floor area remained. Intrusive burial pits were partially responsible.... I did not suspect the structure extended so far to the west because of the absence of flooring. However, the length of trench on the SE side suggests that its parallel mate was as least as long. Subsequent checking with earlier ground plans shows the possible extent of NW trench to the west by the presence of a few intermittent postmolds. Feature 68 was no doubt an important structure in the village life at a time previous to mound construction.... No postmolds showed in the trench in contact with pit or immediately to the south.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narative information and observer illustrations available at the institution. See also photographs 223HA3 [fhm00896], 224HA3 [fhm00897], and 227HA3 [fhm00900].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>700; 792; 809; 829; 852</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>68</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>225HA3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00898</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003203</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
