<record>
  <dc:title>23RE12 DeArmond Site 2RE12, Roane County, Tennessee. Feature 5, Longitudinal cross-section view of the NE wall of structure showing widely spaced molds and their depths. Sq. 34R9. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-12-11</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian; Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>House number 5. [Feature 5] Several patches of hard burned floor also shown. Entrance on side nearest the camera shown by two additional post-molds and two horizontal molds projecting from structure wall. [Feature 5] This structure is of the "pit" type but differed from Feature 7 in that no "wall trench" was used, and that the individual posts were rather widely separated, although at the corners 3 holes were found closer together than along the length of the walls. The floor was irregular and somewhat disturbed, however it had been especially prepared. In many sections it was burnt hard and well smoothed while in other areas it was of unburned clay. Centrally located was a large circular fire basin that had two floors separated by a layer of ash. The lowest section was used by this structure, while the second phase was used by Feature 9. A curb was built around the basin and used during the first period. The roof was supported by large interior posts placed at the four corners and ca. 3' inside of the corner of the walls. The house pit was identified by the concentration of a mass of midden material that had been thrown into the pit after the abandonment of the dwelling, and by flecks of daub which was found in greatest concentration near the floor, however this material was not very abundant. Since there was no evidence of destruction by fire, no evidence on superstructure was available. The entrance was on the East side and probably was in the form of a tunnel. The ground plan evidence consisted of an offset in the outline of the pit and on the floor of this area were two parallel log molds on opposite sides. This passageway entered the dwelling through the wall at a point where a change in the post mold pattern allowed a wider section. This dwelling lies directly below Feature 9, a structure built just after the abandonment of this house and used the same fire basin.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>37 Field Specimen numbers are on file at the insitution and range from 592 - 873 then 959, 1024 and1026. See also photograph 17RE12 [fhm01539].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>592; 604; 808; 706; 959; 1024</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>5</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>23RE12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Post Molds</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01543</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003814</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
