<record>
  <dc:title>176RE12 DeArmond Site 3RE12, Roane Co., TN. View of mound with Phase "D" removed and superstructure of Feature 16 on summit exposed. Shows embankment encircling summit, small platform in foreground with ramp leading up to it, and post holes of arbor on platform and post holes along edges of ramp. Direction southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>John Alden</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-27</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 16] Square, small post, house with superstructure. Feature 16 was the only house on the summit of Phase E. This house was square with walls built of poles about 0.2' in diameter standing upright, rather close together in irregular rows. The large scale drawing of Feature 16 shows these wall post fairly accurately, but some post are undoubtedly missing. It should be noted that at intervals of 1.5' to 2.0' (where the walls are fairly complete) an extra upright post was placed next to a wall post but on the inside of the row. These were presumabaly reinforcements. The only gap in post hole rows which seemed natural and at the same time, significant, is the one in the center of the southeast wall. This was probably the entrance. The entrance may have been the 3 foot onewith one side at stake 49L1, or it may have been as wide as 10 feet, with one side at 7.5' N, 3.0'W of 48L1 and the other at 5.0'N, 4.5'W of 49CA. This wider gap, containing only a few irregularly placed post holes, also contains two of the burned basins (mentioned later), which would probably not be inserted in the real wall of the house. For better understanding of this problem, refer to the comments on these burned basins, and also to the large scale ground plan. While a lot of charred superstructure was found on the floor, not much information on superstructure was acquired. Grass thatch was found along the walls, the longitudinal axis being such that the grass evidently hung vertically. Many instances were found of cane lying under the thatch, so cane was probably attached to the outside of the wall posts, in all likelihood, horizontally. The grass probably hung from the cane. In squares 49CA and 49L1 on the large scale plan, will be seen poles lying on top of each other at approximately right angles. This immediately suggests that horizontal poles were attached to the vertical posts. Since they are all about the same size, there is no telling whether the horizontals were on the inside or outside of the walls. Note that on the ground plan it cannot be ascertained whether the uppermost logs are vertical posts or horizontal poles. Several specimens of matting were found on the floor in a charred condition. Some of this was found wrapped under a wall (or roof) pole with some charred string. Another specimen found on the firebasin also indicated that the matting was a wall fixture and not placed on the floor. Very few postholes were found in the interior of the house. Most of these could probably be explained as furniture posts. However, a peculiar pattern of seven burned stumps of posts was found between the fireplace and the northwest wall (See large scale ground plan). Whether these posts are the remains fo an interior compartment, or whether they might have supported a platform or large elevated seat, could not be ascertained. Some sort of throne makes an attractive guess but nothing more. The pattern's lack of concentricity with the form of the house makes the roof support and unlikely function. The firebasin was oriented so that the sides were parallel with the walls of the house. It was built of sand, with a thin coat of clay, which had burned hard and reddish purple. Of particular interest waas a small hole in the center of the pit bottom. This and the pit were full of ash. For dope on Pit 7, Burial 82, and Feature 16A (antler workshop) see the respective forms. It is worthy, in passing, to consider the wide spread functional possibilities in the light of the the latter two associations. Finally, the fifteen shallow burned basins should be noted. The walls were lined with charcoal, which had a thin lining of burned sand, the interior containing unburned sand. Note their placement: a row of five along the southwest wall inside, one outside the south corner "in front", one on each side of the entrance, one between fire basin and entrance, and a group of six between fire basin and northeast wall, two of which are replacements. Their is probably due to a short lived fire smothered with sand. They may have served as lamps or beacons. Mention should be made of the low, clay covered sand embankment encircling the house and the summit of the mound. This was definitely a part of the mound fill, and not fallen roof dirt. This rather looks like an imitation of semi-subterranean houses. It should be remembered that the burned roof was partly covered with burned sand, possibly placed on roof while in use. The usefullness of this is doubtfull. [Feature 17] "Brush arbor" This structure was mounted on the platform extending out from the front (southeast) side of Phase E. It was contemporaneous with Feature 16, the house on Phase E and was a part of the "ceremonial" complex of this stage in mound development. The brush arbor consisted of two parallel rows of small, closely set poles. These rows were approximately 9 feet long, and were approximately 14 feet apart. Their longitudinal axes lay almost exactly NW - SE. The front (southeast) wall was set back in from the southeastern ends of the side walls approximately 1.7 feet. This front wall had post moldds of 0.4' to 0.6' in diameter. There were seven of these large molds set with fairly regular interstaces of 1.5'. This wall ran NE-SW. Between the third and fourth mold from the southwest end fo the wall was a gap of 2.9'. Between these two large molds were two small, relatively shallow ones. It is thought that this was the entrance, and that these two small posts may have supported or secured some kind of a sill. There was no back wall to this structure unless it was supported without the use of posts set in holes, which is unlikely. However, since this was the side next to the principle structure (Feature 16) it was probably left open. The floor of the structure (and top of the platform) was burned. The burning wasn't over 0.1' deep and was not particularly even. It is not known whether this was the result of a burning structure or was intentional preparation. There was no trace of burned superstructure on the floor. There was not even the burned sand which was found over, mixed with, and under the burned roofing of Feature 16. It should be remembered, however, that the front edge of the platform protruded and was used during the occupation of Phase D. At least part, and probably all, of the platform was, therefore, cleaned off, if there was anything to clear away. It should be noted that the back (northwestern) ends of the side walls are intrusive to the clay covered embankment encircling the summit of Phase E. (See ground plan of Phase E for general relationships). [Feature 18] This ramp was attached to the center of the front (southeast) face of the platform of Phase E. Its inclined surface was very compact and irregular from being walked on, but it could not be said that it had steps on it. No trace of logs were found. However, along each side of the inclined plane was a row of small postmolds. Seven were found on one side, eight on the other. Note the symmetry of their placement, even the double holes near the bottom. This ramp was built of clay, much lighter in color than that which went into the platform. Thus, the contact between the two was clearly visible. However it is thought that the ramp was applied immediately after the construction of the platform, and accordingly, no separation was made during excavation. Several functions for the postmolds on the ramp might be suggested. The most obvious would be that they supported a hand rail or bannister. Posts in these holes may have supported a cover of some sort, on the order of a marquee. A final and less likely function would be to anchor wooden log steps laid crossways on the inclined surface. Placed on the down-slope side of the logs, these pegs would keep the logs from rolling or slipping. In refutation of this it should be remembered that no trace of wood was found, that the holes are not quite similarly placed in relation to the inclined surface of the ramp (the southwest row is on the inclined surface, the northeast row is slightly over the slope), and that regular depressions were found across the inclined surface. These would certainly result if the log steps were walked on much. The post holes were about 0.2' in diameter, and 0.8' deep.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 178RE12[fhm01577], 179RE12 [fhm01578], 181RE12 [fhm01579], 182(B)RE12 [fhm01580], </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1071; 916; 917; 913; 732; 729; 728; 727; 726; 712; 711; 1260</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>16; 17; 18</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>176RE12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation; Mound; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01575</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003846</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
