<record>
  <dc:title>5RE12 DeArmond Site 2RE12, Roane Co., TN. Feature 2, a north-south cross-section view of kettle shaped pit showing contents of charred wood on bottom, overlying layer of ash, and upper layer of mussel shell, stones and midden soil. Central mass of loam and large stone in upper section apparently dropped from above. Sq. 35L12-13. Direction east.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>W.C. Walker</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-11-24</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This pit was almost identical with Feature 1 pit. It was circular in shape with a narrower top circumference, giving it a kettle-shaped body form. The cross-section view on back shows distribution of pit contents. The bottom of the pit was covered with a layer of charred saplings, over which was a layer of ash, and above this a layer of mussel shells and midden soil and stones. The central mass of loam soil and large rock seems to have dropped in from above. Sherds examined were grit or limestone tempered. The pit most likely was used for cooking purposes and its proximity to Feature 1 pit and the fact that they both originated at about the same level, suggest that they may have been in use simultaneously.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>462; 463</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>2</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>5RE12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category> Pit</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01531</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003802</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
