<record>
  <dc:title>59MN3 Mouse Creek Site 4MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 16, Ridge of compact wattle and loose bits of wattle intact. Sq. 24L1. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-05-11</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Semi-subterranean structure - last 1/4 not excavated as it lay under cornfield. Walls of pit 1.9' deep at S-W side probably indicating minimum original depth of these houses. Walls of pit were very vertical with a slight tendency to be undercut. Just inside pit edge was a zone of nearly pure clay which was sharply set off from fill of pit. This seemed to be a bank built up between edge of pit and peripheral post molds, perhaps to reinforce the posts Below the bank and co-extensive with it was a very shallow trench, 0.1 - 0.2' below floor, in which there were no visible postmolds. this may have been a drainage feature. No postmolds were found in the trench so that it cannot be a structural feature. Floor was generally flat and level and was covered with layer of hard packed occupational detritus. Wattle apparently filled almost entire pit and was mostly composed of small fragments showing some grass impressions. SW of firebasin were two long ridges of higher wattle running NE-SW. These proved to be collapsed interior partitions. The western one was badly broken and consisted of a long pile of large pieces of wattle in definite briquettes with one flat side and cane impressions on the reverse. The eastern partition had the lower 0.7 in place in unbroken state. It consisted of a wall 0.7 wide at the base with smooth sides and horizontal canes running the length of it. Vertical posts apparently ran up through a hypothetical reconstruction indicated a height of 1.9. These partitions apparently divided house rooms or cubicles. Between walls was considerable burned canes and grass perhaps indicating beds or other furniture. Under wattle on floor were considerable quantities of burned beams and cane. Not much could be learned as the material was very fragmentary. An area of burned floor surrounded the firebasin, for a considerable distance. It seemed to be simply burned detritus and not a prepared floor. West of basin was an inclusive burial, 4MN55. This burial had been dug into floor and earth from pit not all returned, clay was subsequently packed hard and could be easily separated from original floor. Burned material was found above pit. Entance passage consisted of two sets of passages - apparently a repair arrangement. Inside entrance had a separate step set off by shallow trenches. Upper surface of step was burned. At either side of entrance was small narrow trench along side of pit. It did not connect with larger trench. First basin was rectangular with vertical walls and flat bottom. Second basin was built slightly to SW and was circular with vertical walls, flat bottom and well made rounded curb. Basin #1 burned 0.1d, basin #2, burned 0.1d, common floor area burned 0.3' d. Walls and floor of both basins were composed of hard baked puddled clay, curb of basin #2 was softer and showed some grass impressions. In center of NW side was small step-like projection from pit wall that extended up to top of pit and between this is a step or simply an unexcavated portion that could not be determined. See notebook pp 123, 124, 126.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>List of 28 Field Specimens is on file at the institution. See also photographs 56MN3 [fhm01368], 58MN3 [fhm01370], 60MN3 [fhm01372], 61MN3 [fhm01373], and 62MN3 [fhm01374].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>993; 997; 1003; 1004; 1007; 1018; 1039; 1044; 1094</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>16</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>59MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Wattle</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01371</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001568</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
