<record>
  <dc:title>105MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. In lower foreground depressions on south slope of Level E west of Feature 39 pyramidal mound suggest toe-holds. These may have afforded access to the summit of Feature 39 mound. Direction south.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-03-25</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This pyramid mound is in the Southwest section of Level E. The South slope is very steep and runs from a D.D. of 17.5' to a D.D. of 23' at bottom. The slope has an incline of Ca. 80 degrees. The East slope forms the junction with Feat. 38 mound with the ramp 38c and 39c connecting the two at the Northeast corner of the mound. The North slope is very sharp, being almost vertical but dropping only Ca. 1.5' to a terrace (Feat. 41 floor). On the West side the slope is rather sharp for a drop of Ca. 2' in a horizontal distance of 6'. In the next 6', it levels out almost flat before the final drop to the outer edge of Level E. On the south side slope just west of the mound proper, are a number of toe holds on the side slope. These lead up to the flat area. then on the southwest corner of the mound on the first steep slope a crude step has been built and below this another small leg mold. It would appear that this arrangement is a sort of secondary approach to the top of the mound. On the South slope of this mound slightly East of the center point is a very well made ramp (39B) with well defined steps out into it. On the top is a flat area 25' x 17' and somewhat East of the center is a very well made clay platform (Feat. 39A). In back of the seat is a row of post molds running across the width of the mound. At the extreme west end is another such row. This would indicate that some sort of canopy was placed over the seat. Feature 40 lies over the north section of the mound surface. The floor was well made and possibly hardened by fire, although this may have been accidentally done when Feature 41 burned.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>No record on file for this photograph, however Feature Data Form for Feature 39 is available. Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 93MG31 [fhm01208], 99MG31 [fhm01213], 103MG31 [fhm01217], 104MG31 [fhm01218], 107MG31 [fhm01221], 109MG31 [fhm01223], and 115MG31 [fhm01227].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>39</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>105MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation; People Lab and Field Scenes</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01219</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000021</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
