<record>
  <dc:title>BMG31(C) Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Level E1, Building [Feature] 43 Fireplace.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-03-21</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian; Late Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative> [Feature 43] This structure is rectangular in shape and is delineated by deep rather evenly spaced post molds. A fairly hard, well made floor of packed sandy clay burnt dull red in many areas runs directly to the post molds, leaving no sign of a wall trench. However, on the inside of the post molds and just below the floor is a log mold. On the floor are a number of misc. post molds most of which are a the western end back of the platform 43A. Roughly these divide this section into small compartments. The subfeatures on the floor are independently described. This location is shown on the plat for this structure. The platform, two pits and fire basin are all on an east-west central axis through the structure. Feature 40B encircled this structure lying heavily over certain sections of the post mold pattern, while over the entire floor, thin in the central sections and much thicker toward the wall was a mass of clay that in all likelihood fell from the roof. From this evidence it becomes evident that this structure was an earth lodge in all essential respect similar in form (see Feature 41 form) to Feature 41. There is practically no burnt material on the floor of this structure -- just a little piece of thatch at the southwest corner. The log mold on the inside of the post mold pattern in ca 6' deep but ranges from .3' to .9'. The effect is exactly what one would expect if the small ends of saplings were doubled over the end of another sapling where two were laid together, end to end. This, of course, was necessary because it would have been very difficult to have found single saplings long enough to have reached the length of the wall. These log molds were found only on the north and south walls and were not present for the east and west walls. Further no log mold was bound at the bottom of the post molds on the opposite side; however molds were set in a wall trench. [Feature 43C] This fire basin is on the E-W central axis through the structure [Feature 43], is square and raised above the floor 0.1'. The basin is of very interesting form. The curb or base is Ca. 0.9' wide on each side. Then there is a drop of 0.2' to a square inside basin in the center of which is a circular depressed basin. The basin is made of puddled clay burnt brick red. When found, the entire basin was covered with a layer of white ashes which also lay in the basin proper.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>No record on file for this photograph, however narrative information is available for Features 43 and 43C. See also photographs 103MG31 [fhm01217], 106MG31 [fhm01220], 112MG31 [fhm01224], 113MG31 [fhm01225], 114MG31 [fhm01226], 118MG31(A) [fhm01230], 118MG31(B) [fhm01231], 120MG31 [fhm01233], 126MG31 [fhm01235], 134MG31 [fhm01239], 139MG31 [fhm01242], BMG31(E) [fhm01290], BMG31(F) [fhm01291], BMG31(G) [fhm01292], BMG31(H) [fhm01293].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>43; 43C</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>BMG31(C)</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01288</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000090</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
