<record>
  <dc:title>26RH41 Hampton Farm Site 86RH41, Rhea County, Tennessee. Pit number 15, Kettle-shaped pit in cross section (same pit as 24RH41 photo) Sq. 18R1. Direction southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Wendell C. Walker</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-12-08</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Rhea</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>A very distinct example of the kettle-shaped variety of pits. Pit is circular with inward sloping walls toward top, rounding at bottom to a very gently rounded bottom, almost flat through central section. Pit fill dark humus with a layer of shell (mussel and univalve variety) with charcoal flecks about midway up from bottom. A number of cracked stone, some animal bones present.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photograph 24RH41 [fhm01624].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>P15-1; P15-2; P15-3; P15-4; P15-5; P15-6; P15-7; P15-8</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:photograph_number>26RH41</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category> Pit</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01626</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003897</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
