<record>
  <dc:title>33RH41 Hampton Farm Site 86RH41, Rhea County, Tennessee. Pit number 2, Stratum II midden pit, in cross section. Sq. 19R3. Direction south-southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Wendell C. Walker</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-11-20</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Rhea</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>A deep midden pit, circular in shape and associating with Stratum II. The pit body had a slight tendency toward being kettle-shaped in cross section but not as pronounced as in the so-called cooking pits. Pit fill comprised of dark midden soil with an abundance of cracked stone, univalve shell (periwinkle) and mussel shell. Several pieces of worked bone were found in this pit. The bottom was flat and there may have been a slight tendency toward a flaring orifice but this was not definitely visible due to the homogeneity of the soil.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>P2-1; P2-2; P2-3; P2-4; P2-5; P2-6; P2-7; P2-8; P2-9; P2-10; P2-11; P2-12; P2-13; P2-14; P2-15; P2-16; P2-17; P2-18; P2-19; P2-20</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:photograph_number>33RH41</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Pit</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01628</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003899</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
