<record>
  <dc:title>49SW1 Gray Farm Site 3SW1, Stewart County, Tennessee. Association of Feature 4 with 1 and 2. Feature 4, trench filled with stone underlying Feature 1 stone wall (also mound Phase B) trench associated with Phase C. Square 9. Direction southeast. </dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Non-Reservoir</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-07-22</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Stewart</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Inside of Feature 4 are four large post molds, two in each section, placed so close together that their tops merge. In the background is Feature 2 associated with Phase C. [Feature 4] This feature is a wide continuous wall trench filled with loose rock. The trench encloses an oval area in which 3SW13 cremation was found. The south, east, and west sections of this wall underlie Feature 1 rock wall while the north section is under the side slope of Mound Phase C, thus associating this feature with Phase C. In the central section are four post molds set in pairs at opposite ends of the enclosure. Noted on burial form 3SW13 is a series of large burnt logs lying between these molds and indicating the presence of a long narrow scaffold. The actual use to which this rock-filled trench was put can only be conjectured; however, two points of evidence are helpful: First, at one place in the trench a butt end of a sapling stuck into the rocks and projected inward, Second, lying over the burial for an average depth of ca. 0.2' was a mass of heavily burnt earth. These two factors would indicate a structure of some sort over the central scaffold. The evidence suggests sapling stuck or wedged into the rock trench and sloped to a common apex. Over this dome arrangement was placed a covering of earth. This crematory structure is contemporaneous with Feature 2, Phase C, and it was not until after the burning of the burial had taken place and Phase C Mound was constructed that Feature 1 rock wall was constructed. [Feature 1]Oval rock wall encircling a mass crematory basin of Burial 3SW13. While excavating a north-south trench through this mound in the central section of the ramp, rock walls were encountered running at right angles across the trench and ca. 20' apart. These walls were made up of small chert rocks ranging from the size of a man's fist to the size of his head and piled up without any attempt at fitting or masonry. The walls ran up to within a few inches of the surface of the ramp and hence the north wall was very much higher than the south one. This north wall seemed to have been built up on the side slope of the original mound as a sort of rock facing. The wall was traced and the oval outline worked out before the earth fill inside was worked out. Except for the size of this rock wall the external appearance was very similar to that associated with Burial 3SW9, however, with this difference: that the rock of burial 9 was simply a ring around the top of the burial pit while this was a wall of stone built up from the burial level. The top earth inside this rock area was typical of the ramp fill except in square 9 and 9R1 where an oval column of burnt clay extended from a few inches below the surface to the underlying floor of the burial mass. At a datum depth of ca. 7', this burnt clay spread over the entire area within the rock wall. This burnt clay was removed with trowels and revealed a large number of cremated individuals and evidence of charred logs. This burnt material ran back under the north rock wall and hence several feet of it had to be removed in order to trowel out the burial. This seems to indicate that the wall was built after the burial had taken place. There seemed to have been two general groups of burials here, a central group showing the most burning and a group to the East end that ranged from semi-cremation to bones showing no burning... It is important to realize that this rock wall was built after the cremation was completed and after Mound Phase C was built over Feature 2 rock pile and after Feature 4, the original rock wall of this burial tomb (3SW13), was partially covered by the fill of Phase C. This last point is of extreme importance in interpreting this entire burial complex with relation to the time element as can be seen from the 'notes' and digramatic sketch. This wall has been called inclusive in Phase B; actually it is Phase B, being called so because, 1st, it overlies Phase C (although its underlying association with C) and, 2nd, it is covered by Phase A with which it is not definitely associated. The time element here is indicated as being consecutive and quite rapid because, first, Phase C includes Feature 2 and the actual crematory period of 3SW1. second, Phase B was built shortly after the cremation was completed , and , third covered by Phase A, probably with little lapse of time. [Feature 2] This rock pile was rectangular in shape and was very carefully made by the piling of small rocks over the entire area. While the rock pile is flat on top, it slopes from east to west. On the west side there was only a single layer of rock lying on the old humus while at the east-end there were several layers of rock. When these rocks were removed, a gray humic band was found and in some areas this was quite black, however there wasn't the slightest sign of bone, and if any burials had been present it was impossible to identify such remains, unless those areas that were so black could be so identified. It would seem that burials should be effected here if direct comparison is made with 6SW1. It is to be noted that the soil was extremely wet or moist when the rocks were removed and it is probable that this was a contributing factor.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 25SW1 [fhm01695], 26SW1 [fhm01696], 35SW1 [fhm01703], 48SW1 [fhm01710], 50SW1 [fhm01712], and 51SW1 [fhm01713].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>4; 1; 2</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>49SW1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Stone Wall</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01711</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004383</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
