<record>
  <dc:title>41MN3 Mouse Creek Site 4MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 4, with two fire basins. Burial 32 lies in corner of house at left side of picture. Sq. 12L14. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-04-19</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Irregular, rectangular house structure with two fire basins -- pit house. Raised, burned floor area in center of structure -- flush with tops of fire basins I and II. No roof wattle. Inset in pit outline in east corner and southeast side. Entry trenches entirely inside pit outline in east corner. Burial 4MN32, and infant in north corner of house -- pit in floor of house. Two piles of water worn rocks -- one in north half of house and one in south half of house. Pit outlines show clearly where they exist so there can not be any mistake in regard to relationship of entry trenches to pit outline. Large postmold or pit between two fire basins contained water worn rocks. The burned floor area flush with the tops of the fire basins was raised from 0.2' to 0.3' above the general floor area of the house. Several postmolds were apparent when the burned floor area was removed -- doubtful if these were associated with the house -- at least they were not apparent as penetrating through the butned clay. Fire basin 1 appeared circular to the eye, but shows to be slightly ovoid when plotted on the ground plan. The fire basins were rather shallow and bowl shaped -- no raised or modelled rim. The edge of firebasin II, where it projects beyond the edge of the floor, was partially destroyed so that only the bottom and a suggestion of the curve of the side remained. T.M.N. Lewis suggested it would not be necessary to make a large scale drawing of the house in that a draftsman could redraw the structure at approximately the same scale it is shown on the ground plan for publication. The observer may draw his own conclusions regarding any pattern for the interior post molds, by referring to the ground plan.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:field_specimen>298; 304; 310; 323; 324; 325; 334; 362; 363; 366; 380; 384; 385; 391; 442</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>4</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>41MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01360</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001557</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
