<record>
  <dc:title>23MN3 Mouse Creek Site 3MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 16, Dwelling house floor pattern with probable entryway in right foreground. 3 central fireplaces were associated with the pattern. Sq. 15L7. Direction southwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-04-08</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>The structure presents most of the features of the characteristic semi-subterranean house pattern -- common in this region -- however no pit could be discerned. The 4 rows of outer wall posts were remarkably regular and evenly spaced -- the confusion of interior post molds obtained as in most of these structures -- a small quantity of wattle still remained in the central portions of the structure. What appears to be an entry way is shown on the southeast wall of the structure. Three separate fire basins were uncovered apparently representing periods of destruction and recontruction of separate fire basins. The wattle over the central portion of the house averaged about 0.3' in thickness and the top was 0.5 above the floor level. Soft black fill lay between the wattle and floor. A rather large, deep pit, irregular in outline was sunk in the floor about 3.0 northeast of the fire basin it contained black, humic fill and some charred wood and cane, very fragmentary, and medium sized water worn stones. A large shallow depressed area in the floor was adjacent to the fire basin 2 on the north. It contained several medium sized water worn stones -- the edges of the pit were sloping and tended to merge with floor. It was filled with mixed soil and had a compacted crust over the top apparently having been filled in and packed down during occupancy. Large potsherds were scattered through the fill of both pits. Several post molds were apparent in the bottoms of the pit.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments> 43 field specimens taken, all numbers on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>762; 932; 699; 732</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>16</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>23MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01353</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001550</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
