<record>
  <dc:title>98BY11 Rymer Site 15BY11, Bradley Co., TN. Features 37 and 44, Semi-subterranean structures with central firebasins and entrance passages. Feature 37 to the right, and Feature 44, to the left. Square 29R1. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Unburned wattle lies on Feature 44 floor. [Feature 37] Semi-subterranean structure with outline nearly complete - SW side of pit cut away in approach. Walls of pit were very slightly sloped outward. Entrance trench at SE side had inside trench. It was disturbed at exterior end by intrusive shallow pit. Wattle over floor was mainly in small peices but seemed to be fairly hard and contained grass impressions. Under wattle and on floor were remains of burned thatch which appeared to be small sherds of either grass or bark. Floor extended around basin hard and smooth, was burned red 0.2' deep. Firebasin was rectangular with rounded corner. Curb was well built and rounded; wall vertical and hard. Basin filled with ash and some wattle; bottom was burned 0.3' deep. Large post hole NE of basin and touching it is intrusive. On southeast side near corner shallow intensive pit cuts edge of coutersink, does not seem to be associated with structure. Two burial pits containing three burials cut floor. These definitely cut floor but wattle seemed to extend over them to some extent. However, fragments of wattle were found in pits below floor level thus indicating intrusion after collapse of house. Pit to southeast contained one burial 15BY11. Pit to southwest contained two burials apparently simultaneous interrments - 15BY161 and 15BY162. [Feature 44] Semi-subterranean structure which seems to be the most intact of any yet encountered in regard to depth of pit. Pit was traced to depth of 1.0' and seems to have been originally 1.7' at least deep. Walls of pit nearly vertical. Wattle over floor was about 0.5' over and west of firebasin, grading down to 0.1' at edges. Wattle in main unburned but small areas burned even red - I believe this is not due to burning of structure but to burning in place before collapse of structure. Under wattle were remains of bark and/or cane thatch. Wattle cut at burial pits showing definitely that they were intrusive to structure. Wattle did not show cane or grass impressions even in burned areas. Floor baked hard mainly east and south of firebasin. Firebasin well made, lined with hard puddled clay and burned red 0.1 1/2' below bottom. Basin slightly rectangular in shape, walls vertical, curb probably once present but nearly gone now. On northwest side near west corner a pile of 22 small 0.3 dia, broken pebbles - these seem to be associated with Feature as pile touches wall, were probably in pit dug just outside house. Few stones scattered on floor. Floor fairly flat and level. Little [?] detritus above subsoil. Two entrances were found in southeast side. There is no evidence of another structure here as that entrance must be subsequent passages for same house, one being abandoned for some reason. Southern one is cut by Burials 15BY163, 15BY164, but as these cut the wattle and are subsequent to collapse of Feature 44 they could not be the reason for abandoning this trench. A large hole north of basin, 0.2 deep may have been a pit but no evidence of heat and comparatively small size lead me to believe it is simply a large post. Fill above wattle was very rich in sherds, the exceptional depth of this countersink as found probably accounts for large amounts of sherds found. Northern entrance appears to have a cross trench across outside but this may actually be caused by intrusive post holes.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>For Feature 44, see also photographs 99BY11 [fhm00246], and 102BY11 [fhm00249]. Contact institution for specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: 2002 - 2003, 2006 - 2022; 2026 - 2048</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1677; 1907; 1932; 2002; 2006; 2026; 2034; 2037; 2060; 2070; 2121; 2137</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>37; 44</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>98BY11</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00245</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002995</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
