<record>
  <dc:title>66HA3(B) Hixon Mound Site 1HA3, Hamilton Co., TN. Feature 11, Small rectangular post mold pattern in old occupation layer to east of mound 1HA3. Sq. 22L3. Three views [A, B, and C]. Direction south.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-06-19</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Posts set in narrow trenches. Raised platform denotes area of indurated floor. Outline of small rectangular structure. 4 interior corner posts and 6 interior posts; two and three along sides. All ten posts are conspicuously larger than the wall posts. Small wall posts set in trenches. Hard packed floor in eastern 1/3 of building. Two large exterior post molds about 5.0' west from SE to NE corners. One large post in middle in eastern third of structure. Partially burned soil on floor suggesting evidence of fireplace.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Photographs 66HA3(A) [fhm00843] and 66HA3(C) [fhm00845] are of the same view and feature.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>11</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>66HA3(B)</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00844</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003150</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
