<record>
  <dc:title>245HA1 Dallas Site 7HA1, Hamilton Co., TN. Feature 8. Dwelling house floor pattern upon which lie scanty remains of burned superstructure, two pottery vessels and several stones. A burned area is outlined in the center of the floor. Dimensions 15' x 15'. Arrow points to north. Depth below surface 2'. Stake number 44L5. Direction west-northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-12-04</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936; 1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 5 is associated with Feature 8]. [Feature 8]Over the floor of this structure was a considerable mass of split cane matting and an occasional charred log. However, the charred material doesn't give any indication of structural form. In the center of the structure is a circular burned area; probably the fireplace. A number of stones, averaging 1-1/2" thick and 3" to 4" long, were lying on the floor of the structure, many of them near pots. The inference is that they were used in heating water, etc. This inference is strengthened by the fact that a stone was found inside one pot. The post molds were found at the outer edge of the burned area. In order to find them, it was necessary to cut down below the floor level. Except at the NW corner, the corners were square and the post molds were vertical, showing no tilt to indicate that the posts might have been pulled inward. The fact that burnt clay lay over the entire structure indicates that the roof as well as the walls have been plastered with clay. The presence of smoothed wattle work indicates that the clay had been fired on the structure, but the point is debatable. [Feature 5] This burned area overlies considerable charcoal and burned cane, and in many places the clay is in the form of wattle work. It averages .2' to .3' in depth. In square 45L5 a burial pit (7HA8 - 7HA9) was sunk through the clay from above level. The burned clay is more heavily concentrated on the southern half of the structure and overlay the post molds of the south wall.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments> Observer illustration on file at the institution. </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>81; 82; 83; 86; 87; 88; 89</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>8; 5</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>245HA1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01949</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005082</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
