<record>
  <dc:title>23RH41 Hampton Farm Site 85RH41, Rhea County, Tennessee. House number 12, Central fire basin, circular with modeled rim. Small jar (on ash FS 12-11) Sq. 9CA. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Wendell C. Walker</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-15</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Rhea</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Pit house mold pattern of rectangular dwelling. This structure was one of the best examples of the Mississippi pit house that this observer has witnessed. It comprised a large rectangular post mold pattern lying inside a house pit of the same general shape. The walls of the house were delineated by rather large postmolds with wide interstices and a tendency to lean inward toward the top. The floor was mostly accretive with a general burned appearance around the outer edges, but in the central section, ranging south, southeast, and southwest of the firebasin was a fair-sized area of prepared clay floor, which though burned black, seemed to be a section of prepared clay floor. The central fire basin was of puddled clay with sloping walls, a flat bottom and a modeled rim extending above the level of the floor. This rim was damaged in many places, probably from general use. The basin was filled with brown wood ash. Information on the superstructure was the most informative encountered by this excavator. Charred timbers lay on the floor in such a manner as to suggest rafters radiating from the center of the dwelling. Some of these pieces of wood seem to be logs that had been split, while others may have been round saplings. Slightly to the northeast were several parallel pieces of charred wood that lay more or less at right angles to the rafter pieces, these suggesting that they may have been incorporated in the side walls, or that they may hae been lashed to the rafters as a part of the roof construction. Most of the wall molds still contained large sections of the parts and many of these were burned off to the level of the floor. Some of the wood identified was pine. About midway between the walls of the house and the fire basin was a series of interior molds, most of these containing the charred ends of posts. These molds ranging from 1.1' to 2.2 in depth, described a roughtly circular pattern inside the house and gives weight to the theory that radial rafters were involved in the method of construction of this dwelling. These timbers referred to as rafters did not extend completely to the walls of the house. Overlying the central section of the floor and the timbers on it was a somewhat irregular mass or concentration of burned daub. The location of the material is the center of the house and above the fire basin suggests that the radial rafters may have joined in the center to form a smoke hole in the roof, this being heavily plastered with daub as a prevention against the fire hazard. Several pieces of this daub also indicated that it had been plastered on split logs. Other charred material found scattered over the floor included burned grass thatch and a few pieces of charred cane. This material was not found in large enough quantities or good enough condition to be very informative. The depth of the house pit below its point of origin averaged about 1.0' from top to floor just inside the walls. The house pit sloped inward to the walls and there was also general sloping of the floor toward the center. This, however, was rather gradual, the floor around the basin being only about 0.5; lower than the floor around the edges of the house. Overlying the cloved superstructure and daub concentration was a general deposit of midden material, much of this fire blackened and permeated with small particles of burned daub. This material filled the house pit. Because of the fire blackened appearance of much of this midden it is suggested that this may indicate that the house was heaped with earth before it was destroyed by fire. The general slope of the house, with its sweeping corners, could very well have appeared circular in its completed state. This, it seems, would be particularly true, if radial rafters were used and the whole affair heaped with earth. Culture materia found scattered on the floor was rather plentiful. Several large sherds, artifacts and large stones were found in good association. Many of these stones were badly cracked by the heat from the conflagration. Among the materials found on the floor were several piles of charred beans or seeds, possibly two different varities. Charred walnuts were also found and in an location near the E wall cracked walnuts were found around two stones, this apparently representing a nut cracking station. Resting in the ash in the central fire basin was a diminutive jar with a rather crude in and design around the rim. A brass ring from the floor suggest the late aspects of this dwelling. This home was located by an E-W trench, which cut through the south section. No indication was seen of an entrance, but it does not seem likely that this trench could have completely destroyed such evidence. This home was intrusive to House No. 13, and underlying structure. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Field specimen numbers on file at the institution and range from 12-1 to 12-46. See also photographs 19RH41 [fhm01620], 21RH41 [fhm01621], and 22RH41 [fhm01622].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>12-1; 12-46; DS-3; DS-4; DS-8; DS-9; DS-10</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>12</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>23RH41</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category> Fire Basin</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01623</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003894</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
