<record>
  <dc:title>55MN3 Mouse Creek Site 4MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 13 showing depressed floor, fireplace and excavated postmolds. Sq. 20L9. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-05-09</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>The fire basin had apparently been rehabilitated. The upper portions of the sides and the curbing having been replastered with roughly puddled clay to a thickness of 0.1' to 0.2'. The bottom had no additional clay added. The bottom was burned to a thickness of 0.4', and the rim and sides showed abundant grass fiber impressions in cross-section. A shallow depression or pit 0.3' deep had been scooped out in the floor immediately south of the central burned clay floor. It was filled with the mottled clay and humus that accumulates in shallow depressions in the floor -- no regular or very distinct outline was apparent. A small limestone slab lay at one edge of this pit at the level of the burned clay floor. A collection (24) of small water worn stones were imbedded in basic clay half within and half out of the house pit about midway of the northwest side. It was impossible to determine their relation to the house, but since the inside stones were not encountered until the floor was cut out it seems probable that they were precedent to the house. The depth of the pit at this point amounted to little more than 0.1' so the fact that the stones showed higher on the outside than on the inside might be accounted for an uneveness in the deposition of the stones. The complex entryway shown on the ground plan probably represents two distinct entryways separate in point of time though it was impossible to determine which was precedent. The roof wattle with the exception of two small outlying patches was centrally disposed - it was separated from the floor by a thin layer of black organic soil. The wattle showed the impressions of logs and cane and grass fiber admixture. The fill of the pit was black organic soil flecked with burned clay - a moderate amount of cultural material was recovered from the fill and the floor. The central portion of floor around the fireplace was roughly puddled and burned and compacted. The posts were discernible in the remainder of the house in the compacted unburned floor about 0.2' lower than the central burned floor. No posts apparent as intrusive through the burned clay floor. The observer may draw his own inference in regard to an interior post mold pattern by referring to the large scale drawing.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>List of 22 Field Specimens is on file at the institution. See also photograph 54MN3 [fhm01366].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>910; 775; 810;</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>13</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>55MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; People Lab and Field Scenes; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01367</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001564</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
