<record>
  <dc:title>88UN4 McCarty Farm Site 6aUN4, Union County, Tennessee. Rock shelter. Opening to east. Cave measured 6' high in front, 6'6" wide in front, extending 8' to rear from front, and 6' high at rear. Relics found in shelter included pot sherds with and without handles, 1 broken arrow point, skeleton of an animal, beaver jaw, and two bear teeth.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Union</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Interior filled in on rock floor with loose stones and earth, mixed with charcoal and ashes to a depth of 3 feet. The cave measured 6 feet high in front, 6 feet 6 inches wide in front, extending 8 feet to rear from front, and 6 feet high at rear. The cave is located in a bluff above Powell river opening to the east, and about 40 feet above the river. The cave is 10 feet below the upper edge of the rock bluff. Relics found in shelter included pot sherds with and without handles, 1 broken arrow point, skeleton of an animal, beaver jaw and two bear teeth.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>88UN4</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Rock Shelter</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01767</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004418</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
