<record>
  <dc:title>10-433 John Ausmus Farm Site 2CE10, Claiborne County, Tennessee. Mound 1. Feature 20, Relationship of seventh and eighth structures.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Claiborne</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Floor level of eighth structure 4 ft. 4 in. above hardpan (at center) of structure. Floor level of seventh structure 3 ft. 3 in. above hardpan (at center) of structure. See attached diagram (the floors of these structures sloped slightly toward the center).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 10-435 [fhm00340], 10-432 [fhm00337], and CE10(K) (945-TVA) [fhm00380], and CE10(M) (944-TVA) [fhm00382].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>20</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>10-433</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation; Mound</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00338</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002900</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
