<record>
  <dc:title>273RE33 Tarwater Site 116RE33, Roane County, Tennessee. Feature 1, Shell mound. Shell mound rising from Stratum IV. Sq. 60CA. Direction southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1941-06-30</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This feature represents a shell mound or 'heap' laid upon Strata IV by a people who preceded the Upper Valley Woodland group. The mound was composed entirely of a small species of mussel shell (see specimen (8)). Included specimens were rare and largely just small pieces of animal bones. The whole mound must be considered a dump heap resting on Strat IV which apparently was a small village area. Village area here yielded a few pieces of worked bone. Since worked bone is atypical of the Southeastern Woodland it is thought that this area is evidence of the Archaic.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photograph 272RE33 [fhm01603].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1-1; 1-2; 1-3; 1-4; 1-5; 1-6; 1-7; 1-8</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>1</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>273RE33</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Shell Mound; Mound</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01604</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003875</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
