<record>
  <dc:title>16HS1 Slayden Site 3HS1, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Same as 15HS1, Rectangular structure with square corners. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1935-12-17</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1935</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 14] A rectangular structure oriented with the long axis North and South. At the North end is a double wall, the outside wall of which extends eastward and under Feature 23 to stake 15.8. From the datum readings it would appear that the structure is on a lower level than the circular one (Feature 23). The east side of this structure is 1.5' beneath the surface, however the west side is only a few tenths of a foot below. This is probably due to the fact that this side is on the west slope of the mound (natural rise) and the plow has dragged the soil away thus leaving the West wall near the surface. [Feature 15] A small fire bed of red baked clay hollowed out in the center into a basin shape. It was filled with charcoal. This fire basin is associated with structure 14 and is in the SE corner. [Feature 16] A square firebed, 1' below surface, hollowed out into a basin shape and was filled with charcoal. This seems to have been the main fire bed in structure 14, and was fairly close to the center.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative and observer illustrations are on file at the institution. See also photographs 14HS1 [fhm00946], 15HS1 [fhm00947], and 27HS1 [fhm00953].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>12; 13; 14</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>14; 15; 16</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>16HS1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00948</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004369</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
