<record>
  <dc:title>13-73 Bullock [Farm] Cave Site 8CP13, Campbell County, Tennessee. Mouth of Bullock Cave in winter. </dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Campbell</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>One-half mile from Lindsay Mill, Campbell Co., TN. Midden deposit located along north side near entrance to a distance of 60 feet to the rear. South side washed down to bedrock by drainage water from field. Excavations made south of entrance by unknown party of men from Kentucky about ten years ago. Local inhabitants advise that several burials were found. ...</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative and observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photograph 13-74 [fhm01886].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:photograph_number>13-73</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Cave; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01885</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005075</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
