<record>
  <dc:title>67MG31(B) Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Level D, Showing Feature 25 in foreground and Features 26, 27, and 28 in rear. At this level the substructure assumed a pyramidal conformation and is shown partially blocked out in the photograph. Same as photograph 67MG31(A) but made with 6-1/2" lens. Direction east.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-10-06</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 25] This structure is the first encountered on level D and differs in several respects from those of level C. It is somewhat larger than those of level C and was apparently much better made. The floor, while not baked, is nevertheless of very hard packed mottled clay and sand from which the above earth cleaves sharply. In several places the floor has sunk slightly where the earth undernearth it has settled and this may indicate pits; at other places the floor has been cut thru by pits and here it must be noted that these pits appear to originate at the floor level and either associated with the structure or were dug just before the structure was abandoned and burnt. The structure is equipped with two fire basins and one seat. The fire basins are duplicates, one of the other, being raised .2' to .3' above the floor on rect. burnt clay blocks 3' by 4'; while the basins themselves are 1' by 2'. These ___ basins are on the central long axis of the structure and divide the center point of the structure between them. The seat is built up from the floor ca. 1' and in two steps, the topmost section being smaller. It is made of hard packed mottled clay and sand, but was not burnt. It is located along the south wall and directly south of the westernmost fire basin. That the structure was burnt can be seen by the charred posts, cane, and thatch all along the north wall and about half of the east wall. Some of the posts have fallen over onto the structure in these areas, but of the total structure only very little remains to give evidence of superstructure form from observing the position of the burnt material. The following facts can be ascertained. (1) Posts were set in wall molds completely around the structure in a vertical position. At the corners the posts were much smaller than elsewhere although there are none outside of the wall trench to close the corners. Exception at the S.W. corner. The wall trenches do not join together at the corners. (2) Outside the posts splt can, probably in the form of matting, was laid close up against the posts to form a wall. (3) The third step apparently was to lay an earthen bank against the posts on the inside of the structure and against the cane mats on the outside, to height of several inches. (4) Next thatch was placed over the cane mats on the outside of the structure and run down over the earthen embankment to establish drainage and weatherproof walls. A point of extreme interest is that nowhere in the excavation of this structure was there any evidence of dirt having been placed on the walls of the structure. The earth lying against the charred thatch was the same unburnt black humic loading material that is shown for level D fill. There is little or no evidence for roof construction except that overlying the more central parts of the structure floor was ca. 3" of mottled sandy clay from which the above earth cleaved sharply. This earth in all likelyhood fell from the roof and this gives evidence of the finishing material used on the roof. On the floor plan there are indications of an entranceway but nothing as to the form of the door thru the wall. At the SW corner the wall trenches lack 2' of connecting and at the end of each trench is a small post mold from which the door could have been hung. On the floor leading to this corner is a series of flat limestone rocks that may well have formed a sort of paved walkway to and from the entrance. That the entrance is so narrow is confirmation of many historical accounts.... [Feature 26] Very small almost square structure delineated by post molds. No wall molds apparent. Post molds have been found for south, east, and west walls but it has been impossible to find them for the north wall although much time has been spent looking for them. Floor is hard packed with a burnt area near the center. A puzzling feature is that the floor has a break in it straight across the structure E - W and a hard paced floor-like area goes down under the structure floor beyond. This seems to be due to the facet that this structure was built after Features 25 and 27 as an afterthought and so it became necessary to patch and slightly build up the area of Level D from the center of the structure to the south. Structure has only three walls and may have been built as a storage room for some special occasion. In effect it is a lean-to constructed so the the open north end was against the south wall of Feature 27. [Feature 27] This structure is delineated by post molds set in wall molds with open corners and corner post molds. The floor is of hard packed sandy mottled clay and rather irregular. A few misc. post molds are scattered about the floor. The centrally located fire basin is raised off the floor ca .1' to 2' and is 1.3' in width, and .4' deep. The rim is .4' to .5' in width. Just north of the fire basin is a cache pit 5.5' in length, 2.5' in width and 3.6' deep. The wall structure is of interest because, while the 1st 5 or 6 molds on each wall at each corner are vertical the rest of them slant inward at the bottom at about a 5 degree angle. This would indicate some outward stress from the roof, equally divided between the four walls but not at the corners. This would indicate a rather heavy roof construction. Since the corners appear to be unaffected by this roof stress (possibly because of greater reinforcement) the rest of the walls would have to give outward to relieve the roof stress if not strong enough to resist it. Of further interest are the very small post (stake) molds along the inside edge of the wall molds. They apparently were to keep a long log in place in the wall trench on the inside of the posts. In removing the charred material along the W. wall the cane construction is apparent as was used for Feature 25. However the cane matting appears more abundant. Little can be said of the roof construction although several burnt areas and unburned logs from the roof are found on the floor.... [Feature 28] This structure is practically identical with Feature 27 and so nearly the same level that for large areas the floor was the same for both dwellings. This can be seen by the fire basin which had been cut down horizontally so that the floor of Feature 27 could be placed over it. This basin apparently had been very well made of puddled clay. It is circular with a diameter of 1.9' and a present depth of .4'. As to whether or not it was raised above the floor no statement can be made since it had been cut partially away to allow the building of Feature 27. The structure is delineated by post molds set in wall molds. Corners are open. Only in the wall trenches is there burnt material that furnishes evidence that the dwelling burned. Since the structure was cleared before Feature 27 was built the mass of charred material was not found and hence no evidence as to superstructure form. The post molds show the same slant as was recorded for Feature 27, but there is no sign of the small stake molds of Feature 27.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative and observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 63MG31 [fhm01181], 65MG31 [fhm01182], 66MG31 [fhm01183], 67MG31(A) [fhm01184], 68MG31 [fhm01186], 69MG31 [fhm01187], 70MG31 [fhm01188], 71MG31 [fhm01189], 72MG31(A) [fhm01190], 72MG31(B) [fhm01191], 74MG31 [fhm01192], 76MG31 [fhm01194], 77MG31 [fhm01195], 78MG31 [fhm01196],79MG31 [fhm01197], BMG31(I) [fhm01294], BMG31(J) [fhm01295], BMG31(L) [fhm01296], BMG31(M) [fhm01297], and BMG31(O) [fhm01299].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>256; 257; 258; 259; 252</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>25; 26; 27; 28</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>67MG31(B)</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01185</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004560</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
