<record>
  <dc:title>43HS1 Slayden Site 3HS1, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Features 19 and 21 of Unit 3. Square structure with round corners. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1935-12-09</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1935</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Structure 19 at the west precedes structure 21 in point of time. [Feature 19] This is one of two identified structures that lie one above the other, the top one (F.19), being about 10' further west than the lower one. There are a few miscellaneous post molds inside this structure having an average depth of 10", but no fire beds, refuse pits or cache pits are present. The floor of this structure was worked down 2" or 3" in an attempt to find any such pit. Over the Northwest corner was an extensive burned area that seems to represent a burning or at levels partial burning of the structure. This area runs underneath the west wall at the north end and cornered with Feature 35, another burned area over Structure 11. The evidence, then, is that originally Structure 11 burned; the ground was then leveled off leaving the charcoal, etc. lying in place. Then Structure 19 was built with the west wall over the east wall of Structure 11. Then this structure burned the charcoal, etc. laid upon that of the lower structure, forming a deep deposit at the Northwest corner. The South end of this burned area was entirely above Feature 19. Mold 27 is seen to come up to Mold 19 and stop. It continues again on the other side. Mold 19 is seen to cut through Mold 27. Whole structure 21 has a mold only 10" deep, as compared to 19" for Structure 19, it nevertheless precedes Structure 19 in point of time. [Feature 21] This is the second of two identified structures and lies under the other but about 10' further East. No fire beds or cache pits were found in this structure although the floor was taken down several inches. At the east end five or six feet in from the wall were two shallow refuse pits, Features 32 and 37. There are a few miscellaneous post molds inside the structure. For a discussion of its relation to structure 19 in point of time see Feature data sheet for structure 19.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Institution has more information and illustration on file.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>28; 29; 49</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>19; 21</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>43HS1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00960</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004381</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
