<record>
  <dc:title>80MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 31, Circular post-mold pattern associated with level D. Direction east.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-11-01</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This structure is unusual in that it is small and circular and apparently a dwelling. It is delineated by post molds, but no sign of any wall trench has been found. The post molds have a tendency to slant outward at the base although some are vertical. The floor is of hard packed sandy clay and at certain spots are slight burnt areas, one near the center is of red clay. Near the south wall is some charcoal that indicates the structure had burnt. Judging from the slanting post mold form the structure was built of light saplings that were bent over and tied together to form the roof. The slant of the post molds seems to be due to the stress of bending these poles since the slant is not the same in every case and some of them are vertical while a few slant in the opposite direction. This lack of conformity in the slant of the mold seems to indicate that the slant is the result of a stress and not purposefully done. No fire basin although the three burnt areas near the center seem to have been so used.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>285; 286; 287</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>31</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>80MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01198</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004573</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
