<record>
  <dc:title>168MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 50, Level F. Entire south wall of Feature 50 showing burned material along postmold patterns. In background is embankment of earth which lay along north wall of this earth logde. Direction southwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-05-27</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>In structural form this building was probably an earth lodge, rectangular in shape. The ground plan is delineated by a well spaced post mold pattern of fairly deep molds. On the outside of the walls on the North and West side is a very heavy bank of earth that laid on the side walls of the structure. (See Feature 40 for a similar bank of earth). This wall did not extend to the East and South sides or at least there was no evidence of them. Over the floor was a mass of earth much mixed with charred fragments of saplings that probably fell from the roof. This earth lay much heavier along the inside of the post mold pattern than over the center of the floor and the remains of the two or three charred posts indicate that at least a portion of this earth fell from the side walls; and from the position there is some suspicion that the inside of the walls may have had a coating of earth however, the evidence is unsatisfactory.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 167MG31(A) [fhm01250], 167MG31(B) [fhm01251], and 172MG31 [fhm01255].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>394; 395; 396; 397; 387</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>50</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>168MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Posts Molds</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01252</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000054</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
