<record>
  <dc:title>28-1/2MN3 Mouse Creek Site 3MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 19, after removal of wattle and roof clay.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-04-05</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Walls of pit somewhat irregular probably due to sandy subsoil. Top of burned material just below plowzone. Wattle was very sandy soil and was not burned evenly. I believe earth covered entire area to depth of Ca. 0.5' but some of it was only partly burned or burned in small spots only. Wattle did seem to be thicker and more burned in area ground planned and this probably represents roof wattle. This was really not daub but simply sandy earth. Wattle overlay charred roof. On west and north sides thatch lay just below earth; was composed of what appeared to be grass, probably sedge grass. Thatch lay over cane. Most of charred canes were definitely whole canes not split and lay over beams. Some canes lay at cross angles but most of the cane lay parallel to sides of house. Some of this cane must have been on side walls. Cane apparently not woven as no interlacing of canes occurred. Beams were in general small -- 0.2' -0.4' diameter which agrees with the size of post holes. Small beams perpendicular to sides were probably upright; long beams parallel to sides appear to have been rafters. Few details of central (i.e. roof) beams were preserved. Some vertical posts were found and there seem to have been at the open corners and 1' and 3' inside trenches. Trenches were -.1 - .04' and did not extend to corners. Post hold in trenches were small and deeper than trench. On west side not all of post molds could be found. Near northwest corner there was a precedent stump in trench -- holes could be seen in fill of stump. At northeast and northwest corners were post holes that seem to have been strenghthened with piles of mud. On at 22L20 stake had burned clay lining. Interior posts larger than trench posts. Firebasin was small hole almost unburned, surrounded by burned clay floor burned very hard 0.25' north of this the floor falls away slightly and rises again towards edge. Floor away from center baked less hard. At south side just west of center was raised bench. This bench at least 0.5' high and perhaps higher. Was composed of nearly pure clay and sand. May have been built up from floor as it seems to contain more clay than subsoil of floor. Trench is broken around back of bench but one post mold was found back of bench. Bench appeared very flat on upper surface and did not show plow marks. In rush of removing this structure it was impossible to give each wood specimen a separate D.S. number. Numbers were given to various beams, these numbers appear on ground plan and on tags on wood specimens.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photographs 24MN3 [fhm01354], 25MN3 [fhm01355], and 28MN3 [fhm01356].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>989; 1018; 1019; 1027; 1047; 1170; 1182; 1184; 1185; 1194; 1195</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>19</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>28-1/2MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01357</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001554</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
