<record>
  <dc:title>57MN3 Mouse Creek Site 4MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Feature 15, Shows fireplace, floor and postmolds. An entry way at southeast. Sq 21LE. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-05-09</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Semi-subterranean structure. All of pit outline could be traced but northern portion was eroded and very shallow. Deepest post near south corner was 0.9 d. Walls nearly vertical, sloping outward slightly. Floor, flat and fairly even, was covered with hard packed detritus to depth of 0.1'. Fill of pit very dark with considerable midden material. Small scraps of wattle were found on floor and in basin but no large areas of wattle were found. Wattle may have been plowed away especially on north side on floor were few scraps of charred material, probably cane. Near west corner and in center in center of northwest side were small areas (3) of burned clay floor with smooth upper surface. At north edge of floor near firebasin was large hole with sloping sides, probably large post hole, not a pit. In it was a large unmodified stone. Near east corner was a small limestone slab lying on floor. Burials 4MN79, 81, 83, 84 were near entrance in south corner. 79 may be in fill but 81 was definitely in small post mold in floor. Burials 4MN83, 4MN84 were in small rectangular pits in floor. They seemed to be inclusive in structure. Three peripheral post molds contained charred basal ends of posts, indicating probable destruction of structure by fire. Entrace passage at south corner consisted of two deep external trenches and a shallow interior trench. North east of entrance was an external trench. These firebasins were found each apparently associated with a separate floor stage. The first basin had vertical sides and flat bottom with was burned 0.3 d. The next basin also had vertical walls and flat bottom burned 0.25' d. To this second basin a third addition had been added with sloping walls and basin shaped floor. This consisted of hard puddled clay layer 0.3 thick. This was burned yellow on top, red below. See p. 121, 122 of notebook.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>List of 41 Field Specimens is on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>945; 1000; 852; 902; </wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>15</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>57MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01369</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001566</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
