<record>
  <dc:title>323HA1 Dallas Site 8HA1, Hamilton Co., TN. Mound. Feature 14, Semi-subterranean ceremonial structure with Feature 22, Fireplace. Feature 20, Bench forming peripheral portion of Feature 14. Feature 21, Mussel shell embankment surrounding Feature 14. Feature 23, Compartments and 2 entrances.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>J. D. Jennings</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-01-11</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936 - 1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 14] This structure formed base of mound. Over it was fill and rubble. Just above feature and lying on floor was charred roof and wall material and fragments from daubed walls. Has an entrance on S and E. See sheets for [features] 20, 21, 22 and 23. [Feature 20] This bench forms the outer portion of feature 14, serving as a bench or couch surrounding the central floor and fireplace. It is unbroken except for entrance corridor on south. Edge is rounded and molded. Built on a framework of canes in usual daub manner. When found was covered with grass. [Feature 21] Deposit of mussel shells scraped up to make pit in which feature 14 was built. Had no bearing on Feat. 14, incidental to it. [Feature 22] Is an integral part of Feature 14. Deep fire basin modelled rim, 0.6' wide and 0.3' high, with puddled clay lining over entire bottom. Contained some ash and roof material when found. [Feature 23] Four and possibly five compartments were built on the bench. These had fallen and crumbled so that their original height is unknown. The maximum width of one, which lies on its side, was 1.8, but the top was there, so this gives only a minimun width.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations are on file at the institution. See also photographs 312HA1 [fhm00750], 313HA1 [fhm00751], 314HA1 [fhm00752], 315HA1 [fhm00753], 316HA1 [fhm00754], 317HA1 [fhm00755], 318HA1 [fhm00756], 319HA1 [fhm00757], 325HA1 [fhm00759], 326HA1 [fhm00760], 342 [fhm01119], 344HA1 [fhm01121], 347HA1 [fhm01123], 348HA1 [fhm01124], 349HA1 [fhm01125], 352HA1 [fhm01126], 353HA1 [fhm01127], HA1(A) [fhm01137], 696HA1 [fhm01946], 342HA1 [fhm02015], and 344HA1 [fhm02017].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>424; 425; 426; 427; 433; 434; 439; 489; 390; 391</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>14; 20; 21; 22; 23</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>323HA1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Clay Partition; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00758</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004306</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
