<record>
  <dc:title>15PK1 Ocoee Site / Henry Crox Farm Site 1PK1, Polk Co., TN. Feature 3, Showing fire basin, wattle and floor isolated. This is not a semi-subterranean house. The area dug deep is only to isolate the three elements of the house, namely fire basin, wattle and burnt floor. Sq. 22L3. Direction east-northeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>William Beatty Jr.</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Ocoee Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-10-27</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Historic Native American; Mississippian; Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Polk</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Feature 3 is a house of unknown extent. The limits of excavation were set when it was decided to close 1PK1. From that time on only the squares already opened were completed. Feature 3 appeared (during the completion of the squares,) near the NW limits of excavation at level 2. No outline was distinguishable on the southern side of the feature. No other portion of the edge was cleared. The excavated portion of the house consists of a triple fire basin, several post holes, a small log impression, a fairly consistent floor, no pits and no outline. The larger fire basin measures 2.5' in diameter and 0.5' in depth. It contains the usual ash fill and burned clay walls and floor. A trench run through the basin showed the burned portion to a depth of 0.05'. The southernmost fire basin is 2.4' in diameter, 0.4' in depth, and contains a bridge across the NE end. Ash fill, burned clay walls and burned clay floor comprised the structure. The smallest of the fire basin lies at the NW extremity of the largest fire basin and is an exact duplicate on a smaller scale (1.5' diameter - 0.3' depth). The burned portion of all 3 does not exceed 0.05'. The floor showed a relatively poor cleavage and no burned clay, although 2 of the westernmost post holes contained small bits of wattle throughout the fill. Due to the limited cleared area no large scale ground plan was made (such information being available on the site ground plan). A photograph (10PK1) was made of the fire basin. Feature 3 is noticeably lacking in artifacts and sherds.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments> See also photograph 10PK1 [fhm01384].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>709; 727</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>3</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>15PK1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01385</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001579</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
