<record>
  <dc:title>413HA1 Dallas Site 8HA1, Hamilton County, Tennessee. Village. Feature 41, Structure, including fire basin.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-03-10</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936 - 1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Structure - sunk from St. II into subsoil. Square with rounded corners. Post holes along inside edge of sunken area. Floor sunk ca. 1.0' below St. II. The walls of the sunken area are clearly defined. No bench or other features. Fire basin round and deep - 1.6'. Pottery on floor was shell temper. Floor seemed to be marked by shell hoes, and covered with fine sand. [Added later to document]: Structure - Feature 41 - intrusive from St. II cleared. This is a deeply sunk semi-terranean structure - sunk about 1.0' - extends down into undisturbed basic clay. Structure is square, rounded corners. Post holes are large and small regularly alternating. Deep circular fire basin in center - had low unbaked curb.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photograph 412HA1 [fhm01134].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>835</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>41</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>413HA1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01135</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004510</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
