<record>
  <dc:title>237MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 95MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 95MG31 - Shell bed, Probable mound. Feature 2, bottom of square postmold seen in picture 235MG31 (probable historic postmold). Square 1. Direction southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>W. C. Walker</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-12-12</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative> This mold was very unusual in that it was virtually square, being 0.65' by 0.7'. It originated at the bottom of the plow line and therefore was only visible in subsoil. It was relatively deep and retained its square shape to the bottom. The mold was split vertically and carefully cleaned out for the purpose of checking the bottom, which proved to be neither sharp not blunt, but a shape as shown on the reverse side of this form [feature data form on file]. The clay matrix in the bottom was tightly compressed as if having been subjected to some sort of force such as driving or pounding. It would seem impossible for a post as large and as nearly blunt as this to have been driven in such hard clay subsoil. It doesn't seem logical that it was the work of a white man, since the post was not sharpened, nor a previous hole dug, but the chances are that it is of historic origin, since the observer had been informed that the village area was the site of the house of a family that cleared the land 50 or 60 years ago. It is suggested that a hole slightly smaller than the post was first dug and the post driven into this, the post forcing its way into the hard clay in such a manner as to leave a mold such as the one herewith described. There was no evidence to suggest a previous hole having been dug</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photograph 235MG31 [fhm01276].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>2</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>237MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Post Mold</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01277</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000079</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
