<record>
  <dc:title>44HS1 Slayden Site 3HS1, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Mound 3. Feature 11, rectangular structure with square corners. Shows small storage pit at the left (Feature 39), a shallow pit near the center (Feature 38), a deep pit along the south wall (Feature 13), and a small midden pit near Feature 13 (Feature 8). Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1935-12-02</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1935</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This structure is underneath Structure 23 by about 1.1' and its east wall is underneath Structure 19 about 6". From the datum readings it is evident that it lies on a lower level than Structure 14 and hence this structure is the earliest one found in Unit 3 of HS1. It is a narrow rectangular structure of irregular proportions since the North end is disproportionatly further east than the South end. It is also somewhat wider at the North end. At the North end and about half way between the two sides was a large fire bed built up 4" above the floor and dished out in the center. Originally, the fire bed was orientated North-South and about 6" deep. At a later time, however, it was filled in and another fire bed built East-West. This latter bed was only dished out about 2" (Feature 30). The North half of the structure floor was covered with a fire layer of sand mixed with clay (the only structure so treated at the site). Above this are many burned areas showing that at least part of the structure was burned. (See Feature 33, 35, 31). 11a is a short partition wall running into the structure from the west wall. 11b is a short row of post molds 3' South of 11a and parallel. Feature 13 adn 39 are two cache pits, while Feature 8 and 38 are refuse pits. Throughout the structure are numerous miscellaneous post molds (all marked with a small 11 on the plot). This structure is resting upon the hardpan. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is available at the institution. See also photograph 45HS1 [fhm00962].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>35; 36; 37; 38</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>11; 8; 13; 38; 39</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>44HS1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00961</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004382</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
