<record>
  <dc:title>5-127 Irwin Village Site12CP5, Campbell County, Tennessee. Mound 1. Feature 14, Stones scattered and grouped irregularly in squares 8.7 and 7.7.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Campbell</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>The group near stake 7.7 covered a burial. See chart for location, see Burial form for Burial number 2. See appended chart. The stones on this level (24" above original humus line) in combination with the remains of a clay baked floor, lead to the assumption of another level of occupancy above structure 2. To seemingly clinch this assumption it is at this level that Burial 2 was found, the burial of an adult paritally flexed on the right. On this same level over the entire mound numerous stones were found, some forming a line as in squares 1.1-1.2 etc., others in squares 5.1-5.2-5.3 etc. These stone lines apparently serve the same purpose as those stones found at lower levels, i.e. to support posts, but those at the higher levels have been disturbed by cultivation since at the present time the surface is at a maximum distance of 8" above them, and in some cases (line 1.1) the stones actually protrude from the earth.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>14</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>5-127</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Stone Scatter</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00533</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004097</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
