<record>
  <dc:title>5-129 Irwin Village Sites 11CP5 and 12CP5, Campbell County, Tennessee. Mound 1. Feature 12, Burned area 26' 6" in length and 6 feet in width showing baked clay and burned cane which seemingly was part of a structure.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Campbell</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative> A pit at the Western extremity exhibits burned animal bone intermingled with burned cane. This burned area parallels the line of stone which are placed on edge at the Northern end of the mound. The burned area is seemingly in a pit or trench which is dug in the hard pan below the original humus line. This proved later to be burnt clay from the structure which had fallen upon the subterranean primary floor. At the Western extremity of the burned area is a pit with the following dimensions; 48" SW-NE. 60" NW-SE and 12 inches in depth. On the floor of this pit is burned cane exhibiting a design in arrangement. This proved later to be burnt clay from the structure which had fallen upon the subterranean primary floor.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>12</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>5-129</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00534</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004098</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
