<record>
  <dc:title>119MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Features 41, 41A, B, C, D, Level E. Picture shows postmold pattern of Features 41 with minor Features (fireplaces 41C, partition41D, part 41B, platform 41A) picture made before Feature 40 (earth embankment around structure) was removed. In background are Features 39 and 39A, pyramidal earthworks with platform. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-03-08</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 41] This structure is practically square and is delineated by a post mold pattern of deep evenly spaced molds ca.4' in diameter. At the ends of each wall is a very small mold not over .2' in diameter but about as deep as the rest of the molds. A very smooth hard baked floor of sandy clay runs directly up the post mold pattern leaving no sign of a wall trench, however, on the inside of the post molds is a log mold just below the floor and in all probability a wall mold will show up when the floor is cut away. The hard baked dull red floor extends all over the inside of the structure running up to such features as the firebasin, platform, etc. There is considerable amount of charred material lying on the floor but very little of it is of much value in reconstructing the superstructure. No posts of logs remain but only charred, split can material covered over with thatch and in some cases a third layer of bark (See drawing of burnt material). Heavily laid over the post mold pattern is the earth bank (see Feature 40) which indicates that a heavy layer of earth was placed on the side walls. Overlying the entire floor was earth of a similar nature as Feature 40 and this, no doubt, fell from the roof of the building. Thus we may conclude that this structure was an earth lodge. The earth placed over the wooden framework was dome-like in appearance matching into the side slope of Level E. A cross-section drawing. Through Features 39 and 41 in reconstructed form. Inside this structure are a number of sub-features, 41A, B, C, D, and E, each of which will be fully described on separate sheets. Aside from these are a number of misc. post molds located to the north of Feature 41D and tending to subdivide this back section into small compartment-like areas. This area is separated by a partition (Feature 41D) from the rest of the building and the occurance of post molds directly behind this low clay partition indicates a high wall had been placed there. Most of these internal post molds were ca. 1.4 deep and 2' diameter although a few are as large as the wall post molds and may have been for post supporting the roof. The fire basin (41C) was about centrally located and in the larger of the two rooms directly in front of a small wooden seat (41E). Between the fire basin and the partitions 41D was a cache pit (41B). These three sub-features were to the south (or in front of) the partition. The partition dividing the structure is placed just in front of the platform (41A).... [Feature 41A] This platform is made of hard packed clay burnt to a smooth dull red on the surface. It is .8' high 5.6' long, 3.8 wide and rests on the floor of Feature 41. It was thinly covered with Feature 40 earth. The sides are slightly sloping making the base of the platform somewhat larger than the top. There is an irregular post mold pattern at the back of the seat but it doesn't seem to have any specific relation to it. In front of the platform is Feature 41D partition which is open in the center to allow the person sitting on the seat to look into the larger room. [Feature 41B] This cache pit lies just to the south of partition 41D and to the north of the fire basin. The side wall and bottom are well defined but not smoothed, nor does the pit show any particular care in manufacture. The sides are nearly vertical but both ends slope rather gently to the bottom and at the west end the pit fans out to its greatest width. Two fair sized post molds are in the western down slope. Feature 40 lay in this pit to a depth of several inches. [Feature 41C] This fire basin is almost centrally located and is raised .1' above the floor on a square base. The fire pit is circular, .7' in diameter and .2' deep. It was completely covered over by white ashes and they extended down into the fire pit. Over the ashes Feature 40 lay very thin with some of the ash showing through. The basin was made of puddled clay burnt brick red. [Feature 41D] This clay ridge divides the interior of this structure into two sections or rooms. The larger being to the South and containing sub-features 41 B,C and E and the smaller to the North containing sub-features 41A and a number of small post molds which again subdivide this back room. This clay partition doesn't meet in the center, but leaves an opening of 0.3' in front of the platform. The ridge averages 0.6' to 0.7' high and Ca. 1' wide and directly in back of it is a row of post molds that indicate posts for the complete partition wall. The ridge was made of clay smoothed and burnt red.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information for Feature 41 is on file at the institution. Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 101MG31 [fhm01215], 103MG31 [fhm01217], 107MG31 [fhm01221], 115MG31 [fhm01227], 116MG31 [fhm01228], 117MG31 [fhm01229], 132MG31 [fhm01238], BMG31(D) [fhm01289], BMG31(E) [fhm01290], BMG31(F) [fhm01291], BMG31(G) [fhm01292], and BMG31(H) [fhm01293].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>360; 361; 362; 363; 364; 365</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>41; 41A; 41B; 41C; 41D</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>119MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Clay Platform; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01232</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000034</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
