<record>
  <dc:title>28HS1 Slayden Site 3HS1, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Mound 3. Feature 23, circular ceremonial house pattern. Feature 17, wall mold (part of structure Feature 23). Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1935-12-17</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1935</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 23] This circular structure is east of Feature 14, a square structure 1.5' below the surface at the east end, and seems to be on a slightly higher level. The datum readings here are on the highest level at which the wall was found. The sections of the wall in squares 12.6, 13.6 and 11.9 were not found on this level (due to lack of observation), but the bottom of the post molds were picked up 9" lower down in squares 12.6, 13.6 and in square 11.9. The wall was found originally and cut down to a somewhat greater depth. The section indicated on the plot of Feature 17 was found previously at a depth of 0.85' and since the north of this mold came to an abrupt end it was removed before the rest of the structure was dug, to facilitate excavation. However, the bottom of the post molds were again found about 9" lower down and cleared off for a photograph. Thus the only part of the structure that was completely missed was 18' of the mold on the south side. Inside the structure there is little to note- two fire areas (Feature 26 and 27)) both oblong in shape, the former of red burned clay and the latter a thin layer of burned clay covered with charred wood. Feature 28 is a square fire area of red burned clay. This circular structure is probably of a later date than the square structure since it is on a higher level than one (Feature 14) and overlies part of Features 11, 19 and 27. However, the shallowness of the total village deposit and the apparent similiarity of pottery and artifacts leads one to believe that the whole site is a single habitation level. The time sequence here indicated is probably slight, representing in all probability, the life and time of a structure built by a single people. [Feature 17] A slightly curved wall mold 0.85' below surface. The North end came to a very definite end while at the South end no continuation has been found. Further discussion will be found under the Feature 23 description.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is available at the institution. See also photograph 17HS1 [fhm00949]</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>23; 17</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>28HS1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00954</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004375</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
