<record>
  <dc:title>21MN3 Mouse Creek Site 3MN3, McMinn County, Tennessee. Features 14 and 18, dwelling house floor pattern. Slight depressed floor is Feature 18, postmolds in foreground belong to Feature 14. Sq. 6L14. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-03-25</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>McMinn</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 14] Structure represented by floor, firebasin and postmold pattern. Floor lies just below plowzone and is scored by plow. Floor baked red, upper surface missing in some spots. On floor and in soil above were crumbs of baked clay that appear to have been wattle. Firebasin filled with wattle showing grass impressions. Upper edge of large baisn was plowed away, walls vertical, curve at bottom to flat hard floor. Floor of basin had black upper surface and was burned to depth of 0.35'. Second basin lies to S-E of large basin and is earlier than large basin. Second basin was mostly destroyed and only floor left. No outline of pit of Feature 14 ws found. Post mold pattern seems to indicate a rectangular structure. No evidence of entrance passage. Wattle and ash in firebasin seem to indicate structure was burned. Subsoil very sandy in this region. [Feature 18] Semi-subterranean structure below and precedent to Feature 14. Floor of Feature 14 overlaps pit and floor of Feature 18. Part of pit only could be traced. Pit edge regular in outline and walls vertical. Entrance of three trenches near south corner. Floor was covered with thin layer of greyish mixed sand and clay. This appears to be weathered clay and may represent unburned wattle. Had good cleavage away from floor. Lay in area mainly toward edges and was lacking in small space north of basin and large area SE of basin. No area of floor hard burned and structure apparently not burned. Basin at center circular without curb. Walls nearly vertical and fairly hard. Floor was flat, very hard and burned 0.3' deep. Near NE edge was small piece of limestone on floor, just north of entrance were several pieces of limestone and a river pebble 0.4' dia. in a small hole. NW of firebasin were two shallow pits with flat bottoms and vertical sides. Pits showed no signs of fire. SE of firebasin was small trench 8.5' long. In trench were small but deep post holes, trench semi-circular in vertical cross section. Trench not encountered until floor level reached. May be precedent as it was very shallow as if it had been partly cut away by structure.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photograph 15MN3 [fhm01349].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>613; 713; 845; 896; 880; 897; 898; 913; 919; 920; 929; 933; 944; 995; 691; 694; 696; 714; 721; 723; 739; 761; 777; 796; 858; 865</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>14; 18</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>21MN3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; People Lab and Field Scenes</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01352</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001549</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
