<record>
  <dc:title>140BY13 Ledford Island, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 5, with arbitrary pit outline. Roof wattle shows in center. Square 3R12, etc. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-07-06</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938; 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Rectangular postmold, pattern, depressed "floor" area, and two central fire basins. Basin 1 superimposed above and overlapping Basin 2. Entryway on SE side near south corner- 2 stump holes obscure entry and destroyed entry trenches. The roof wattle was rectaingular in outline and was oriented with the house 0.5' - 0.8' above the central portion of the house. The wattle was rough and broken, the top portions partially disturbed by plowing. It averaged 0.3' in thickness and showed grass and cane embedded impressions. An average of 0.3' rather loose, black fill lay between the wattle and the burned clay floor. The level at which the post molds appeared was considerably below (0.3 - 0.5) the level of the burned clay floor. Sherds from one or two vessels were embedded in the top of the wattle. As stated above the pit outline of the house was obscured, the fact that the floor of the house is somewhat longer than the surrounding excavation levels indicates that some sort of an attempt at scoping out the interior of the house was made. Several factors may be responsible for the absence of a pit outline. It seems that surface disturbances such as plowing and erosion may be ruled out. Since with the exception of the upper most projections of wattle wich were somewhat disturbed by plowing no concerted disturbing agencies is manifest. The principle cause for the obscurity of the pit outline seems to be a natural soil condition.... Feature 5 house is later than Feature 23. Refer to later form for details. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is on file at the institution. Contact institution for specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: about 120 numbers ranging from 630 to 1946 and 2206, 2207 and 2216.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen> 630; 1946; 2206; 2207; 2216</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>5</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>140BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00257</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003007</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
