<record>
  <dc:title>117MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 41A, Level E. Platform on floor of Feature 41. Direction south.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Charles H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-03-28</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This platform is made of hard packed clay burnt to a smooth, dull red on the surface. It is 0.8' high, 5.6' long, 3.8' wide and rests on the floor of Feat. 41. It was thinly covered with Feat. 40 earth. The sides are slightly sloping, making the base of the platform somewhat larger than the top. There is an irregular post mold pattern at the back of the seat but it doesn't seem to have any specific relation to it. In front of the platform is Feat 41D, a partition which is open in the center to allow the person sitting on the seat to look into the larger room.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 115MG31 [fhm01227], 116MG31 [fhm01228], 119MG31 [fhm01232], 132MG31 [fhm01238], BMG31(D) [fhm01289], BMG31(E) [fhm01290], BMG31(F) [fhm01291], BMG31(G) [fhm01292], and BMG31(H) [fhm01293].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>41A</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>117MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Clay Platform</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01229</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000031</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
