<record>
  <dc:title>50BY11 Rymer Site 15BY11, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 9, Dwelling house floor pattern with depressed floor to right. Feature 24, Firebasin in center. Feature 12, Post mold pattern together with trenches and vestibule entrance-way to left. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C. H. Fairbanks</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-11-15</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 9] Rectangular structure countersunk from plowline to subsoil. Outline of pit could be traced on most of three sides. East side obliterated by Features 29, and 12. Feature 9 earliest structure, was unburned. Roof clay lay on floor and was especially heavy around fire basin. See ground plans and note book, P. 65. [Feature 24] Semi-subterranean structure with central firebains and entrance trenches. Probably semi-subterranean structure though no outline of pit could be traced. Subsoil line was higher to south of entrance than over floor. Chipping station probably associated with this structure; also between firebasin and entrance was pile of cut and broken antler pieces together with piece of shallow bowl decorated with curvilinear guilloche. Wattle overlay fllor about 0.4' deep. Wattle did not seem as extensive as floor. Floor burned hard near firebasin; at out edges of floor as it could be traced it was simply reddened clay without hard surface. Firebasin larger than average and well made of puddled clay; clay below firebasin burned to depth of 0.4'. Floor was covered with detritus in parts not burned hard. Curb of firebasin seems to have had grass mixed with clay. See note book p. 101. [Feature 12] Hard baked floor of clay with firebasin. Floor partly missing to West, no evidence of countersink found. Firebasin of puddled clay with raised curb 0.3' high. Wattle lay above floor mainly SE of firebasin. Wattle was cut by number of long, narrow depressions running NW - SE. Wattle daub showed molds of grass and logs. Post holes around East side could be isolated but to West Feat. 9, Feat. 29 confused the outline. See note book p. 65.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>See also photographs 41BY11 [fhm00224], and 43BY11 [fhm00226].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>626; 634; 599; 583; 646; 896; 1056; 1063</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>9; 24; 12</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>50BY11</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00229</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002980</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
