<record>
  <dc:title>185JE1 Fains Island Site 1JE1, Jefferson County, Tennessee. Features 8 and 9, cross-section of third floor altar with second floor altar appearing beneath. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Douglas</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1935</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Jefferson</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 8] West side of altar cut away for pit Burial 93. See accompanying diagram for floor datums and burials around altar. [Feature 9] Fire basin directly over fire basin of primary structure Feature 11. Hard baked red clay and sand and clay 0.3' lip around edge. See diagram for pits in secondary floor.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 187JE1 [fhm01483], and 188JE1 [fhm01484].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>8; 9</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>185JE1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Altar</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01482</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000001676</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
