<record>
  <dc:title>49HA3 Hixon Mound Site 1HA3, Hamilton Co., Tennessee. Feature 18, Well preserved wooden post in ground. Square 20L17. Direction east.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Stuart Neitzel</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-06-24</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Hamilton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Rotted post in mold. The rotted wood is in a surprisingly good state of preservation. The top of the mold shows the origin to be at least as high as the bottom of the disturbed soil. It is very possible that this is a modern fence post. The line of its origin could not be traced to the surface - probably because of plowing and erosion.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>A Field Specimen consisting of a "rotted fragment of wood" was collected, however there is no F.S. number available in the photographic record.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>18</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>49HA3</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category> Post Mold</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00833</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003139</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
