<record>
  <dc:title>79MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 28, Floor pattern delineated by wall trenches, post-molds, and hearth located somewhat to the left of center. Direction east.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-10-27</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This structure is practically identical with Feature 27 and so nearly the same level that for large areas the floor was the same for both dwellings. This can be seen by the fire basin which had been cut down horizontally so that the floor of Feature 27 could be placed over it. This basin apparently had been very well made of fired puddled clay. It is circular with a diameter of 1.9' and a present depth of 0.4'. As to whether or not it was raised above the floor no statement can be made since it had been cut partially away to allow the building of Feature 27. The structure is delineated by post molds set in wall molds. Corners are open. Only in the wall trenches is there burnt material that furnishes evidence that the dwelling burned. Since the structure was cleared before Feature 27 was built the mass of charred material was not found and hence no evidence as to superstructure form. The post molds show the same slant as was recorded for Feature 27, but there is no sign of the small stake molds of Feature 27.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution. See also photographs 67MG31(A) [fhm01184], 67MG31(B) [fhm01185], and BMG31(M) [fhm01297].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>282; 283; 284; 278</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>28</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>79MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01197</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004572</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
