<record>
  <dc:title>11-337 C.J. Walters Farm Site 11UN11, Union County, Tennessee. Feature 13, Structure [number 4].</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Union</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>A small structure with central fireplace filled with ashes. Numerous postmolds made definition of structure indistinct. Large hole in NE corner filled with ash. Numerous molds were partially filled with mussel and gastropod shells. Many bones were found in holes. The central fireplace was filled and heaped with ash (cf. photo 11-337). When ashes were removed a large pit of irregular shape, 22 inches deep was disclosed just NW of the fireplace. The firepit was 8" deep, of nearly vertical walls and 18" in diameter (cf. photo 11-338). Within the area inclosed by dotted line on the chart, a well hardened floor was found around the fireplace. Several holes near this hardened area were 10-12 inches deep. The outer postmolds average 6-8 inches deep.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 11-338 [fhm01822], 11-339 [fhm01823], and 11-340 [fhm01824].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>13</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>11-337</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01821</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005016</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
