<record>
  <dc:title>281BY14 Candy Creek Site 17BY14, Bradley Co., TN. Feature 11, with double fire pits and associated posts and pits. The third fire pit in background is Feature 7. Square 24R3. Direction north-northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>John Alden</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-03-17</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 11] Two fire pits, two pits, and post-molds. This feature appeared in the lower limits of Level 2. The fire pits were unrecognizable as such, when first seen. They showed up as black pits, with indistinct outline. The first traces of a circular red outline appeared after two inches were removed. Excavations were extended to find the outline of a house. Numerous post-molds and two pits were found. The sketch on the back of the sheet indicates the profile of the two firepits. The smaller, (southeastern) pit seems to be intrusive to the other. The larger firepit has seen at least two stages; (1) as a shallow (.5' - .6') basin-like hole, (2) with the bottom dug out as at present. The upper rim (that is, first stage) is a dull buff. The lower rim of this pit is red, and appreciably harder. The two pits were mottled and probably were refuse pits. They were about .5' deep and flat bottomed. The many posts that are in the surrounding squares made up several outlines. However, these outlines have no constant levels, and are intermittent. Therefore, no outline has been associated with this feature. There was no discernable house pit or any other such sign of the limits of this feature. [Feature 7] Narrative not available. [Feature 17] A fire pit. This fire place was apparently a roughly dug hole in the ground. The interior surface of the pit had been burned, the colors varying from dull buff to light red. The pit was roughly oval in shape (see ground plan). There was no evidence that the pit was lined with clay or any other such material. In cross-section, it was found that the burned area extended from 1/2" to 1" into the soil in all directions. It should be noted that directly under the fire pit, the sand is light gray, while the surrounding sand is brown with humus. The ground plan shows that there were a number of post-molds near this feature. No outline could be found. It is thought that this fire pit is more recent than those of Feature 11, since it appeared higher up by 0.2'. The cross-section of this fire pit indicates that it has been dug out at least once after its original construction. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations are on file for Features 11 and 17 at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1182; 1127; 1138</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>7; 11; 17</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>281BY14</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Pit; Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00286</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003031</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
