<record>
  <dc:title>181BY13 Ledford Island Site 16BY13, Bradley Co., Tennessee. Feature 25, Showing feature completely exposed. Square 12R10, etc. Direction east-northeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>William C. Beatty. Jr.</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-08-18</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1938 - 1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Woodland; Late Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Bradley</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Feature 25, a rectangular house structure including completely or partially squares 10R9, 10R10, 11R9, 11R10, 11R11, 11R12, 12R9, 12R10, 12R11, 12R12, 13R10, and 13R11, appeared slightly below the plow line and was manifested by numerous post holes and a fairly distinct house pit, part of the wall of which was surrounded by burned clay. The fill was then removed down to the level of the floor and central fire pit. It will be noticed from the large scale ground plan of Feature 25 that first level post holes are lacking noticeably in squares 11R9 and 12R11 and generally throughouth the feature. That is, 1st level post holes are not as numerous in Feature 25 as they are in similar house structues of 16BY13. A glance at Feature 25 on the small scale ground plan however, shows an abundance of second level post holes. From this evidence it might be gathered that many of these second level post holes were missed, and actually appeared at level one. However, a fairly consistant floor was located and none of the second level post holes showed above this. Needless to say, it is not impossible on such a site as 16BY13 for first level post holes to show no trace until the second level is reached. The central fire pit measured 7.5' east and west, and 2.75' north and south. In addition there was a "bridge" 0.3' wide, the center of which measured from the most western point of the fire pit. From this center point the "bridge" curved back sharply to the west to form a rough circle with the western half of the fire pit proper. The western half of the fire pit was 0.6' in depth, while the eastern side of the "bridge" showed a depth of 0.5'. The pit showed little or no evidence of the usual rim. Along the northeast, northwest, and southwest corners of the house outline, a rather peculiar situation was apparent. Here a burned clay resembling floor was found. Averaging about 0.8' in width it followed the outline with regularity and apparently was the base for the wall. On the east side a line of small rocks followed the house outline for 14.0'. This also must have been for the same pupose as the red clay.... Three burials, 2 infants and one mature male were found beneath the house (16BY155, 156, and 161).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Additional narrative information is on file at the institution. Contact institution for specific field specimen numbers. Additional field specimen numbers: about 130 numbers non-consecutively ranging from 2382 to 3481.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>2382; 2401; 2507; 2611; 2702; 2808; 2902; 3149; 3204; 3311; 3401; 3481</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>25</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>181BY13</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00266</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000003016</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
