<record>
  <dc:title>4HY1 Williams Site 1HY1, Henry County, Tennessee. Feature 5, Fire basin showing potsherds inclusive in central basin. Square 10L9. Direction south-southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>George A. Lidberg</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-06-17</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Henry</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>A series of superimposed fire basins, five in number were discovered at the base of the plowzone, but they had no associated floor. At subsoil a pattern of post mold filled trenches was found which we assume from the location that the basins and pattern are associated. The fire basins had been rebuilt in roughly the same place, and seem to represent a rebuliding by a constant occupation. They vary in shape from a square basin with rounded corners through oval to a circular basin. The most recent one is oval, the one preceeding it square with rounded corners and the earlier ones tend to be roughly circular. The cross section shape is mostly constant, showing sloping sides and a curved bottom. Only the uppermost basin shows a curb, but the others probably also had curbs which not having been as well fired as the basin were soft and crumbly and were destroyed. The basin, designated as "B" on the drawing was filled with large sherds of at le ast 4 vessels, the matrix around the sherds being almost wholly ash. The trench and post mold pattern differs from an ordinary case of superimposition. The trenches on the East and South are compound and on both these sides the trenches run parallel. On the remaining two sides the trenches are single except at the ends where they are double for a short distance. The corners on all sides are open and do not have corner posts. This structure is subsequent to Feature 3, the trenches intruding into the trenches of Feature 3 and extending 2.0' less deep than Feature 3's trenches.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>5</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>4HY1</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00994</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004415</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
