<record>
  <dc:title>11-213(B) C.J. Walters Farm Site 11UN11, Union County, Tennessee. Feature 4, Burned structure and postmolds showing pottery vessels on floor.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Union</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>This small structure had a well defined, hard packed floor underlain by clay and sand mixed with chert fragments. The double row of post molds on the south side are of the same depth. The small depression (G) is smooth walled, 13" in diameter and gently slopes to a depth of 4" in the center. The post molds within the structure were somewhat larger in diameter and deeper than those of the side walls of the structure. The fireplace was of three large sandstone boulders and the area encompassed (H) was burned black and surrounded by clay. The two stones (I and J) were sandstone and limestone respectively. One stone (I) lay upon the burned structure, while the other (J) was upon the floor. A large brass ring, 1" in diameter and cut by a hacksaw lay at (A) but 8" above the floor. (K) is a drilled mussel shell (Unio sp.) found upon the floor. There is also a stone quoit (L). A fragment of deer antler (M) lay completely charred but in place beneath the burned structure. Of the pottery, a bowl (E) was found inverted. Another bowl (D) was also inverted as was a pot with a square rim (B2). Another small shallow bowl (C) was found inverted. Another bowl (B1) was found upright and 4" above the floor. Half of a larger paddle marked pot (F), was evidently broken by the plow. [One area] (N) was probably a storage pit outside the structre. It is 16" in diameter and 30" deep. It was filled with midden soil. There is also an implement of limestone (P).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 11-213(A) [fhm01809], , 11-214 [fhm01810], 11-215 [fhm01811], 11-216 [fhm01812], 11-218 [fhm01814], and 823UN11 [fhm01828]. </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>4; 5; 6; 37</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>4</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>11-213(B)</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01808</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005003</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
