<record>
  <dc:title>303RE12 DeArmond Site 2RE12, Roane County, Tennessee. Feature 35, Roof. Note broken painted pot in center, partly covered by roof. Thatch has been cleared to show main roof members. This is the south corner of house. Sq. 43L1. Direction southwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>John Alden</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1941-05-01</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian; Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Probably demonstrates roof dirt seeping through during fire, but before collapse of roof. This structure was excavated specifically for the information on superstructure that might be obtained from it. The form and the ground-plan show most of the characteristics of the structure, so these remarks are limited chiefly to a discussion of the interior and the superstructure. In passing, it should be noted that no evidence of a house pit was found. Small profiles were cut at critical points, and as the structure lay on the Humus Under Village, any house pit would have to cut down through The Village Alluvium, and as a consequence would be easily seen. When it was first "roughed out" the superstructure appeared as a tangled mass of scorched sand and broken charcoal. Further clearing indicated that in some places there were alternate layers of burned roof material and burned sand. Such a series can be seen on the large scale ground plan of Feature 35. On the north corner of the house was found thatch at dd. 6.2'. Beneath this was burned sand. Beneath the sand was more thatch dd. 6.6', which covered more burned sand. At d.d 6.8' was found some mixed roof charcoal which covered some more scorched sand. Beneath all this was the floor at about d.d 6.9'. The sand was evidently on the roof or piled around the walls at the time of the fire. The structure did not collapse all at once, but in small sections, allowing the sand to trickle through thereby giving the stratified appearance at the time the house was excavated. There was a comparable situation on 3RE12, Phase E, Feature 16 roof. The walls were built of small (0.2') poles set upright in postholes. These were single poles spaced from 1/2 foot to 1 foot apart. Horizontal poles were attached to them on the inside of the walls. From the situation in the west corner it seems likely that these horizontal clamps were spaced from 0.5' to 0.8' apart. From the way that this section of wall fell, it is probable that the walls of the house were at least 6' high. What the walls looked like above a height of 6' cannot be said. These conclusions are partially substantiated by the section of wall along the southwest side near the south corner. Additional information was furnished by this section, as considerable cane was found. The cane shows fairly well in the drawing, and as the drawing indicates, it could not be positively determined whether the cane was inside or outside the walls. In any case, it was laid close together and was horizontal. Over all was found the burned thatch oriented perpendicularly to the axes of the walls along which it was found. A similar situation of cane and thatch was found on the roof, and in that case the cane lay over the roof members and was covered by the thatch. The extensive area of burned superstructure lying across the 44 line between stakes 44L1 and 44L2 is almost certainly roof structure. Nowhere in the samples of wall construction in this house can be found pairs of light poles lying at right angles to each other. The walls were built of single upright and horizontal poles. Before going into a description of the roof construction it should be noted that three main interior support post molds were found, lying in a rectangular pattern. Their positions were as follows: 43L1, 7.3N, 7.3N; 44CA, 3.5N, 8.8W; 44L2, 2.1N, 2.1W. That was the fourth hole necessary to complete this rectangular pattern, was not found, should not be allowed to confuse the issue. There was considerable late intrusion, tearing up the floor near where this hole should be. It should be remembered that this four-post interior pattern is a common one, particularly in this village. It is very possible that these interior posts supported four large beams which furnished the main support for the center of the roof. A vertical post would give only local support and would not be of much use in such a light structure, whereas a few horizontal beams could support the whole roof. It is believed that the 0.4' log lying between 7.8W, 2.7S, 44L1 and 0.9'W, 2.5'N, 44L1 is one of these horizontal beams. This type of central support allows many possibilities in the type of roof.... Unfortunately, no examples were found of the contact of roof and wall....If it is assumed, for a moment, that the walls and roof were separate units, it is worthwhile to further consider the interior support pattern....The question may well be asked as to why believe that the large beam just described is a horizontal beam and not a vertical support post....The mimimum height of the end walls can be approximated by means of the large log lying between 1.2'N, 3.0'W, 43L1 and 7.6'N, 7.8'W, 43L1.... This concept of the house, then offers two short end walls about 8' high and an arched roof formed over a pair of parallel beams reaching across the house, with the side walls reaching up to meet the roof, giving a gabled effect.... If it is assumed that the walls and roof were continuous, some interesting results can be obtained.... If the wall poles were bent over at the eaves to make the roof, some device would have to be employed to make the poles bend evenly all along the line.... Of particular interest is the complex section of roofing found 4.0' west of stake 44L1. As has been stated before, the excavator does not believe that the various members and components of this roof would be found in such neat relationship unless that relationship existed before the fire.... The chief interior feature of interest is the partition of small, widely spaced poles, running across the southeastern half of the house.... Nothing is known about the facilities for entrance and exit. A gap in the center of the northwest wall can be seen on the plat. This may or may not have been the entrance. The other walls were filled and the post molds were easily seen, so this may well have been the entrance. No sign of a fire place was found. As stated previously, the floor was badly torn up in places, and the fire place may have been destroyed. If this were the case, the fireplace would have to be considerably off center in the neighborhood of 6' or 7' north, 6' or 7' west, 44L1. It will be noted that the central roof section comes to the center of the house. The north western border of this section does not look like it was nearing an appreciable hole in the roof. The excavator is inclined to believe that no smoke-hole existed. A partition, no fireplace and smoke hole, all seem to point more forwards the "ceremonial" concept than to a domestic dwelling.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Extensive additional narrative on file at the institution. See also photographs 300RE12 [fhm01588], 301RE12 [fhm01589], 302RE12 [fhm01590], 304RE12 [fhm01592], and 305RE12 [fhm01593].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>2740; 2739; 2738; 2735; 2711</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>35</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>303RE12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; Artifacts</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01591</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003862</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
