<record>
  <dc:title>170MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 51, Level F, Postmold pattern, of large rectangular structure. Fire place near center is from Feature 41 of Level E and was left to indicate close separation of these levels at this point. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-05-31</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>To the right of this fire place was a burned pattern found at a slightly higher level than the post mold pattern of this structure, but may have been associated with it. In the background is the postmold pattern of a small structure (Feature 56) which was built against wall of Feature 51. Wall trenches of the large structure in the foreground failed to appear on three of the sides until a considerable depth of the floor had been cut away. [Feature 51] Structure is delineated by a post mold pattern of deep, evenly spaced molds. On the East wall is a wall trench averaging the same depth as the post molds. Just below the top of the trench on the inside of the posts was a small log mold most of the length of the trench. Vertical cutting revealed wall molds of a similar nature for the other three walls. This structure was not more than one or two tenths of a foot below Feature 44, and hence it was difficult to find the floor, much of which appeared to be practically the same as for Feature 44. The post molds in many places did not show up until ca. 0.3' or 0.4' below the floor because the floors above had packed hard into the tops of them. Near the center of the west wall a burnt pit 0.7' deep, 1.5' long and 1' wide was found. This was filled with white wood ash and charcoal. The posts were set vertically in the wall trenches and except for a short section on the east wall no horizontal log molds were found in the trenches. The wide open corner at the S.E. may have been the entrance.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>51</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>170MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01254</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000056</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
