<record>
  <dc:title>238MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 46MG31, Meigs County, Tennessee. 46MG31 - Mound. Pile of mussel shell over Burial 46MG53. Note how shell dips toward the center. This is probably due to post mortem shifting and decay. Square 6R1. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1938-12-12</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>It can hardly be said that the burial is in a pit, although the sunken bed of shell gives that appearance. What is more likely is that after the body had been placed a number of mussel shells was heaped over it. As the flesh decayed, however, the shells sank down over the body so that instead of a rounded heap it is now concave in form. This is made the more probable since no evidence of a pit having been dug was apparent. On either side of the burial were placed large logs. Nothing remains of these except a charred line the width of the logs. It is apparent that the logs were burnt, but nothing of a fire is apparent with the burial itself, or with the artifacts. The burial itself is nearly extended. The bone is very red in color contrasting the rest of the burial found to date. The burial is in Mound Phase C. The skull, however, rose into Phase B. Thus one would suspect that the burial had been placed on the very top of Phase C and covered with material of Phase B. Apparently the burial associates with Phase C. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>523; 524</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>46MG53</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>238MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Burials</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01278</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000080</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
