<record>
  <dc:title>5-132 Irwin Village Sites 11CP5 and 12CP5, Campbell County, Tennessee. Mound 1. Feature 17, an area of baked clay without any central pit on the mound floor.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Campbell</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative> This area was surrounded by an area of smooth hard clay seemingly an old floor. Near the baked clay area were two small ditches in the floor. This fireplace was small and surrounded by an area of hard clay for about 2 1/2' by 2'. Alongside of the small fireplace which measured E and W 19"-27". N-S and to the SW and NE were two parallel small ditches with a depth of 3". Beyond this area the floor could not be traced. Another ditch ran NE and SW diagonally. It was later found that this fireplace was situated in the NE corner, nearby Structure 1. In photo 5-162, the post molds of the E wall of Structure 1 can be seen while the row in which the figure holder is set is the row along the small ditch which is approximately 5' S of the N wall of Structure 1. </wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration available on file at institution. See also photographs 5-131 [fhm00535], and 5-162 [fhm00549].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>17</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>5-132</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Rock Pile</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00536</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004100</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
