<record>
  <dc:title>269BN30 Lick Creek Site 14BN30, Benton Co., Tennessee. House 45, Huge 31' diameter circular wall trench pattern post molds. Square 48L12. Direction southeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Douglas Osborne</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1941-04-10</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1941</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Opening (door ?) at west and one at NE, precedent to typical wall trench postmold patterns. St I bottom - DD. It is unfortunate that this structure had been, with the exception of the deper parts of the wall trench, completely destroyed. Its size, precedence - all make it likely to have been a town house or some other sort of social structure. Openings, probably doors, exist on the West and NE of the structure. All of the straight wall trenches are visible through those of the circular structure. Even the line of post holes, running throught 47L10 and L11 is intrusive to the circular pattern. How the roof of this large structure was made, or even whether or not it had a roof, is questionable. No post holes in regular pattern, such as would exist if regular roof supports were used, were found although there is a single large posthole in the cneter of the structure. Just why the variance in wall trench depth exists I am unable to say. Perhaps it is because the southern side, the deeper, was - (it is so now) in a rather lower place with washed in humus. It was necessary to dig deeper to reach the clay hardpan and assure a firm bed for the posts - Excavated material from this humic area (the wall trench here showed with yellow clay - elsewhere dark in the yellow clay). Squares 46L11, 12, 13, the Northern 5 feet) will be sent it. This is only for comparative purposes as it is the only area that could possibly be precedent to the house 45.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:photograph_number>269BN30</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00188</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002849</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
