<record>
  <dc:title>182(B)RE12 DeArmond Site 3RE12, Roane County, Tennessee. Feature 16A, Antler workshop on the floor of Feature 16 (Phase E summit). View shows large, flat abrader with striation, at the left, two slightly worked shoulders and some fragmentary antler and mussel shell. Sq. 51L1. Direction northwest.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>John Alden</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Watts Bar</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-10-08</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian; Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Roane</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>A broken antler point lies on the abrader near its right-hand edge. The complete shop was collected for an exhibit (FS 1071). This workshop consisted of a large abrader slab with deep grooves on its surface. On it was lying a broken antler point. West of it was a rounded boulder, possibly a hammer or anvil. Another boulder lay about 1.0' south. A broken antler on some mussel shell lay between it and the abrader. The datums were taken on bottom of abrader (D.D. 5.7'). Note that the side towards north corner of house was 0.1' higher. The floor slopes up towards the edges.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 176RE12[fhm01575], 178RE12 [fhm01577], 179RE12 [fhm01578], 181RE12 [fhm01579], </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>1071</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>16A</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>182(B)RE12</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Antler Workshop</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01580</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000003851</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
