<record>
  <dc:title>72HS6 Link Site 43HS6, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Site 43HS6. Feature 3, Square structure - rounded corners; Feature 4, Central fire basin and Feature 5, Stone pile at left.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1936-05-06</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 3] A small square structure delineated by wall molds and had a fire basin in the center. This house was underneath Feature 2 about 4" and cannot be associated with it. As is the case with structures under later ones it had been thoroughly cleared leaving no evidence as to how it was destroyed nor any artifacts other than those listed above. [Feature 4] A small circular fire basin centrally located. It was filled with charcoal and burned dirt mixed with a little sand. The top is flush with the floor of the structure. Made of puddled clay. [Feature 5] Stone pit. This pit lies just south of the fire basin and was filled with stones. All these stones show signs of having been heated by fire. This pit formed a receptacle for the stones that were used for boiling water.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>There are three Feature Data Forms on file for this photograph, one for each feature. See also photograph 71HS6 [fhm00980].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>3; 4; 5</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>72HS6</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Fire Basin; Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00981</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004402</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
