<record>
  <dc:title>56HS6 Link Site 19HS6, Humphreys County, Tennessee. Group of stone graves after removal of surrounding earth. Burials 24 and 25 in foreground. Direction south.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1936</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Humphreys</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[19HS25] Small size of grave indicates child burial. [19HS26] No Narrative. [19HS27] Broken pottery bowl at NE end of grave is the only indication of orientation of head. Small size of grave indicates child burial. [19HS28] Small size of grave indicates burial of infant. [19HS30] The above objects (pottery vessel, clay trowel, 1 quartz and 3 stone objects) cached 1' from E end of grave. Suggesting E orientation of head. [19HS31] Mound number 19. [19HS32] Mound number 19. Number of individuals one (?).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:field_specimen>5; 1; 2; 3; 4</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number> 24; 25; 26; 27; 28; 30; 31; 32</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>56HS6</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Stone Graves</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00976</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004397</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
