<record>
  <dc:title>243BN8 Harmon Creek Site 8BN8, Benton Co., Tennessee. Feature 7, House 1. Feature 8, House 2. Square CA81L12. Direction north.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>Douglas Osborne</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Kentucky Lake</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1940-12-21</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1940</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Late Woodland</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Benton</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Feature 7 (house 1) offset to east square wall trench and post mold pattern, open corner. Feature 8 offset to west, ditto as to type. All St. I bottom. 8.4 DD. Wall trench of Feature 8 at north has been destroyed by TTR. [Feature 7] Feature 7, (Hse 1), is almost directly beneath Feature 8, (Hse 2) and is precedent to the latter. The burned layer would logically be associated with the later structure; therefore I have associated the materials with them with Feature 8. The pit (pit 9) is cut by a wall trench of Feature 8, therefore, if if is associated with either of these houses is would be with the peceeding one Feature 7. Other than the small burned areas there is no architectural associated with either, House 1 or 2. No fire pit or true floor was found. This must mean that the floor level was well above the present plow line. Therefore, although these features were not worked out until we were down in the yellow clay-subsoil they may be logically said to originate at the plow line. Becuase of lack of floor or fire basin no reasonable estimate can be made as to post mold or wall trench depth. [Feature 8] Feature 8, house 2, is almost superimposed upon Feature 7, house 1, and is intrusive to it. This was obvious at the Southwest corner where the wall trench pattern showed best. I have, merely on the basis of logic, associated the burned area with Feature 8, house 2. Other than this there is no association. The same remarks concerning the origin of F. 7 House 1 may pertain to this structure. The Northern wall trench was partly destroyed by my test trench. Indications as to its placement were plentiful but I was unable to place the post holes within it.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:feature_number>7; 8</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>243BN8</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00147</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002808</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
