<record>
  <dc:title>5-80 Irwin Village Site 11CP5, Campbell Co., TN. Mound 1. Feature 9, Three rows of stone on edge at right angles to each other. Feature 10, Circular stone pile.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Campbell</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 9] These stones are on a fairly straight line and seemingly mark the limits of a structure but no molds can be traced nor any ditch. Upon complete removal of all the earth over structure 2 and the tracing of the south end of these three lines of stone, it was found that the South end was not completed with a line of rock as on the other three sides. Instead, on the south side approximately 9" above structure 2 were four stones on a line and a row of post molds which did not touch the floor of Structure 2. (See photos 300 &amp; 301). Other stones were found on this level but scattered. In combination with the 8 post molds found on the clay bank 15" above structure 2 and 18" west of stake 8.5 it seems to clearly indicate the super-position of a structure on structure 2 which definitely came at a later period. On the assumption that these lines of stone and post molds marked the limits of a structure, the approximate dimension would be: North side 29' 6"; South side 32'; East side 24'; West side 24'. [Feature 10] A circular pile of stones about 30 in number. The material is sandstone being smooth and rounded. None of the stones have a diameter greater than three inches.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>For Feature 9, see also photograph 5-79 [fhm00525]. For Feature 10, see also photograph 5-101 [fhm00528]. </wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>9</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>5-80</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Rock Formation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm00526</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000004090</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
