<record>
  <dc:title>87MG31 Hiwassee Island Site 37MG31, Meigs Co., TN. 37MG31 - Earth mound. Feature 35, Level D. Ceremonial house pattern showing postmolds at wall trenches. Dimensions 31' x 45'. The trenches representing the south and west walls in the foreground and at the right, were partially excavated for photographic detail; the remaining 2 walls were destroyed by Feature 29. Direction west.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>C.H. Nash</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Chickamauga</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1937-12-04</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1937 - 1938</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Meigs</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>Some interior post-molds can be seen in the photograph, and a small circular formation appears at the left center. The floor contained no fireplace. This structure is just below Feature 29 and is identical in size and shape. The same fire basin was used for both structures. The east and north walls were used for both structures or else two sets were built in exactly the same area and that of Feature 29 destroying that of Feature 35. The south and west walls were just inside those of Feature 29, so close that the wall molds overlapped. Inside the structure are a number of misc. post mold, all relatively shallow. One set of these form a circular enclosure. Ca. 7' just east of the west wall is a row of molds partitioning off this end of the structure from the rest. This partitioned area is roughly divided into 3 sections by rather irregularly placed post molds. Just east of this partition is a cache pit 2' in diameter and 1.7' in depth. The sides and bottom are lined with a hard packed sandy clay, grey in color. The floor of the structure is of hard packed sandy clay and a few small areas of burnt charcoal lie on the floor. The posts were set vertically in the wall molds and show no evidence of strain. No corner posts were found and hence the corners on the superstructure must have been made without the aid of posts. The wall trenches were filled with earth and showed no evidence of having contained horizontal support logs.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution..</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>315</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:feature_number>35</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>87MG31</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01205</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000000007</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
