<record>
  <dc:title>MF8 John Ausmus Farm Site 3CE10, Claiborne County, Tennessee. Mound 2. Feature 16, The second definite floor from top. Postmolds indicating one or more structures. The second row of molds (lower level at left) belong to Feature 17. Direction northeast.</dc:title>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Norris</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1934</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Claiborne</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[Feature 16] The post molds were so numerous at this level that it is almost impossible to distinguish a definite structure outline. It is quite possible that there are at least two outlines of structures at this level. The floor was a definite one, and covered with a thin layer of white sand. Many of the holes, shown in the chart, no doubt came down from the level above. The extension of pits (where burials were removed) downward also increased the difficulty of completing the outlines. Holes which probably belong to the upper level are shown in green. [Feature 17] This was the third lineup of postmolds encountered after the mound was topped. The east row was quite definite. At the time the photo was made, the holes varied from 12" to 15" in depth, but when originally found were considerably deeper. It was very difficult to locate the south row of holes, and it is not certain that these shown in the photo and on the chart are the ones actually belonging to this structure. It is possible that they were cut away. But no indications were exhibited on the vertical face, when the excavating took place. No floor could be found that actually belonged to this outline of molds. Three holes are shown on the chart (north end) which were found in the hardpan. They are questionable - and have been indicated thusly. At the SW corner, no holes were found, due, probably, to an extensive midden area (Feature 23).</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustration on file at the institution. See also photographs 10-572 [fhm00369], CE10(I) (1216-TVA) [fhm00378], and CE10(J) (1217-TVA) [fhm00379].</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:feature_number>16; 17</wpa:feature_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>MF8</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Structure Patterns; General Site and Excavation</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01842</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000005036</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
