<record>
  <dc:title>268SW20 Indian Bluff Site 30SW20, Stewart County, Tennessee. Burials 30SW98, 30SW101, 30SW136, 30SW135. Cover slabs after removal of burials. Direction from foot of burials.</dc:title>
  <wpa:observer>John Alden</wpa:observer>
  <wpa:project_reservoir>Non-Reservoir</wpa:project_reservoir>
  <wpa:date_photographed>1939-10-12</wpa:date_photographed>
  <wpa:years_excavated>1939</wpa:years_excavated>
  <wpa:arch_time_period>Mississippian</wpa:arch_time_period>
  <wpa:county>Stewart</wpa:county>
  <wpa:state>TN</wpa:state>
  <wpa:narrative>[30SW98] Top slabs present, overlain by bottom slabs of 30SW102 on SE side. Position of remaining leg bones indicates possible flexure. If this is true, the skeleton has probably been placed in a cist built for an extended burial. [30SW101] Top and bottom slabs present. Both sides were to west, although only western side is shown, thus 30SW101A is intruded into 30SW101. Most of the middle of 30SW101 is gone. The right femur was disturbed and dragged up to the skull. [30SW101A] Intruded into thorax of 30SW101. See 101 for sketch. [30SW136] Full top, head, and foot stones were all that remained of the cist. No sides or bottom slabs. Feet disturbed, thorax rotted, otherwise in fair shape. [30SW135] Complete top, bottom, side, and end slabs. The skull was broken and somewhat scattered. Thorax was disturbed. 30SW135A lay in a bundle over the lower legs of 30SW135. 30SW135A was a bundle of long bones, foot bones, teeth, etc. of a previous occupant of this cist. [30SW135A] See 30SW135 for remarks.</wpa:narrative>
  <wpa:comments>Observer illustrations on file at the institution.</wpa:comments>
  <wpa:field_specimen>263</wpa:field_specimen>
  <wpa:burial_number>30SW98; 30SW101; 30SW136; 30SW135; 30SW135A</wpa:burial_number>
  <wpa:photograph_number>268SW20</wpa:photograph_number>  
  <wpa:photograph_category>Stone Box Graves</wpa:photograph_category>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Work Progress Administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeology Southern States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Archaeological museums and collections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Tennessee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tennessee Antiquities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <wpa:identifier>fhm01731</wpa:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200400000004402</dc:identifier>
  <wpa:project_name>Frank H. McClung Museum WPA/TVA Photograph Archive</wpa:project_name>
  <dc:subject>United States; Work Progress Administration; Tennessee Valley Authority; Archaeology Southern States; Archaeological museums and collections; University of Tennessee; Tennessee Antiquities; Frank H. McClung Museum (Knoxville, Tenn)</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
  <dc:rights>Digital Image Copyright (c) 2004.  Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  Permission granted for reproduction (print, photocopies, download) for use in research and teaching, provided proper attribution of source is made in all copies.  Form of attribution to use: [description of item], WPA/TVA Archives, presented courtesy of Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee.  For all other uses contact: Curator of Archaeology, Frank H. McClung Museum, The University of Tennessee, 1327 Circle Park Drive, Knoxville, TN 37996-3200. Phone number for inquiries: 865-974-2144. Museum Web Site URL: http://mcclungmuseum.utk.edu/</dc:rights>
  <dc:relation>WPA Photographs of TVA Archaeological Projects: http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002669</dc:relation>
  <dc:relation>WPA/TVA Archaeological Photograph Archive:  http://idserver.utk.edu/?id=200300000002670</dc:relation>
</record>
